<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Graphene possesses excellent mechanical and thermal properties
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup> and a high theoretical specific surface area (2630 m
 <sup>2</sup> g
 <sup>−1</sup>)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, over the past decades, graphene’s potential uses have been examined within many fields
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>: fields emission (FE) devices
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>, sensors and biosensors
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, optoelectronic devices (transparent electrodes for solar cells), liquid–crystal displays (LCD)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>, and electrode materials in batteries and supercapacitors
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>. Graphene can exist in the form of zero-dimensional (0D) dots (nanospheres
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>, hollow spheres
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>), one-dimensional (1D) fibers (ribbons)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>, two-dimensional (2D) sheets
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>, and three-dimensional (3D) foams
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. 3D graphene foam is a network of connected graphene sheets and, just as 2D graphene, can be widely used to improve the electrical, mechanical, or thermal properties of electrochemical devices. The size, quality, and type of graphene sheet synthesis determines the properties and potential application of the 3D materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. The synthesis of a three-dimensional graphene structure is based on either the assembly of two-dimensional graphene flakes or on a direct synthesis. Many papers describe 3D structure synthesis based on chemical vapor deposition (CVD) of graphene on a nickel foam matrix
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>. A relatively new synthesis method is the 3D printing of graphene materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. Well-known methods of synthesis produce three-dimensional graphene materials effectively, but they are too expensive and require specialized equipment. The assembly of graphene flakes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup> by the hydrothermal method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup> is also popular, although not without disadvantages; self-organization of graphene sheets is the most common problem that researchers want to eliminate
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. The microwave method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup> supports the synthesis of graphene, combining many advantages: it is fast, simple, does not require specialized equipment, and the starting material for foam production can be expanded graphite
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup> or sucrose
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
