<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <italic>Castanea sativa</italic> is considered threatened due to its sensitivity to various diseases, such as ink disease and chestnut blight, which are responsible for the decline of many chestnut orchards in several countries of the world [
 <xref rid="B47-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. In Europe, 
 <italic>P. cambivora</italic> Petri and 
 <italic>P. cinnamomi</italic> Rand are responsible for ink disease. Air temperature, air humidity, elevation, and soil can be counted as determining factors for the spread of diseases and pests in the chestnut tree. The temperature variation can act on different biological and evolutionary aspects, in the hosts and parasitoids, can reveal effects on the development and death of pathogenic individuals or reduced productivity [
 <xref rid="B31-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B48-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>,
 <xref rid="B49-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. Very wet springs can be detrimental, promoting the development of ink disease (
 <italic>P. cinnamomi</italic>) and white root rot disease (
 <italic>Armillaria mellea</italic>) [
 <xref rid="B44-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. Air humidity is the special factor for the establishment, spread, and longevity of (
 <italic>P. cinnamomic</italic>) [
 <xref rid="B3-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Regarding elevation, a study carried out in the Calabrian region, the development of 
 <italic>Dryocosmus kuriphilus</italic> Yasumatsu occurs earlier at lower altitudes (550 m) when compared to higher-elevation sites (1200 m), but high altitudes have a higher number of individuals than lower altitudes [
 <xref rid="B48-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]. The accumulation of water on clay soils may promote the proliferation of chestnut ink disease (
 <italic>P. cinnamomi</italic> Rands or 
 <italic>P. cambivora</italic> Buissman or 
 <italic>Armillaria mellea</italic>), compared to porous soils [
 <xref rid="B40-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. 
 <italic>P. cinnamomi</italic> Rand and 
 <italic>P. cambivora</italic> Petri cause the root rot disease, which mainly occurs in wet and poorly drained soils, in particular in silty loam soils [
 <xref rid="B50-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]. The ink disease (
 <italic>P. cinnamomi</italic>) and chestnut blight (caused by the fungus 
 <italic>C. parasitica</italic>) are the two most destructive diseases affecting 
 <italic>Castanea sativa</italic> and 
 <italic>Castanea dentata</italic> [
 <xref rid="B51-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]. Hybrid progenies, segregating for 
 <italic>P. cinnamomi</italic> resistance, have been obtained and extensively studied to understand the chestnut resistance mechanisms to ink disease [
 <xref rid="B52-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]. The rise of temperature in the Mediterranean Basin favors the spread of 
 <italic>C. parasitica</italic> and reduces the systematically acquired resistance of the host trees [
 <xref rid="B40-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. In the early 20th century, the massive mortality of 
 <italic>Castanea sativa</italic> in southwestern Europe, which was caused by different species of 
 <italic>P.</italic> spp., led to the introduction of genes of the Asiatic species 
 <italic>Castanea crenata</italic> and 
 <italic>Castanea mollissima</italic>, where rootstocks that are resistant to this fungus resulted [
 <xref rid="B53-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>].
</p>
