<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Temperate-climate trees like chestnuts often require relatively cool winters to fulfill their chilling requirements during wintertime dormancy, which allow proper physiological and phenological development, such as budburst, flowering, fruit set, and maturation. Accumulated exposure to low temperatures enables plants to properly set inflorescence production when warmer temperatures arise in spring [
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. The chestnut tree is associated with moderate chilling accumulation (&gt;90 CP) [
 <xref rid="B20-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Subsequently, the temperature accumulation acts as a booster of tree phenology, regulating release from the endo-dormancy period after the accumulation of adequate cold units during wintertime and the release from the eco-dormancy period, whose duration is dependent on forcing units cumulated from the end of endo-dormancy to flowering stage [
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. For example, budburst timing depends on the exposure to cool temperatures (chilling) to release dormancy, followed by optimal temperatures to promote plant growth in spring [
 <xref rid="B33-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]. Nonetheless, under the same pedoclimatic conditions, different varieties of chestnut trees may have different phenological timings, which are influenced by genetic characteristics [
 <xref rid="B34-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. The levels of individual biochemical compounds are also closely connected with the climatic conditions of fruit growth. According to the studies by [
 <xref rid="B38-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>], performed in Portugal (Trás-os-Montes Region, Portugal), in the cooler areas, fruits showed higher moisture content, total phenols, flavonoids, crude proteins, soluble sugars, and starch content, and a clear prevalence of polyunsaturated fatty acids. The extreme summer or winter temperatures may restrict chestnut tree yield performances. Warmer temperatures anticipate vegetative activity, leading to advancing in phenological stages and promoting the increased incidence of diseases and pests [
 <xref rid="B3-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. However, this ancient species may exhibit termoinhibition when the air temperature is above 32 °C, which is frequent during summer [
 <xref rid="B9-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B31-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. In the case of drought, the tree appears to be particularly prone to increasing water stress leading to mortality risk [
 <xref rid="B39-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. On the contrary, cooler temperatures after bud break may result in late-ripening, thus delaying fruit maturation [
 <xref rid="B10-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>].
</p>
