<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To take advantage of the most informed CMIP5 ensemble output (see table S2), our LCDI focused on the single climate variable of surface temperature anomalies. Although the CMIP5 projections show a larger uncertainty at high latitudes (especially with high-emission scenarios and longer time scale predictions; see fig. S25), there is broad agreement that these regions will experience extreme warming (
 <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>6</italic>
 </xref>) and the CMIP5 temperature signal is considered robust. The ensemble temperature projections, while intuitive and useful for communication, display a general pattern that surface temperatures over land are warming faster than those over the ocean (
 <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1C</xref>). Beyond warming projections, our analysis indicates that three of the five ecological regions with the highest LCDI are in the ocean ( 
 <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3B</xref>). Because of the extent, volume, and heat capacity of seawater, our approach using surface temperatures only does not reflect that most of heat generated from anthropogenic climate change is absorbed by the ocean and subsequently manifests in heat waves, hypoxia, sea level rise, extreme rainfall, and mass coral bleaching events. Future approaches to indices of climate disparity, therefore, may also include additional climate change variables (sea level rise, precipitation, etc.) and moreover track domain-specific variables (
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>27</italic>
 </xref>) such as sea surface temperature and ocean heat content as they are increasingly reflected in general circulation model (GCM) outputs (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>28</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>29</italic>
 </xref>). In addition, how local indices of climate disparity intersect with income (
 <xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>30</italic>
 </xref>) may inform efforts to reduce poverty, forced displacement, transboundary migration, and economic inequalities that are driven by climate change (
 <xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>31</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>32</italic>
 </xref>).
</p>
