<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>COVID-19, an infectious respiratory infection, rapidly spread to other parts of China and eventually became a global epidemic (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). Several early studies shown that being in close proximity to anyone who has the disease increases the risk of infection (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Furthermore, recent review papers state that there are two modes of COVID-19 transmission: direct and indirect. SARS-CoV-2 bioaerosol is transferred in direct mode through the air in the internal atmosphere in the form of droplet nuclei and other body fluids, as well as from mother to infant. In the indirect mode, infections are caused by fomites or the surfaces of furniture and fixtures in the immediate environment of an infected patient (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). According to recent research, air pollutants are risk factors for infectious respiratory disease as well as COVID-19 (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>–
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). Air pollution can make patients more vulnerable to the disease and have a detrimental effect on their prognosis (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>–
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). This could be explained by enhanced angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE-2) expression in respiratory epithelial cells exposed to air pollution (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). COVID-19 lockdown, on the other hand, has had numerous positive effects on the environment and energy consumption (
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). It was loosely defined in terms of climate change and COVID-19. However, many of the underlying causes of climate change are also linked to an increase in pandemics through climate factors such as temperature, wind speed, and humidity (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>–
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). Recent studies have indicated a mostly negative relationship between COVID-19, air pollution, and climate change, for example, the relationship between climate change, environmental pollution, COVID-19, and mental health (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>), and the influence of air pollution on COVID-19 mortality (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). However, further research is needed to determine if it is relevant or not. The highlight of this mini-review is the state of both the relationship between COVID-19 and air pollution and climate change, as well as revealing both positive and negative effects of the relationship.
</p>
