<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-11-01840-f002">Figure 2</xref> shows that slurries with different pH values have similar shear thinning behavior, which is typical rheological behavior of CMC since it is often used as a thickening agent in suspension due to its long-chain molecular and network structures [
 <xref rid="B42-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>]. The long-chain molecules tend to orient themselves in flow direction with increasing shear stress, thus the shear resistance to flow as well as viscosity decreases [
 <xref rid="B43-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. It is observed that with an increasing amount of acetic acid addition, the slurry pH value decreases from 12 to 8, while the viscosity increases from 2 to 9 Pa·s at a reference shear rate of 50 s
 <sup>−1</sup>. The tendency is not the same compared to the viscosity of NMC 111 slurries from Bauer et al. [
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], where the viscosity remains constant at around 4 Pa·s in a pH range of 8 to 11. However, the viscosity rise with decreasing pH value from 12 to 8 is consistent with the study on the viscosity of CMC solution under different pH values from Lee at al. [
 <xref rid="B44-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. Na-CMC is very sensitive to pH value changes. The variation of pH value affects the protonation of the derivative sites on CMC, which in turn impacts the molecular conformation [
 <xref rid="B45-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]. In the neutral region (pH value around 7), the dissociation of CMC produces negatively charged polymer chains, the mutual repulsion among carboxylate ions (–COO
 <sup>−</sup>) results in an expansion of the network chains to form a hydrogel [
 <xref rid="B46-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>], thus leads to high viscosity. When the pH value increases to an alkaline region, sodium ions dissolve from Na-CMC in the water. The number of dissolved sodium ions increases with elevated pH value, resulting in the restraint of the extension of the tangled molecular chain in the hydrogel, therefore, the viscosity decreases [
 <xref rid="B46-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]. The rheological property of the slurry has a significant influence on the manufacturing process of cathodes, such as mixing and coating. With high viscosity, the sedimentation of active material particles, convection of conductive additives, and binder migration can be limited [
 <xref rid="B47-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. Therefore, the addition of acetic acid can not only adjust the slurry pH value to avoid corrosion on the current collector but is also beneficial for thick-film manufacturing.
</p>
