<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The climate is a crucial element that determines various characteristics and distributions of managed and natural systems, including hydrology and water resources, cryology, marine and freshwater ecosystems, terrestrial ecosystems, forestry and agriculture [
 <xref rid="B5-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. It can be explained as the phenomenon that involves changes in environmental factors such as temperature, humidity and precipitation over many years. As a result of increased temperatures, climate extremes, increased CO
 <sub>2</sub> and other greenhouse gases (GHGs) as well as altered precipitation patterns, global food production is under severe threat [
 <xref rid="B6-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Global warming is a serious problem facing the world today. It has reached record breaking levels as evidenced by unprecedented rates of increase in atmospheric temperature and sea level [
 <xref rid="B7-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. According to the World Meteorological Organisation (WMO), the world is now about one degree warmer than before widespread industrialization. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) [
 <xref rid="B7-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] also reported that each of the last three decades has been increasingly warmer, with the decade of the 2000s being the warmest. Based on a range of global climate models and development scenarios, it is expected that the Earth could experience global warming of 1.4 to 5.8 °C over the next century [
 <xref rid="B8-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. The main cause of global warming is increased concentrations of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. The most prevalent atmospheric gases are carbon dioxide (CO
 <sub>2</sub>), methane (CH
 <sub>4</sub>), and nitrous oxide (N
 <sub>2</sub>O), which are caused by many anthropogenic activities including burning off the fossil fuels and land-use change [
 <xref rid="B9-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Looking at the period of industrialization in the last two centuries, the concentration of greenhouse gases has increased immensely compared to the pre-industrial era [
 <xref rid="B10-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Among the greenhouse gases, CO
 <sub>2</sub> is the most important and the most abundant [
 <xref rid="B11-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. The increase in atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub> is one of the most recorded global changes in the atmosphere in the last half century [
 <xref rid="B12-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Its concentration in the atmosphere has increased dramatically to 416 ppm, against 280 ppm reported from pre-industrial period, and is likely to double in 2100 [
 <xref rid="B8-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. CO
 <sub>2</sub> is considered a greenhouse gas due to its high absorbance in certain wavelengths of thermal infrared radiation emitted from the Earth’s surface. The greater the amount of atmospheric gases that absorb thermal infrared radiation from the Earth’s surface, the greater the proportion of radiation emitted from the atmosphere toward the Earth’s surface [
 <xref rid="B14-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. As a result, the long-wave balance of the Earth’s surface becomes less negative, while more energy is available for sensible and latent heat flux at the Earth’s surface. As more energy is available for heat flux, this leads to an increase in air temperature [
 <xref rid="B15-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Changes in extreme weather and climate events have been observed since the mid-20th century. Many of these changes, which have been linked to anthropogenic influences, include a reduction in cold temperature extremes, an increased occurrence of warm temperature extremes, enhanced rates of sea level rise, and an increase in the frequency of heavy precipitation events in numerous regions. Heat waves are expected to become more frequent and last longer, and extreme precipitation events are expected to be more intense and frequent in certain areas [
 <xref rid="B7-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. It is very likely that the precipitation pattern will change and not be uniform. In the higher latitudes and equatorial Pacific, there appears to be an increase in mean annual precipitation. In the dry mid-latitude and subtropical regions, mean precipitation is likely to decrease, while in the wet mid-latitude regions, mean precipitation is likely to increase. Extreme precipitation events in most mid-latitude areas and humid tropical regions are likely to become more frequent and intense [
 <xref rid="B7-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. The United Nations (UN) and the IPCC have made numerous decisions to reduce GHGs emissions, provide financial assistance to developing countries, and improve adaptive capacity to meet the challenges posed by the harmful effects of climate change.
</p>
