<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Standard material characterization included the following. Nitrogen adsorption-desorption isotherms at 77 K were measured by a Micromeritics Tristar 3000 system using vacuum-degassed samples (180°C for at least 6 h). These isotherms were used to calculate (a) the specific surface area by the Brunauer-Emmett-Teller (BET) method and (b) the pore volume and pore size by the Barrett−Joyner−Halenda (BJH) method. For microscopy, scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images were obtained using a field emission Magellan 400 microscope (FEI Company), and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) was conducted using a JEOL 2011 microscope. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) was collected in a RBD upgraded PHI-5000C ESCA system (Perkin Elmer) with Mg 
 <italic>Kα</italic> radiation (
 <italic>hν</italic> = 1253.6 eV). Cyclic voltammetry (CV) tests and constant (galvanostatic) charge-discharge (CC) tests were performed using an electrochemical analyzer, CHI 660E, under ambient conditions. Electric impedance spectroscopy (EIS) was performed with an excitation amplitude of 10 mV, scanned from 10 MHz to 100 kHz. Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR) reflection spectroscopy was performed in a Spectrum Spotlight 200 FT-IR microscopy (Spotlight 200, PE, US). The solid-state 
 <sup>13</sup>C-NMR spectrum was measured at 400 MHz in a WB Solid-State NMR Spectrometer (AVANCE III, Bruker, Switzerland). Proton conductivity of a commercial additive-free PAA (Macklin, MW~ 5,000, 50% aqueous solution, dried at 70°C before the measurement) was measured in a stainless steel/PAA/stainless steel cell (having a PAA electrolyte of Φ = 15.5 mm and thickness = 1 mm between two stainless steel disk electrodes) using AC impedance spectroscopy between 0.01 Hz and 100 kHz as shown in Fig. 
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supplementary-material-1">S5</xref>. With only proton mobile, the proton conductivity 
 <italic>σ</italic> can be estimated by 
 <italic>σ</italic> = 
 <italic>h</italic>/(
 <italic>R</italic> × 
 <italic>S</italic>), where 
 <italic>h</italic> is the thickness of the PAA film, 
 <italic>R</italic> is the total resistance obtained from the crossover point of the semicircle and abscissa at the high-frequency end ~70,000 
 <italic>Ω</italic>, and 
 <italic>S</italic> is the disk area (
 <italic>S</italic> = 
 <italic>πr</italic>2, 
 <italic>r</italic> is the radius of the PAA disk). The proton conductivity obtained in this way was ~1.1 × 10
 <sup>−6</sup> S cm
 <sup>−1</sup> at 20°C.
</p>
