<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is generally understood that environmental disturbances exert social influences over a variety of spatial and temporal scales (
 <xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>33</italic>
 </xref>). This is an important feature of the climate change dialogue, as the uncertainty, nonlinearity, and scale of climate science all influence how individuals perceive and respond to the climate crisis (
 <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>9</italic>
 </xref>). This complexity has unexpectedly therefore been a common topic—with some arguing that it has received too much attention (
 <xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>34</italic>
 </xref>)—in climate change outreach and communication. Studies demonstrate, however, that uncertainties in the magnitude, distribution, and timing of climate change inhibit individual changes in human behavior. These uncertainties may create a false sense of isolation from climate threats (
 <xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>35</italic>
 </xref>) and a skepticism or pessimism that individual human agency can improve chronic, global problems (
 <xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>36</italic>
 </xref>). Past studies have addressed this issue by focusing on terrestrial climate change impacts only and using coarser country-level emission summaries (
 <xref rid="R37" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>37</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R38" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>38</italic>
 </xref>). However, there are substantial socioeconomic differences and inequities (e.g., incomes, technologies, and access) within countries, especially those that are large and contain significant geographic diversity (
 <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3A</xref>). While this may constrain available data, emission impact analyses that use the most resolved and extensive datasets will provide a more comprehensive evaluation of anthropogenic emissions from various spatial units, even if they differ in their basic underlying characteristics and methodologies.
</p>
