<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par12">In summary, an effective method of obtaining N-doped graphene in a microwave reactor was developed, one which uses expanded graphite and 
 <italic>Chlorella vurgalis</italic>. Research indicates that the use of a natural N-reagent during synthesis in a microwave reactor in various solvents can contribute to the incorporation of nitrogen atoms into the graphene structure at a level of several percent. It can be concluded that ethyl alcohol and dimethylformamide are good solvents which contribute to the exfoliation of graphene layers and the production of pure graphene material. The high quality of the obtained material, without defects, shows that the method is a promising way of producing heteroatom-doped graphene foams. The optimal time for synthesis in the microwave reactor was 30 min and introduced mainly pyrrolic-N groups descend from N-precursor 
 <italic>Chlorella vurgalis</italic>. The best electrochemical results were obtained for materials using ethanol as a reaction medium. The solvent also influenced the introduction of nitrogen functional groups into the graphene structure. The products showed good catalytic activity owing to the nitrogen functional groups introduced into the graphene structure, which are responsible for the catalytic properties in the oxygen reduction reaction. The tests proved their high activity towards ORR, i.e., the number of electrons n reached 3.46 for tested materials (no Pt added), while the analogous value for the C-Pt (20 wt% loading) reference was only slightly higher and equal 4. For pristine, i.e., non-N-doped graphene, the n value was only 2. It has to be underlined that the progress in electrochemical performance was achieved in an environment-friendly way, not only without the use of noble metals, but also with a reduction in energy consumption. Heteroatom doping of graphene materials is an alternative to more expensive materials based on metals, an alternative that can have promising properties for electrochemical applications and a huge impact on the potential use the composite materials in supercapacitors, metal-air batteries, or fuel cells.
</p>
