<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Extensive research has been carried out for developing promising polar, nonpolar, organic, and inorganic materials for the confinement of lithium polysulfides (LPS) and minimize the active material losses. The carbon-based materials can provide conductivity to the sulfur cathode and also reduce the LPS shuttling by physical confinement. This weak interaction between nonpolar carbonaceous materials and polar LPS limits the performance of the Li-S battery.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> Therefore, the strong interaction between lithium polysulfides (LPS) and polar materials can trap the lithium polysulfides efficiently through chemical interactions. Transition-metal oxide, carbide, nitrides, and sulfides are mainly identified as polar materials, which can easily adsorb the LPS on their surface by the Lewis acid–base reaction, unlike nonpolar carbonaceous materials.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> The shuttle mechanism is only partially limited by chemical interactions using transition-metal oxides, nitrides, carbides and sulfides due to the less number of available sites for these materials, which therefore hamper the cycling capability of the Li-S battery. To improve the performance of the Li-S battery, new materials/chemistry should be explored. The study on interactions of metal borides with lithium polysulfide has not been reported much. Li et al. have reported conductive and polar titanium boride (TiB
 <sub>2</sub>) as a sulfur host in Li-S batteries and effectively confined the shuttle effect.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup> Guan et al. have reported an amorphous Co
 <sub>2</sub>B@graphene composite for immobilization of LPS and explained that the synergistic effect of Co and B interactions with LPS and high conductivity of graphene could efficiently restrict the LPS dissolution.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
