<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par16">We expect that the changes in stratification phenology that we have described here will have far reaching implications for lake ecosystems throughout the entire twenty-first century. For example, an earlier onset of stratification, as our historic and future simulations suggest under climate change, has been found to facilitate phytoplankton growth in lakes through the amelioration of light limitation. In a number of lakes, this has brought forward the onset of the spring bloom
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. The earlier growth of phytoplankton communities has the potential to alter the species composition and succession, where increased abundances of early-season taxa or cold-adapted species are favoured
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. Earlier growth may also open up ecological niches later in the spring that enable the growth of potentially harmful filamentous species
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> that may represent a poorer food resource for grazers. The extent to which trophic mismatching is likely to occur between peaks in phytoplankton and zooplankton grazers is unclear, since changes in peak timing in resource and consumer differ between studies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>, although rates of change at higher trophic levels may be slower
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>, with potential for impacts on fish recruitment and survival
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup>. The extent to which changes in stratification phenology will influence lake ecosystems will depend on a suite of variables, including trophic interactions and community dynamics, but could potentially lead to abrupt shifts in global lake ecosystems during the current century
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
