<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par17">The change in stratification phenology that our ensemble projections suggest are also very likely to have a considerable influence on the interactions between surface and bottom waters, such as the exchange of oxygen, nutrients, and carbon. A longer decoupling between epilimnetic and hypolimnetic ecosystem processes will influence some of the key rules of life in lake ecosystems to which temperature, light, nutrient regimes, and habitat succession belong
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>. The severity of such impact is also, however, dependent on limiting conditions in a particular lake. For example, an increasing duration of thermal stratification, closely coupled to oxygen concentrations in bottom waters
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>
 </sup>, facilitates the process of oxygen depletion, by preventing vertical mixing of oxygen from the surface. We suggest that most pronounced ecosystem changes will occur in lakes that will experience hypoxic conditions for the first time and in lakes where the duration of hypoxia will be extended as a response to the projected prolongation in stratification. Generally, it is expected that the projected prolongation in stratification will result in the deoxygenation of productive lakes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>
 </sup>, where, in the worst case, the occurrence of fish die-off events will increase
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>
 </sup>. Anoxic conditions at the sediment–water interface have the potential to result in substantial nutrient leakage from sediments
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>
 </sup> and to have subsequent effects on nutrient mineralization. In particular, declines in redox potential in productive lakes can reduce iron and allow for a substantial phosphorus release from the sediments to the overlying water
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup>. Anoxia is also known to favour the production of the potent greenhouse gas methane, which is produced in and emitted from lakes at globally significant rates
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>
 </sup>. Thus, the changes in stratification phenology that we have described here, and the resulting decrease in bottom water oxygen concentrations that could occur in many lakes, could contribute to a further acceleration of climate change and thus represents a positive feedback that should be carefully considered in future climate change impact studies. However, it is also important to consider that an earlier onset of stratification can also imply a shorter ice-cover season within a warming climate (Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8</xref>), and thus less winter hypoxia
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>
 </sup>. A decline in winter hypoxia could consequently lead to less greenhouse gas accumulation during winter.
</p>
