<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Mitigation strategies look to reduce the net emissions to the atmosphere of long-term GG, which is the “meal” of anthropogenic climate change [
 <xref rid="B54-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>,
 <xref rid="B135-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">135</xref>,
 <xref rid="B136-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">136</xref>] and also look for an increase in the natural systems to eliminate these GGs. This reduction can be reached by:
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>(1)</label>
   <p>Increasing the capacity of the carbon sink by means of afforestation and reforestation. From 1990 to 2020, the world lost 420 million (M) hectares (ha) of forest area; 80 M ha of these corresponded to primary woods [
    <xref rid="B137-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">137</xref>]. Andalucía is one of the three Spanish communities which are developing an emission compensation system using forest projects [
    <xref rid="B138-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">138</xref>]. The economic cost for one of these projects is 229,351.5 euros for 63.42 ha, and it is expected to capture 16,653 tCO
    <sub>2</sub> in 30 years, that is, to assimilate 262.6 tCO
    <sub>2</sub> per forestry hectare. According to the actual GG emission in Andalucía, where there was an annual production of 51 M tons CO
    <sub>2</sub>eq in 2015, it would be necessary to invest €702.27 M to offset through forestry works the GG emissions, and afforest or reforest 194,211.7 ha. Obviously, current efforts are insufficient.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(2)</label>
   <p>Avoiding ocean acidification. In Andalucía, to avoid the acidification of the sea, and to control the waste of plastics, emissions of nitrogen fertilizers and untreated wastewater, it is essential to control overfishing and highly destructive fisheries to prevent the destruction of carbon sinks [
    <xref rid="B55-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. Furthermore, to stabilize emissions at around 450 ppm of CO
    <sub>2</sub>eq (recommended by IPCC), it would be necessary to reduce the annualized consumption growth rate by 0.06% per year during the 21st century [
    <xref rid="B56-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>]. While Global GDP (2019) is $87,698 billion [
    <xref rid="B139-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">139</xref>], the efforts to achieve stabilization would be equivalent to $5.26 billion/year. It has been calculated that Spain would have to reduce its GDP by 1% by 2050 to comply with the limits set by the Kyoto Protocol, i.e., some 12.45 billion euros over 30 years [
    <xref rid="B140-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">140</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(3)</label>
   <p>Promoting the transition of the actual energy generation (electricity) to systems of low carbon emissions. In Spain, the Ministry for Ecological Transition has proposed that 70% of the electric system in 2030 came from renewable energies. Investments in this sector, energy savings and renewable energies (which are cheaper) will allow the GDP to grow by 1.8% by 2030 compared to a scenario without actions: between €16.5 and €25.7 billion [
    <xref rid="B141-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">141</xref>]. This figure compensates for the reduction in GDP indicated in the previous item.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(4)</label>
   <p>Increasing building insulation. Global warming makes predictable an increase in energy consumption for cooling buildings and homes. Current energy-efficient systems allow a building with solar protection, efficient ventilation and an insulated façade to save 38% in heating and 52% in cooling [
    <xref rid="B142-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">142</xref>]. It is expected that the world energy consumption increase will average 57% between 2004 and 2030 [
    <xref rid="B143-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">143</xref>]. Therefore, energy efficiency and near-zero energy homes will be essential because they have no additional costs [
    <xref rid="B144-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">144</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(5)</label>
   <p>Ensuring that new buildings use more natural air and sunlight. Accordingly, the efficient design of buildings through ventilation with heat recovery, building skin insulation without thermal bridges and dynamic solar control using a blind system (passive house model), would obtain a fairly constant temperature throughout the year, without exceeding 25 °C in summer, i.e., higher energy efficiency [
    <xref rid="B142-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">142</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(6)</label>
   <p>Holding back growth of energy demand: promoting private, public and collective transport, which would reduce around 25 Mt CO
    <sub>2</sub> [
    <xref rid="B145-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">145</xref>]; an energy culture based on saving and using more efficient and renewable energies; environmental tax to stimulate the change to non-wasteful production models [
    <xref rid="B146-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">146</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(7)</label>
   <p>Stop playing with Nature [
    <xref rid="B147-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">147</xref>]. As mentioned above, environmental intervention due to inadequate land management, often because of lack of knowledge, produces irreversible ecological cascades which, increasingly common, affect human beings tragically [
    <xref rid="B148-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">148</xref>]. One probable origin of Covid19 disease is the uncontrolled alteration of ecosystems (contact with wild animals such as the bat 
    <italic>Rhinolophus affinis</italic>, or the Malaysian pangolin, 
    <italic>Manis javanica</italic>) [
    <xref rid="B149-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">149</xref>] and its triggering due to pollution [
    <xref rid="B150-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">150</xref>]. Other unfortunate examples of human interventions were the myxomatosis virus [
    <xref rid="B151-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">151</xref>] and HIV, possibly from apes [
    <xref rid="B152-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">152</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
