<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Examining the themes and core concepts from the literature we can make the following observations which have been utilised to construct the model: 
 <inline-graphic xlink:href="10551_2021_4855_Figb_HTML.gif" id="d32e2947" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par133">Cognition and cognitive framing are dynamic and complex processes which can shape action directly or via sensemaking by influencing attention, interpretation and response (Peng &amp; Liu, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">2016</xref>). Influenced by fixed and flexible factors cognition and cognitive framing are unique to an individual based on their nature and their experience including interactions with others (Haney, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">2017</xref>). In addition to forming a foundation (as illustrated by references to cognition within other process literature), cognition itself shapes an individual's cognitive frame (Sharma &amp; Jaiswal, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">2018</xref>). Cognitive frames form filtering devices through which an individual can reduce complexity, guiding their sensemaking and interpretation processes (Groschl et al., 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">2019</xref>; Purdy et al., 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">2019</xref>).
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par134">Sensemaking, contrary to its name refers to a biphasic process which involves both sensemaking and sensegiving. Although undoubtedly including the process of scanning, as highlighted by Hahn et al. (
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">2014</xref>), the core concepts outlined in this review can be grouped under the headings of creating, interpreting and leading. Sensemaking has been reported to be the link between cognition and action (Wang, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR87">2011</xref>), and is integrated with the process of interpretation (Fassin et al., 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2011</xref>). The concept of interpretation is often discussed in the sensemaking literature, and although examined separately in the review process, it has been identified as an area of conceptual cross-over. Cognitive framing has also been reported to shape the sensemaking process by directing attention when scanning. Sensing new information gained through learning leads to new interpretation (Angus-Leppan et al., 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">2010</xref>). The process of sensemaking reshapes an individual’s cognition and framing, increasing complexity as greater experience is gained by the individual.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par135">Managerial interpretation was observed to be a core part of the cognitive process (Haney, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">2017</xref>) impacted by and impacting the cognitive framing and sensemaking processes. Once an interpretation has been made by an individual, they can commence action, taking the interpretation to be reality (Fassin et al., 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2011</xref>). The question needs to be considered as to whether the research on interpretation should be considered separately or incorporated as an area within the growing literature on sensemaking.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
