<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Li-ion batteries with high energy densities are indispensable in applications such as portable electronic devices, electric vehicles, and grid-scale storage. However, current Li-ion battery technologies are approaching their theoretical energy density limits. In addition, there are critical challenges associated with natural abundance, cost, and safety
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>. A plausible solution to these issues is to use divalent batteries based on Ca or Mg metal anodes, because these elements are the fifth and seventh most abundant in Earth's crust, respectively. In particular, Ca has a low reduction potential (− 2.87 V vs. standard hydrogen electrode (SHE)), similar to that of Li (− 3.04 V vs. SHE) but much lower than that of Mg (− 2.37 V vs. SHE). Furthermore, these divalent metals offer higher volumetric capacities (Ca: 2073 mAh cm
 <sup>−3</sup>; Mg: 3833 mAh cm
 <sup>−3</sup>) than Li
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>. Thus, the cell voltage and energy density of Ca batteries are expected to be comparable to and higher than those of Li-ion and Mg batteries, respectively. Moreover, as Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> (1.12 Å) has a larger ionic radius than that of Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> (0.72 Å), its charge polarization is reduced, and this ion softness tends to form more-covalent bonds with host anions, which may lead to improved ion transport and diffusion in electrolyte and cathode materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>, 
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, rechargeable Ca batteries that exhibit not only the advantages of cost effectiveness and abundance but also the battery performances are attractive candidates for post-Li-ion battery technologies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>, 
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. 
</p>
