<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par29">Results from previous studies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>
 </sup>, focusing on the effects of drought, diurnal temperature range, and surface solar radiation to predict the expected range of projected wheat yield trends until the end of the twenty-first century in Spain, agree with those presented here, indicating downward trends in wheat production. Another study
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>
 </sup> focused on the impact of maximum temperature in maize and spring wheat crops, concluded that southern and northern Spain show dichotomous behaviour, with the southern region being more affected by a decrease in maize yield due to climate change. The projected larger decreases in barley yield when compared with wheat yield concur to the premise that barley is the most vulnerable crop to climate extremes over the provincial clusters analysed in this study which is in accordance with previous studies on that area
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>
 </sup>. However, this is still a matter of debate among previous works over the Mediterranean areas
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">66</xref>
 </sup>, and the overperformance of wheat or barley under lowest-yielding conditions is not clear. Nevertheless, few studies have analysed how extreme impacts on both wheat and barley yields are changing under global warming at the sub-national level under rainfed conditions. Other approaches such as the Combined Stress Index (CSI)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>
 </sup>, which combines Heat Magnitude Day (HMD; dependent on maximum daily temperature) and the Standardized Precipitation-Evapotranspiration Index (SPEI) were used at the country level to estimate climate resilience and anomalies effect on wheat
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR68">68</xref>
 </sup> and maize
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">69</xref>
 </sup> in future scenarios of climate change. The CSI has the advantage of depending on non-parametric indicators, i.e., impartial to biases inherent to climate data.
</p>
