<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Among the multivalent systems, Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> batteries are the most studied [
 <xref rid="B71-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">71</xref>,
 <xref rid="B72-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>]. As part of these studies, AACVD was performed for the growth of V
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>5</sub> at 500 °C on a fluorine-doped tin dioxide pre-coated glass substrate utilising a solution of vanadium (V) oxytri-isopropoxide in 2-methoxy-ethanol [
 <xref rid="B73-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>]. The as-grown coatings were found to be orthorhombic V
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>5</sub>, while the morphology characteristics presented grains that were not uniformly distributed on the substrate [
 <xref rid="B73-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>,
 <xref rid="B74-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>]. The electrochemical studies of the sample were carried out using a three-electrode electrochemical cell [
 <xref rid="B73-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>] in an aqueous solution of 0.075 M, MgCl
 <sub>2</sub>, which acted as an electrolyte. The current-potential curves indicated an increase of the current with scan numbers showing that the capacity to store Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> increases with cycling [
 <xref rid="B73-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>]. The curves remained practically stable after 1000 scans. The specific discharge capacity was estimated to be 427 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> with capacity retention of 82% after 2000 scans under a specific current of 5.9 A g
 <sup>−1</sup> (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-14-04177-f005">Figure 5</xref>a). The rate capability is also an important parameter for batteries showing good structural stability and high reversibility of the cathode. In this case, it was found that the battery could still deliver a specific discharge capacity of 425 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> when the specific current was returned to 5.9 A g
 <sup>−1</sup>, corresponding to a capacity retention of 99% of the original value (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-14-04177-f005">Figure 5</xref>b).
</p>
