<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par39">An example of this sort of synergy is illustrated by two recent studies concerning the glacier lake outburst flood risk from Lake Palcacocha to the downstream city of Huarez, Peru. This is the subject of the case 
 <italic>Lliuya v. RWE AG</italic> where a Peruvian farmer filed suit in German court against a German utility company, arguing that the utility’s greenhouse gas emissions have increased the risk (see Burger et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">2020</xref>, section III.C.5.c.iii). (The case sought only the percentage of costs corresponding to RWE’s contribution to total global industrial greenhouse gas emissions, estimated at 0.5%. The case is still pending, having been delayed by COVID-19.) Stuart-Smith et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2021</xref>) performed a probabilistic assessment using a detailed glacier mass-balance model to show that the observed glacier retreat is as likely as not to have been entirely driven by anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions, and virtually certain to have not arisen from natural variability. Note the glacier retreat and rising lake levels may be considered a slow-onset aspect of climate change, thus not an extreme event per se. They then argued that the glacier lake outburst flood risk had thereby increased. Huggel et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">2020</xref>) instead took a storyline approach, developing a causal chain (analogous to Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>, but elaborated for this particular impact) and discussing the evidence for each of the causal linkages, and the potential role of various confounding factors (i.e., alternative explanations). In this way, they created an evidentiary narrative. Huggel et al. also discussed in detail the complex institutional and cultural factors that shape the actual risk within Huarez itself. These two studies are clearly highly complementary and together span the causal chain from global to local.
</p>
