<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This work is primarily motivated by the aim of developing simple and reliable procedures for the synthesis of metal anodes suitable for sodium-ion microbatteries. In this context, we propose the synthesis and analysis of the behavior of a new kind of porous and nanocolumnar NiO electrode without the presence of other materials such as carbon that may also intervene in the process of the insertion–extraction of sodium ions. This analysis should provide new insights about the mechanism of interaction of sodium ions with porous NiO electrodes and the processes that usually lead to the commonly observed drop in capacity with an increase in the number of cycles. For this purpose, a porous and nanocolumnar NiO thin film has been deposited by MS-OAD. MS is particularly favored in mass production and is easy to implement both in industry and for basic research. MS-OAD is achieved by placing the substrate at a glancing angle with respect to the target, a configuration that renders thin films with a columnar and highly porous microstructure with mesopores extending from the surface up to the interface with the substrate [
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. This method has been successfully applied to obtain porous nanostructured thin films [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>] with enhanced performances as electrocatalysts [
 <xref rid="B29-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>], electrochromic electrodes [
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], nanosensors [
 <xref rid="B31-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>], solid oxide fuel cells [
 <xref rid="B32-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>], and Na-ion battery electrodes [
 <xref rid="B33-nanomaterials-11-00966" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>], the latter consisting of WO
 <sub>3</sub> anodes that showed a great robustness and reproducibility. The present work contains a description of the synthesis procedure of NiO electrodes by MS-OAD, a physicochemical characterization of the film electrode (as-prepared and after being subjected to various electrochemical cycles), and a thorough analysis of their electrochemical performance as electrodes in Na-ion batteries.
</p>
