<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>CO
 <sub>2</sub> is the essential chemical compound for photosynthesis, a process in which water and CO
 <sub>2</sub> are converted into sugars and starch, powered by solar energy. Photosynthesis occurs in the green pigments of leaves, and CO
 <sub>2</sub> must enter through stomatal openings [
 <xref rid="B24-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Since carbon is the key element in the structure of the plant, increased CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration enables faster growth due to rapid carbon assimilation [
 <xref rid="B25-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. The main effects of elevated CO
 <sub>2</sub> on plants include a reduction in transpiration and stomatal conductance, improved water and light-use efficiency, and thus an increase in photosynthetic rate. Consequently, elevated atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentrations could have a direct impact on ecosystems by stimulating plant development and growth [
 <xref rid="B26-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Although higher CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentrations could increase crop yields, the magnitude of the effect remains to be determined. Finally, CO
 <sub>2</sub> will affect C3 and C4 plants differently because the C4 group of plants are less sensitive to an increase in atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration than C3 plants [
 <xref rid="B22-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. However, Rötter and Van de Geijn [
 <xref rid="B24-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>] found that both C3 and C4 plants will benefit from an increase in atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration. The vast majority of crop plants use the C3 carboxylation pathway (Calvin cycle), which is the oldest of the carbon fixation pathways and is found in plants of all taxonomies [
 <xref rid="B28-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,
 <xref rid="B29-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. The concept of C3 photosynthesis is based on the observation that the first product of photosynthesis is a 3-carbon molecule, whereas in C4 photosynthesis the first photosynthetic product is a 4-carbon molecule. C4 photosynthesis occurs in the more highly developed plant taxa and the major C4 plant species include maize, sorghum and sugarcane, all of tropical origin [
 <xref rid="B24-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Only 3% of all flowering plant species are C4 plants and yet they account for about 50% of the 10,000 grass species [
 <xref rid="B30-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. C4 plants have about 50% higher photosynthetic efficiency than C3 plants (e.g., rice, wheat, soybean, potato, etc.), indicating that their productivity is very high. This is due to the different mechanism of carbon fixation by the two photosynthesis types. The C3 type of photosynthesis uses only the Calvin cycle for CO
 <sub>2</sub> fixation, which is catalyzed by the Rubisco enzyme that takes place inside the chloroplast in the mesophyll cell. In the C4 group of plants, photosynthetic activities are divided between mesophyll and bundle sheath cells (BS), which are biochemically and anatomically distinct. Primary carbon fixation is catalyzed by the enzyme PEPC (phosphoenolpyruvate carboxylase), which forms OAA (oxaloacetate) from CO
 <sub>2</sub> and PEP (phosphoenolpyruvate). OAA is converted to the salt of malic acid (malate) and then disperses into the BS cell where it is decarboxylated to provide an elevated CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration around the Rubisco enzyme. Finally, the initial substrate of the C4 cycle, PEP, is regenerated in the mesophyll cell by the enzyme PPDK (pyruvate orthophosphate dikinase) [
 <xref rid="B31-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. The mechanism of CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration suppresses the oxygenation reaction by Rubisco and the subsequent energy-wasting process of photorespiration, resulting in increased photosynthetic yield and improved efficiency of water and nitrogen use compared to C3 plants [
 <xref rid="B32-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. C4 plants are usually found in warmer environments, such as tropical grasslands, where photorespiration rates would be very high for C3 plants [
 <xref rid="B30-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. Therefore, under these conditions, the efficiency of C4 photosynthesis is greater than that of C3 photosynthesis [
 <xref rid="B29-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Cure et al. [
 <xref rid="B33-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>] also noted that plants with nitrogen-fixing symbionts (e.g., soybean, alfalfa, lupine, etc.) tend to benefit more from an increased CO
 <sub>2</sub> resource than other plant species under favourable environmental conditions for both the plant and the symbiont.
</p>
