<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par40">To derive principal components of the marine and lake records, we first performed Monte Carlo simulations of the constituent time series from each record (Supplementary Figs. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>–
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref>). We performed 10,000 simulations of both the marine and lake records that acknowledged both measurement and dating uncertainties of the constituent time series. The 10,000 Monte Carlo simulations yield 2D frequency histograms depicting the probability density of a given measurement at a given time for each time series. We took the median (50th percentile) as the ‘most likely’ time series for each variable and used the 5th and 95th percentiles to define a 90% confidence envelope around this ‘most likely’ time series. For the marine record, each of the three constituent time series analysed (Diatom flux, 
 <italic>Chaetoceros</italic> spores flux, and HBI III) were assumed to have a measurement uncertainty of ±7.5% (5–10%) and the depth-dependent dating uncertainty shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, assumed to represent 2-sigma uncertainty. For the lake record, the four constituent time series were assumed to have measurement uncertainties of 2% for Cd:Ti, 0.5 per mil for δ
 <sup>15</sup>N, and 0.001 mg cm
 <sup>−2</sup> yr for fractional sterol, with depth-dependent dating uncertainty (as shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>) assumed to represent 3-sigma uncertainty. To ensure that sterol was not over-represented as two independent variables in the subsequent principal component analysis, we employed fractional sterol, which is sterol flux times sterol ratio. Similarly, for the fourth constituent series, lake diatoms, we used a weighed sum to combine the two principle components (resulting from analyses carried out on centred and standardised, square root transformed relative abundance data) into a single index. This weighed sum is proportional to the per cent variance explained by each principal component (34% for PC1 and 27% for PC2) and assumed an uncertainty equivalent to 10%.
</p>
