<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There are some barriers to the application of conservation genomics to management practices in Australia. A detailed discussion of the technical challenges associated with population genomics is beyond the scope of this paper (but see [
 <xref rid="B86-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>,
 <xref rid="B124-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>,
 <xref rid="B125-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>])—here, we aim instead to highlight the difficulties associated with the implementation of conservation genomics in management and how they can be overcome. First, the link between research and conservation practitioners must be strengthened to allow managers to set goals, make informed decisions, and integrate the findings of conservation geneticists with on-ground management practices in real-time [
 <xref rid="B56-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>,
 <xref rid="B126-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">126</xref>,
 <xref rid="B127-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">127</xref>]. A recent survey of 148 conservation practitioners in New Zealand indicated that although collaboration with geneticists was desired, managers did not know how to reach them [
 <xref rid="B128-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">128</xref>]. Furthermore, Cook and Sgro (2017) [
 <xref rid="B129-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">129</xref>] highlight the need for increased presence and engagement of evolutionary biologists in the conservation space, while Shafer et al. [
 <xref rid="B56-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>] observe that encouraging genome researchers to communicate directly with practitioners about the decreasing costs and potential uses for genomic technology, as well as its limitations, would be a step towards resolving the disconnect between scientists and stakeholders. Kadykalo et al. [
 <xref rid="B130-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">130</xref>] identify the need for an interface that allows researchers to engage and connect with conservation managers, who, in turn, may communicate what types of genomic data would be helpful and applicable in the field.
</p>
