<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Gene editing is also not without its challenges; Phelps et al. [
 <xref rid="B112-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">112</xref>] note that while currently used for agricultural enhancement, such an approach would be challenging in a threatened species context due to the complex nature of adaptation and selection in ecology; traits are sometimes driven by a network of genetic responses (i.e., polygenic), rather than a single genomic region [
 <xref rid="B125-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>]. Varshney et al. [
 <xref rid="B144-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">144</xref>] note that the development of stress-tolerance in crops via gene-editing is difficult, as tolerance can be expressed in many ways and is often the result of many genomic mechanisms. Managers implementing evolutionary rescue in general must also consider that phenotypic expression of genotypes can be unpredictable, and as such, the introduction of a new genotype to a population or area is not guaranteed to have the desired result [
 <xref rid="B86-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>,
 <xref rid="B145-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">145</xref>,
 <xref rid="B146-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">146</xref>]. Incorporating phenotypic data into planning strategies may assist in predicting the persistence of species introduced to new environments. Although a significant body of work on risk assessment has emerged in recent times [
 <xref rid="B19-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B140-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">140</xref>], there remains a need for more resources surrounding decision-making tools and guidelines for conservation managers hoping to implement conservation genetics in the planning of threatened species management strategies [
 <xref rid="B147-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">147</xref>]. Careful planning and risk assessment prior to intervention using tools such as those from Rossetto et al. [
 <xref rid="B148-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">148</xref>] for conservation genomics management workflow are vital if genomic data are to be routinely included in threatened species management. This not only will help prevent undesirable outcomes but also will optimise resource usage and “bridge the gap” between researchers and conservation practitioners [
 <xref rid="B149-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">149</xref>].
</p>
