<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-11-01840-f012">Figure 12</xref> shows the increase in specific capacity and areal capacity of cells with structured electrodes compared to cells with unstructured electrodes. The areal capacities can evaluate the capacity increase including the effect of active material loss due to the laser structuring, the areal capacities are calculated from the data shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-11-01840-f007">Figure 7</xref>. When the C-rate increases to C/2, laser structuring begins to show an advantage in capacity with an increase of 14–17 mAh/g (0.2–1.6 mAh/cm
 <sup>2</sup>) in comparison to cells with unstructured electrodes. This is similar to previous results of cells containing structured electrodes with PVDF as a binder [
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. At C/2, cell containing structured electrodes produced with slurry pH value of 9 retains 40 mAh/g more capacity due to laser structuring, while cells with electrodes produced with slurry pH values of 12.1 and 10 show 16.5 and 8 mAh/g higher capacity in comparison to cells containing unstructured electrodes produced with the same slurry pH value, respectively. This proves that for aqueous processed electrodes with porosities larger than 50% (slurry pH value of 12.1, without acid addition), laser structuring is still feasible to further increase the cell capacity at high C-rates relatively to cells with unstructured electrodes. This may be due to the connection of cavities inside the electrode as shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-11-01840-f003">Figure 3</xref>, which might lead to new diffusion pathways of lithium-ions from electrolyte to the bulk electrode. However, due to the high porosity and the uneven distribution of film thickness, the ablation depth is not stable during laser processing. This might cause local damage to the current collector. Therefore, slurry pH values should be adjusted to 9–10 in order to meet a suitable precondition for subsequent laser structuring.
</p>
