<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Eight 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon</italic> salamanders reside in the PNW. Plethodontid salamanders are fully terrestrial and lungless; they rely on cool moist environments for survival and are found in forested areas, often close to the splash zones of streams and/or the runoff from melting snow fields (Corkran &amp; Thoms, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0019" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>). Plethodontid salamanders are generally considered dispersal limited, though there is some indication that they can travel far distances (Marsh et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0047" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>; Ovaska, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0059" ref-type="bibr">1988</xref>; Smith &amp; Green, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0079" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>). The PNW has a complex geologic history and landscape features (Brunsfeld et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0008" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>), resulting in highly divergent distribution patterns among these species (Figure 
 <xref rid="ece37735-fig-0001" ref-type="fig">1</xref>). Many species occur in sympatry, unlike their eastern counterparts (Kozak &amp; Wiens, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0040" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>), sometimes demonstrating extensive overlap in their ranges, and there is large variation in the size of their distributions. Range expansion has been a common pattern in this group, along with other salamanders in the region, since the Pleistocene glaciations, and rivers only seem to inhibit dispersal in some species (Carstens et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0017" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>; Kuchta &amp; Tan, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0041" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>; Mahoney, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0044" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>; Miller et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0053" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0054" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>; Steele &amp; Storfer, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0083" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0084" ref-type="bibr">2007</xref>; Wagner et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0098" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0099" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>). Even though Plethodontids appear morphologically and ecologically constrained (Mueller et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0056" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>; Wake, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0100" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>), they sometimes inhabit distinct environmental niches and/or respond to changes in the climate in unique ways (Pelletier &amp; Carstens, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0061" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Pelletier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0062" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). These unique patterns make the role that climate change will play in the future of these species difficult to predict. There are 3 main lineages in this group (Figure 
 <xref rid="ece37735-fig-0001" ref-type="fig">1</xref>), and each will be discussed below. We note that there is one other western 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon</italic> species that we are not considering here due to its distribution not being located in the PNW: 
 <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>. 
 <italic toggle="yes">neomexicanus</italic> (Stebbins &amp; Riemer, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0082" ref-type="bibr">1950</xref>).
</p>
