<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon idahoensis</italic> (Slater &amp; Slipp, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0077" ref-type="bibr">1940</xref>), 
 <italic toggle="yes">larselli</italic> (Burns, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0012" ref-type="bibr">1962</xref>), and 
 <italic toggle="yes">vandykei</italic> (Van Denburgh, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0093" ref-type="bibr">1906</xref>): These three sister species have striking differences in their distributions and diverged from each other approximately 5mya (Kozak et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0039" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>). 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon idahoensis</italic> occupies a large, continuous range from central Idaho (ID) to southern British Columbia (BC). This is the only 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon</italic> species found east of the Columbia Basin in the Northern Rocky Mountains. Extensive northern population expansion since the Pleistocene has been detected and there does appear to be some population structure that separates the northern and southern river drainages, likely a remnant of glacial refugia during the last glacial maximum (LGM) (Carstens et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0017" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0014" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0015" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>; Carstens &amp; Richards, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0016" ref-type="bibr">2007</xref>; Pelletier &amp; Carstens, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0060" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>). Moreover, these two populations represent two different evolutionary lineages that display environmental niche differentiation (Pelletier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0062" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>), which could influence species and/or conservation status going forward, especially if population sizes and geographic ranges shrink with the changing climate. On the other hand, 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. vandykei</italic> occupies three small, disjunct ranges in Washington (WA). However, data suggest these populations have not been isolated for very long, as they show little genetic differentiation, large amounts of suitable habitat between populations during the LGM, and similar ecological niches across regions (Pelletier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0062" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon larselli</italic> also has three small, somewhat disjunct ranges in OR and WA where migration among regions seems to be limited, partially due to rivers and high elevation mountains (Wagner et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0098" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>). This species has stricter habitat requirements than the other species (Aubry et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0002" ref-type="bibr">1987</xref>; Pelletier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0062" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Similar to 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. vandykei</italic>, 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. larselli</italic> might have been more connected during the LGM and might even be currently dispersing across the Columbia River (Pelletier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0062" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>).
</p>
