<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The crisis from environmental and energy issues have driven the research and development of new energy technologies on a global scale (Poizot and Dolhem, 
 <xref rid="B41" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>; Larcher and Tarascon, 
 <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Chu et al., 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Stamenkovic et al., 
 <xref rid="B45" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Li and Wang, 
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Chen et al., 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>). Among new energy technologies, sustainable energy conversion and storage technologies such as fuel cells, electrolyzed water devices, and metal-air batteries are developing rapidly (Anantharaj et al., 
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Lee et al., 
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">2016a</xref>; Zhang et al., 
 <xref rid="B57" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Li and Lu, 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>; Yu et al., 
 <xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Wang et al., 
 <xref rid="B51" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>). The metal-air battery has received increasing attention attribute to the advantages of low cost, high specific energy density, remarkable long-term stability, and environmental benignity (Fu et al., 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2017b</xref>; Pan et al., 
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Xiong and Ivey, 
 <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). Moreover, the theoretical energy density of metal-air battery is 5~10 times than that of lithium-ion batteries (Gu et al., 
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Metal-air batteries include a metal anode (metal=lithium, zinc, magnesium, aluminum, etc.) and an air cathode. On the one hand, the metal-air battery is suitable for practical applications due to its abundant resources, low price, and environmental friendliness (Chen et al., 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Wang et al., 
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). On the other hand, the battery performance can be further improved by optimizing the electrode reaction kinetic of the air cathode (Cheng and Chen, 
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>; Lee et al., 
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">2016a</xref>). During the charge-discharge process, the electrode reactions on the air cathode are oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) (Jiang et al., 
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Han et al., 
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>; Suen et al., 
 <xref rid="B47" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Rational design and synthesis of catalytic materials to promote the process of OER/ORR have attracted the interest of many researchers.
</p>
