<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>So far, precious metals and their alloys are still considered to be state-of-the-art electrocatalysts for OER/ORR, such as Pt-based material catalysts with high ORR activity, Ir-based or Ru-based material catalysts with high OER activity (Lee et al., 
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>; Liu et al., 
 <xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">2019a</xref>). However, the prohibitive cost, low reserves, and poor stability severely restrict the large-scale production and commercial application. Since transition metals (such as iron, cobalt, and nickel) based catalysts have the characteristics of low cost, earth-abundance, and good chemical stability, they are recognized as ideal materials to replace noble metals (Han et al., 
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">2019a</xref>; Shi et al., 
 <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). In recent years, there has been a lot of research results on transition metal catalysts (Aijaz et al., 
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Han et al., 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Transition metal, transition metal alloys and their derivatives (such as oxides, hydroxides and carbides) are developed as low-cost oxygen electrocatalysts, which have become a kind of substitute for precious metals and have attracted widespread attention (Gong et al., 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Cai et al., 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Fu et al., 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">2017a</xref>; Liu et al., 
 <xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">2019b</xref>; Xie et al., 
 <xref rid="B53" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). However, a large number of experimental studies have shown that it is difficult for a single metal catalyst to meet the bifunctional catalytic requirements (Liang et al., 
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Park et al., 
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>; Li et al., 
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). Therefore, the development of OER/ORR bifunctional catalysts based on earth-abundant elements with satisfied electrochemical activity and excellent stability still remains a great challenge.
</p>
