<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Extreme winter sea ice conditions contributed to annual variation in both adult survival and nest success. Severe environmental conditions during the nonbreeding period can influence eider body condition via effects on resource availability, access to resources, and energetics (Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Cooper et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0012" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0059" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0061" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). The Bering Sea is a highly productive benthic ecosystem; however, warming temperatures and declining sea ice have caused distributional shifts and overall reductions in benthic prey available to spectacled eiders (Grebmeier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0036" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0059" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>). In years with heavy ice cover across the core wintering area, individual body condition was documented to be poor in response to restricted openings in the ice and subsequent lack of access to suitable prey (Cooper et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0012" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0058" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>). Alternatively, sea ice may dampen the impact of waves and provide roosting areas for individuals during the nonforaging period, thus significantly reducing thermoregulation costs (Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0059" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>). A species’ tolerance to environmental conditions is limited due to physiological and ecological constraints, which accounts for nonlinear relationships between demographic rates and climate (Jenouvrier, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0042" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>). Several studies have identified “bell‐shaped” or otherwise nonlinear relationships between climate covariates, demographic rates, and body condition in sea birds (e.g., Ballerini et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0004" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>; Barbraud et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0005" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>; Gremillet et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0038" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). These relationships are similar to the results documented between sea ice conditions, adult survival, and nest success (Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>, 
 <italic toggle="yes">this study</italic>).
</p>
