<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Severe winter sea ice conditions can reduce body condition (Cooper et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0012" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0058" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>) affecting survival during winter and migration to spring staging or breeding grounds. We found that adult survival was highest when the number of ice days was between approximately 50 and 90 days, over the 180‐day wintering period, and subsequently declined beyond those limits. Our results provide further evidence for a nonlinear effect of winter sea ice conditions and survival for ice‐dependent avifauna (Ballerini et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0004" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>; Barbraud et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0005" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>; Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Gremillet et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0038" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Jenouvrier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0043" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>). Previous analyses of spectacled eider survival between 1992 and 2004 found support for a linear effect of winter sea ice conditions (Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>), with the additional years of data we were able to uncover a more complex pattern between survival and climatic variation. However, the addition of the quadratic terms for ice days accounted for only 16% of the temporal variation in adult female survival, suggesting other factors are also important. For example, female survival may also be affected by reproductive costs, though these may be mediated to some degree. Predation by mammalian predators and ingestion of spent lead shot on the breeding grounds may also contribute to adult female mortality (Flint &amp; Grand, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0024" ref-type="bibr">1997</xref>, Grand et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0034" ref-type="bibr">1998</xref>, Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>) with the latter suspected to be a factor propelling the initial population decline (USFWS 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0666" ref-type="bibr">1996</xref>). Though we did not explore these sources of mortality, research quantifying the relative effects of different stressors on adult survival is certainly warranted.
</p>
