<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We linked nest success to environmental conditions during the nonbreeding and breeding seasons. However, we found no evidence for an effect of fox presence or precipitation during the breeding season on annual nest success. It is possible that both our index of fox abundance and precipitation were not accurate metrics of how predation and weather influence spectacled eider nest success. Mammalian predation is a major cause of partial or total nest failure for ground‐nesting species (DeGregorio et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0017" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Mallory, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0063" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Quinlan &amp; Lehnhausen, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0072" ref-type="bibr">1982</xref>). Foxes are a major nest predator for waterfowl, however, the data on fox abundance on the Yukon‐Kuskokwim Delta are limited and measured based on the proportion of plots with signs of fox; thus, this index may not adequately capture predator‐prey dynamics. Unfavorable weather conditions during the nesting period were found to have negative effects on nest success and recruitment of common eiders (Iles et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0041" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Jónsson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0044" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>). However, the closest weather station to Kigigak Island is nearly 180 km east in Bethel, Alaska and storms and precipitation in coastal regions are often more extreme than those experienced further inland. In the Arctic, severe storm frequency is expected to continue to increase with complex regional impacts on precipitation (Terenzi et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0089" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>) and potentially deleterious effects on nest success, duckling survival, and nesting habitat (Jorgenson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0045" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). Furthermore, phenology of waterfowl nesting on the YKD is related to the timing of snowmelt and nest success (Lindberg et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0057" ref-type="bibr">1997</xref>; Sedinger &amp; Raveling, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0083" ref-type="bibr">1986</xref>; but see Babcock et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0003" ref-type="bibr">2002</xref>). Depending on the timing, coastal storms and subsequent flooding can cause localized nest failure or duckling mortality through a number of mechanisms including drowning, exposure to cold water temperatures, and stunted growth when exposed to salt water prior to developing salt glands (Devink et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0019" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>; Grand &amp; Flint, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0033" ref-type="bibr">1997</xref>; Iles et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0041" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>). Both predation and habitat conditions have been identified as major influences on survival of spectacled eider ducklings (Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0026" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>). Efforts to gather data on duckling survival in response to weather conditions, habitat change, and predation during the breeding season may help us understand the relative impacts of changes in recruitment at the population level and identify potential conservation actions.
</p>
