<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Estimating survival of first‐year spectacled eiders is a considerable challenge because of delayed breeding and lack of information on geographic distribution of 1‐year‐olds. Inference can only be made based on small sample sizes of birds banded as ducklings and recaptured as breeders (2 years or older). On average, first‐year apparent survival was 0.29, which is slightly lower than rates estimated for other eider species (Koneff et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0049" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>) but broadly similar to those of other sea duck species in Alaska (e.g., common goldeneyes; Lawson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0053" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). This value, however, was generally consistent with estimates for spectacled eiders from other studies (Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Previous analyses did not estimate annual survival of first‐year birds and were thus unable to test for an effect of environmental conditions. Prior attempts to monitor spectacled eiders produced no data on the space use of first‐year birds (Sexson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0085" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>). Because we know so little about the distribution of first‐year birds, we chose to use the Arctic Oscillation as an index for climate conditions that first‐year birds may experience but were unable to detect any relationship. Our results indicate that change in first‐year apparent survival had the strongest correlation with variation in female population growth rates. These results are consistent with those of Saether and Bakke (
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0076" ref-type="bibr">2000</xref>) who found that highly variable demographic rates may contribute more to variation in population growth than the demographic rates that contribute most strongly to asymptotic population growth. Further efforts to gather such information may reduce uncertainty in annual estimates of survival and identify appropriate environmental conditions that may affect survival and ultimately variation in population growth of spectacled eiders.
</p>
