<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Estimates of breeding propensity of 2‐year‐old birds are broadly similar to estimates obtained for sea ducks (Koneff et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0049" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Much like first‐year survival, estimating breeding propensity is challenging because of low samples sizes for females banded as ducklings and returning in their second year to breed. Furthermore, it is not possible to determine the age of birds first marked as breeders, though we would expect that some unknown portion of individuals are initially marked as 2‐year‐olds. It is also likely that breeding propensity of 2‐year‐olds is related to environmental conditions during the nonbreeding season. However, we do not have the data required to make such inference and had to constrain this parameter to be constant over time. In this study, we assumed that breeding propensity of adults (3+ years) was 100% each year. Many females in our data set were recaptured multiple years in a row, which provides support for this assumption. However, intermittent breeding has been identified in other eider species and may be linked to environmental conditions faced throughout the annual cycle (Coulson, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0014" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>; Hanssen et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0039" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Jónsson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0044" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Mehlum, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0064" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>). If spectacled eiders were exhibiting nonbreeding rates similar to common eiders (e.g., up to 70% nonbreeding), we may expect the annual estimates of abundance to vary rather substantially in response (Coulson, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0014" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>). However, this was not the case in our analysis or in analyses of the abundance data alone (Dunham et al. 
 <italic toggle="yes">in review</italic>, Fischer et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0022" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). Further research is warranted to determine whether spectacled eiders demonstrate a trade‐off between survival and reproduction (i.e., bet‐hedging strategy; Saether &amp; Bakke, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0076" ref-type="bibr">2000</xref>) through intermittent breeding following severe winter or spring conditions, which may account for some variation in breeding abundances across years.
</p>
