<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Breeding abundance increased substantially over our study period (Figure 
 <xref rid="ece37873-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>), and our abundance estimates and trend were largely consistent with recent analyses of the abundance data alone (Dunham et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0020" ref-type="bibr">2021</xref>; Fischer et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0022" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). Eiders exhibit a slow “pace of life” strategy, which often includes high variance (“boom and bust”) in annual reproductive success and first‐year survival (Orzack &amp; Tuljapurkar, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0067" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>). In structured populations with delayed breeding, we would expect temporal variation in recruitment to affect population structure and subsequently abundance over the long term (Gaillard et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0030" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>; Pfister, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0069" ref-type="bibr">1998</xref>). It is likely that intermittent years of high recruitment could have strongly contributed to the overall positive trend in population growth, despite additional variation in adult survival in recent years. For example, in species with delayed recruitment such as spectacled eiders, variation in first‐year survival can contribute greatly to both recruitment and population dynamics, as we found. But because we had to assume constant duckling survival and 2‐year‐old breeding propensity, and 100% breeding propensity thereafter, we did not pursue a more formal retrospective decomposition of female population growth rates (e.g., Koons et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0051" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Our inference about the relative contribution of demographic parameters to past variation in population growth rates is limited to the parameters that were allowed to vary over time in our integrated population model. Furthermore, sea ice conditions through our study period were often “intermediate” (i.e., within one standard deviation from the mean) and extreme years happened less than half of the time. Therefore, while annual variation in sea ice conditions may affect demographic rates, it is unlikely that the negative effects were severe or frequent enough to cause the population to decline.
</p>
