<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At the site level, the use of carbon and oxygen stable isotopes from biogenic carbonates in sediment as well as the calibration of paleoecological data (e.g., pollen, chironomids, dinocysts, diatoms, insects, and mollusks) (
 <xref rid="r42" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>
 <xref rid="r43" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r44" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r45" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r46" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r47" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r48" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>) based on extensive, modern training sets has permitted reliable quantitative reconstructions of environmental variables (temperature, precipitation, sea ice extent, sea level position) thought to influence human behavior and evolution through their impact on food resources, freshwater availability, habitat suitability, and other parameters (
 <xref rid="r49" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>
 <xref rid="r50" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r51" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>). Moreover, an increased emphasis on detailed, high-resolution sampling of paleoclimatic archives, such as lake sediment cores and speleothems (where sufficient sedimentation or growth rate allow), has fostered the development of records with high temporal resolution. This has been driven, in part, by the development of analytical techniques such as X‐ray fluorescence core scanning (
 <xref rid="r52" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>) and advances in the modeling of radiocarbon and other chronological data (
 <xref rid="r53" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>), but also by research questions that focus on understanding abrupt climate change, climate transitions, and extreme events (e.g., droughts, floods) that occur over subannual to centennial timescales and are more adequate to assess short-term human responses to environmental change. At coarser spatial scales, paleoecological (e.g., Neotoma, Acer) and archaeological (e.g., Canadian Archaeological Radiocarbon Database) databases (
 <xref rid="r54" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>
 <xref rid="r55" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r56" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>), coupled with large-scale paleoclimatic syntheses using high-quality, quantitative multiproxy datasets have facilitated regional- to continental-scale studies (
 <xref rid="r57" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>) that examine the role of climate and ecological change in driving cultural and demographic shifts, and have helped characterize climate variability, especially during the Late Glacial and Holocene at the hemispheric to global scale.
</p>
