<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Nevertheless, high-quality, high-resolution paleoclimate records that consistently span several tens to hundreds of thousands of years are still relatively scarce. In addition, the spatial distribution of available high-resolution paleoclimatic records leaves many regions underrepresented, such as the Arctic and the tropics (
 <xref rid="r58" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>, 
 <xref rid="r59" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>). For example, in Europe many records are available for the Mediterranean domain (
 <xref rid="r60" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>), whereas the vast loess regions of northern Europe remain underexploited (but see refs. 
 <xref rid="r61" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>
 <xref rid="r62" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r63" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>). As a consequence, data from single locations has often been used to infer past climate changes not only on regional but also on global spatial scales (
 <xref rid="r64" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>
 <xref rid="r65" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r66" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r67" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r68" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r69" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r70" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r71" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>). Several major problems arise when dealing with a limited number of patchy proxy records. For example, the signal recorded by proxies may reflect local conditions, rather than regional or global climate changes. In addition, proxies often record seasonal changes in a given parameter, and a shift in seasonality of the recorded climate variable may lead to a flawed comparison between seasons. The development of new proxy data records from different types of archives such as lake sediments, speleothems, or loess, may require different approaches in paleoclimate reconstruction, including a wide range of micropaleontological, geochemical, or isotopic techniques (
 <xref rid="r72" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>). Multiproxy approaches are thus fundamental. While increasingly powerful computers facilitate the treatment of huge, multiproxy datasets, revisiting old datasets—sometimes the only surviving records of past climate and environmental conditions (
 <xref rid="r73" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>)—is also essential as data acquired decades ago often lack temporal resolution and would benefit from updated calibration of the proxies as well as finer isotopic and geochemical analyses now enabled with new technologies.
</p>
