<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>As we have seen above, climate models are useful tools for understanding the mechanisms of past climate change. Paleoclimate simulations provide insights into how external forcings modify atmospheric and oceanic circulation, triggering past climate change. Moreover, climate models can fill the gap in paleoclimatic information between local and global scales, leading to more continuous representation of paleoclimatological conditions. Conversely, paleoclimate reconstructions offer the possibility of testing the climate model outputs for a wide variety of climate states. For example, an early to middle Holocene thermal optimum in the Northern Hemisphere (10,000–5,000 y BP) is documented in a variety of paleoclimate archives, showing a clear summer temperature warm anomaly around 6,000 y BP (
 <xref rid="r59" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>, 
 <xref rid="r81" ref-type="bibr">82</xref>, 
 <xref rid="r82" ref-type="bibr">83</xref>). However, Holocene trends in surface air temperature and SST reconstructed from proxies illustrate different regional patterns with regard to the amplitude and timing of the optimum. The North Atlantic and Norwegian Sea exhibit different patterns depending on the proxy used: SST records based on alkenones and diatoms generally show the existence of a warm early to mid-Holocene optimum, while foraminifer- and radiolarian-based temperature records show a cooling trend with warmer temperature toward the late Holocene. Using a global climate model to resolve the discordance between proxies and models (
 <xref rid="r83" ref-type="bibr">84</xref>) shows that the seasonal summer warming of the sea surface was stronger during the mid-Holocene, while the subsurface depths (&lt;50 m) experienced a cooling. The hydrographic setting, therefore, explains the apparent contradiction between the Holocene trends exhibited by phytoplankton and zooplankton-based temperature proxy records, and the modeling work cited above shows how a climate model helps advance our understanding of the climatic changes described by these records. Progress is still needed, however, in order for us to understand decreasing trends in global temperature over the Holocene. These cannot be represented by climate models, a discrepancy Liu et al. (
 <xref rid="r84" ref-type="bibr">85</xref>) have called the “Holocene conundrum.” At a regional scale, discrepancies among proxies and between models and proxies may depend, as shown in the example above, on the distinct climate-related signal captured by each tracer as a function of the season or water depth, which also has to be taken into account (e.g., ref. 
 <xref rid="r85" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>). Furthermore, some climate reconstructions show regional differences that could be related to fine-scale features, such as ocean current properties (e.g., refs. 
 <xref rid="r86" ref-type="bibr">87</xref>
 <xref rid="r87" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r88" ref-type="bibr">89</xref>), which would require high spatial resolution models in order to be adequately represented (e.g., refs. 
 <xref rid="r89" ref-type="bibr">90</xref> and 
 <xref rid="r90" ref-type="bibr">91</xref>).
</p>
