<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">We explored: (1) whether the change direction of the ecosystem service (ES1) is consistent with the change direction of precipitation and temperature (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>a), and (2) whether the change direction of two ecosystem services (ES1 and ES2) is consistent with the change direction of precipitation/temperature (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>b). This process provides a spatially explicit reference for the relationship between the effects of two climatic drivers and the relationship between the effects of a single climatic driver on two ecosystem services. Specifically, each pixel in the study area was divided into four states (positive–negative, positive-positive, negative–positive, negative-negative) according to the direction of sensitivity to precipitation and temperature (positive or negative). Positive–negative means that the pixel’s sensitivity to precipitation is positive and that to temperature is negative (blue colour in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>a). Also, we calculated the proportion of the four states (e.g., perc1) in the four states. Spearman correlation coefficient (e.g., r1) was applied to assess the relationship between the sensitivity to precipitation and/or to temperature, which indicates the similarity of the effect intensity of two climatic factors. “r1-4” refers to the Spearman correlation coefficient of the sensitivity of ecosystem services to temperature and/or precipitation. Notice that in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>a, “r1” is the Spearman correlation coefficient between the sensitivity of the pixels with positive sensitivity to temperature and negative sensitivity to precipitation. In Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>b, “r1” is the Spearman correlation coefficient between the sensitivity of the pixels with positive sensitivity of ES1 to precipitation (temperature) and negative sensitivity of ES2 to precipitation (temperature). For example, in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>a, if the coefficients of “r2” and “r3” are closer to 1 (−1), and the coefficients of “r1” and “r4” are closer to −1 (1), high sensitivity to temperature is always accompanied by high (low) sensitivity to precipitation. Similarly, we follow the instruction in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>b to detect whether the two ecosystem services (ES1 and ES2) are consistent with the trend of precipitation/temperature. Significant correlations were considered at a p &lt; 0.05.
</p>
