<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>However, one of the species most negatively affected by heat stress is cattle, and particularly dairy cows during their entire life cycle, as documented in the extensive review by 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2020.00116" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Dahl et al.</ext-link>. Heat stress impacts cows starting from gestation, when elevated maternal temperatures can be detrimental to embryonic and fetal development by altering cell proliferation, migration, differentiation, and programmed cell death. These effects are probably attributed to altered nutrient partitioning responsible for restricting the ontogeny of the fetal immune system. Maternal hyperthermia during early stages of fetal development may impact the differentiation, migration, and/or establishment of the highly proliferative pool of lymphoid-hematopoietic progenitor cells that are destined to become immune cells. In addition, the postnatal period is critical for the passive transfer of immunity; prenatal heat stress impairs passive transfer of colostral IgG. Newborn calves from heat-stressed dams, fed colostrum from their respective mothers, have reduced apparent efficiency of IgG absorption, compared with calves born to cooled dams and receiving their dam's colostrum, thus compromising the immune function of offspring from birth through weaning (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). Heifers also suffer from hyperthermia as their ability to dissipate metabolic heat gradually decreases, resulting in reduced heat tolerance during heifer development. Negative impacts of heat stress on lactational performance are well-known, but heat stress also has substantial impacts on a mature dairy cow's immune function and health, as suggested by the association of summer season with increased disease incidence. Finally, recent studies provide solid evidence that during the dry period, heat stress has significant negative effects on innate and adaptive immune function of both the dam and the offspring, influencing the morbidity and mortality of early lactation cows and calves from birth to first calving.
</p>
