<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Quinoxaline (QUI) 
 <bold>6</bold> is an 
 <italic>N</italic>-containing heterocyclic compound made up of a pyrazine ring fused with a benzene ring. The redox potential is more positive relative to that of pyrazine 
 <bold>1</bold> due to the presence of the second aromatic ring [
 <xref rid="B16-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Similar to pyrazine, the total number of electrons involved in the reduction reaction (
 <bold>6</bold> to 
 <bold>7</bold>, first step, 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02227-f002">Figure 2</xref>) has been postulated to be two [
 <xref rid="B8-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], while the number of protons depends on the chemical environment and most notably on the pH of the electrolyte solution [
 <xref rid="B8-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Additionally, the pH has a significant influence on the stability of the reduced form 
 <bold>7</bold>, as well as the reversibility of the oxidation/reduction process. The reduced form of quinoxaline 
 <bold>7</bold> in mild to acidic pH can have two possible degradation mechanisms. In degradation mechanism 
 <bold>a</bold>, quinoxaline 
 <bold>7</bold> undergoes a Michael addition of a molecule of H
 <sub>2</sub>O to give molecule 
 <bold>8a</bold>, which is thought to be immediately converted to the non-redox active tautomer 
 <bold>9a</bold> [
 <xref rid="B8-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], whereas the other possible pathway includes a catalytic addition of a proton to molecules 
 <bold>8b</bold>. Hereafter, molecule 
 <bold>8b</bold> tautomerizes to 
 <bold>9b</bold>, which is then irreversibly reduced to non-redox active molecule 
 <bold>10b</bold> [
 <xref rid="B18-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. The former is visible in cyclic voltammetry as an additional oxidation peak at a more positive potential relative to that shown by its redox potential [
 <xref rid="B15-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. A study of the electrochemistry of QUI 
 <bold>6</bold> dissolved in different electrolytes revealed that the presence of at least 10 mM OH
 <sup>−</sup> (regardless of the cation counter-ion) (pH &gt; 11) improved cycling stability and reversibility [
 <xref rid="B8-molecules-26-02227" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>].
</p>
