<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Propagule pressure is a function of the frequency and number of individuals invading a new habitat [
 <xref rid="B133-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">133</xref>]. In general, the more individuals introduced into an area, the greater the chance that they will successfully establish [
 <xref rid="B147-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">147</xref>]. One or more propagules of a species must first enter a transport pathway, then survive the transport journey, followed by a successful exit from the transport vector, and final establishment of an initial population that may or may not spread and become invasive [
 <xref rid="B148-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">148</xref>]. Propagule pressure is related to the extent of plant trade, the likelihood that alien insects are transported on these plants, and the probability that they pass through border controls undetected in plant commodities [
 <xref rid="B149-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">149</xref>]. One of the most recent examples of such an introduction pathway is the case of the invasion of the highly polyphagous and harmful invasive insect, the Spotted wing drosophila (
 <italic>Drosophila suzukii</italic> Matsamura), in North and South America and Europe. The pathway of introduction is thought to be trade in fresh fruit, with initial propagules occurring undetected in the egg or larval stage in large quantities of fresh fruit traded via South East Asia [
 <xref rid="B150-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">150</xref>,
 <xref rid="B151-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">151</xref>]. The spread of invasive pest species due to climate change is in fact, slow. Parmesan and Yohe [
 <xref rid="B19-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>] found that insect species are spreading at an average rate of 6.1 km per decade due to climate change. This is happening due to the increase in temperature in these areas and is causing insects to survive where they could not previously thrive [
 <xref rid="B92-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">92</xref>].
</p>
