<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>So the question arises why future doctors know about climate change and its health risks and still do not see themselves as professionally responsible, which is in contradiction to the assessment of numerous expert commissions. For example, as early as 2016, the American College of Physicians drafted a position paper on climate change and its impact on human health. It states that physicians, both individually and collectively, are explicitly encouraged to communicate about the health co-benefits of tackling climate change to their community [
 <xref rid="cit0005" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. The position paper postulated that physicians have a role in combatting climate change and to make the earth a safe and sustain place for the next generations [
 <xref rid="cit0005" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. It is not even the big gestures and publicity measures that are urgently required of physicians, but often small steps in the sphere of action of every clinician are sufficient. The Climate and Health Council in the UK has made a series of recommendations for medical doctors that are easy to implement. These include, for example, advice on being a role model in relation to climate change, or encouraging patients to walk and cycle whenever possible, which would benefit their cardiovascular health and the climate [
 <xref rid="cit0036" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. The fact that these steps are very easy to implement is also important in that there is a so-called value-action gap, i.e., it is well known that it can be difficult to draw action from existing knowledge. Measures that are too complicated and demand a great deal of the individual physician would make it even more difficult to incorporate action into a medical career. Nevertheless, it should not be forgotten that medical doctors are perceived as trusted voices in the community and that many physicians are associated with numerous organizations [
 <xref rid="cit0036" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. There is plenty of potential to influence climate policy in these fields.
</p>
