<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Climate models combined with the environmental requirements of a particular pest species (envelope) can be an effective tool for projecting the possible range of changes on a global scale. Modelling the pest risk together with the responses of its plant hosts to climate change can therefore increase the ability to predict the outcome of an insect infestation [
 <xref rid="B92-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">92</xref>]. The potential distribution of insect pest species is primarily estimated by ecological niche models (ENMs). They can be divided into two groups: correlative models and mechanistic models. Correlative models use correlated values of environmental variables and records of occurrence to make predictions about potentially adequate areas for the particular species. The most commonly used correlative models are MaxEnt, Bioclim, Random Forest, etc. [
 <xref rid="B211-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">211</xref>]. As cited by Evans et al. [
 <xref rid="B212-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">212</xref>], correlative species distribution modelling is the most commonly used approach for predicting the impacts of climate change on biodiversity and has become a cornerstone of climate change policy [
 <xref rid="B213-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">213</xref>]. Correlative modelling is a widely used tool for projecting future changes in the geographic distribution of species, assessing extinction rates, and setting priorities for biodiversity conservation [
 <xref rid="B214-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">214</xref>]. These models identify statistical relationships between the current geographic distributions of a given species and climate variables, which are then implemented to projections of climate change to suggest climatically suitable habitats for that species in the future [
 <xref rid="B215-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">215</xref>]. The final output of correlative models is often presented in the form of maps showing future climatically adequate regions for a given species, the total area of which can then be compared with current geographic ranges to estimate the future risk of their introduction and establishment [
 <xref rid="B212-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">212</xref>].
</p>
