<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The functional dependence of discharge capacity vs. C-rate of cells with both thick-film and thin-film electrodes is summarized in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-11-01840-f010">Figure 10</xref>. A decrease in capacity of about 10 mAh/g for cells with aqueous processed electrodes is observed compared to cells with NMP-based electrodes [
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], which may originate from the loss of lithium-ions and dissolution of transition metal ions [
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. In addition, a strong dependence of the specific discharge capacity on electrode thickness and discharge rate was found. At small C-rates of C/20, all cells show a similar initial capacity of about 150 mAh/g. Cells with thick-film electrodes suffer severe capacity fade with increasing discharge current, losing over 60% of the capacity at C/2 compared to capacities at C/20. This may due to the limited lithium-ion charge transfer resistance, local material degradation, and micro-cracks formation on the electrode surface owing to the inhomogeneity of applied current [
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Although cells with electrodes without acid (slurry pH value of 12.1) show the highest discharge capacity after C/10, the extremely high porosity around 60% hinders the possibility of achieving high volumetric energy densities. Additionally, cathodes with high porosity have reduced adhesion strength to the current collector. The corrosion of the aluminum current collector can lead to a deteriorated cycle stability and a shortened cycle lifetime. Not to mention the shedding of electrode materials during handling, which makes the post-processing of electrodes more difficult, such as calendaring, winding, laser structuring, cutting, and packaging. In addition, the cells containing thick-film electrodes produced with slurry pH values of 8.4 and thin-film electrodes produced with slurry pH values of 7.4 show the lowest discharge capacity above C/10 and C/2, respectively. This indicates that an excessive amount of acid deteriorates the electrochemical performance of cells at high C-rates, leading to increased cell polarization and low capacity retention. However, in the pH range of 4–9, the aluminum current collector is chemically protected due to the existence of a natural alumina passivation layer [
 <xref rid="B39-nanomaterials-11-01840" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. Therefore, the pH value of NMC 622 slurry should be adjusted to 9–10 considering the balance between rate capability and current collector corrosion.
</p>
