<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A binder/current-collector-free 3D foam consisting of Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C nanorods with different concentrations of nitrogen-doped carbon (Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C-NR@NC) was prepared by Sun et al. and directly employed as an O
 <sub>2</sub> electrode [
 <xref rid="B133-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">133</xref>]. During the charge–discharge process, the as-prepared electrode minimized the parasitic reactions in LOBs and enhanced the energy density and specific capacity. The Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C-NR with 11% NC (Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C-NR@11NC) exhibited the highest activity for OER and ORR catalytic processes. As shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f010">Figure 10</xref>a, the cell operated in a voltage window of 2.2 to 4.4 V. The excellent capacity of the Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C-NR@11NC electrode is illustrated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f010">Figure 10</xref>b, with a maximum discharge capacity of 6962 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> vs Li
 <sup>+</sup>/Li. The low charge–discharge potential gap was also assessed by subjecting electrodes with different concentrations of NC to cycling at a constant current density rate of 100 mA g
 <sup>−1</sup>. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f010">Figure 10</xref>c–f shows that the cell with the Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C-NR@11NC electrode offered the lowest potential gap (0.28 V), which may be due to the avoidance of parasitic reactions in LOBs. The mechanisms involved in the electrochemical process in an LOB were also proposed (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f010">Figure 10</xref>g). In brief, Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C-NR@11NC reduced the generation of MoO
 <sub>2</sub> on the Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C surface, while the other two electrodes generated significant amounts of MoO
 <sub>2</sub> on the surface, which readily underwent a reaction with Li
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub>, leading to the formation of Li
 <sub>x</sub>MoO
 <sub>3</sub> which dissolves in the electrolyte and limits the reversibility of the electrode. 
</p>
