<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0010">Electrochemistry underlies critical aspects of modern civilization and is the key to developing the sustainable CO
 <sub>2</sub>-emission-free economy that is essential to mitigate climate change (
 <xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr">Davis et al., 2018</xref>). The widespread electrification of society, which is required to reach net-zero CO
 <sub>2</sub> emissions and is being driven by the dramatically decreasing cost of electricity from solar and wind (
 <xref rid="bib21" ref-type="bibr">Haegel et al., 2017</xref>), requires energy-dense durable batteries and fuel cells for the transportation sector (
 <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">Crabtree, 2019</xref>), and inexpensive electrolyzers to produce hydrogen gas as a feedstock chemical and fuel for long-distance transport and long-duration grid-scale energy storage (
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">Dowling et al., 2020</xref>). Capacitive deionization is a promising route for desalination and separations (
 <xref rid="bib25" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2020</xref>) and organic electrosynthetic cells may improve chemical processes (
 <xref rid="bib30" ref-type="bibr">Minteer and Baran, 2020</xref>). Ion-selective polymer membranes, a core electrochemical technology, are essential for these and other applications (
 <xref rid="bib41" ref-type="bibr">Strathmann, 2010</xref>). The capacity of electrochemistry to contribute at immense scale is proven: Production of chlorine via the chloralkali process and aluminum via the Hall-Héroult process have taken place at industrial scales for over a century (
 <xref rid="bib34" ref-type="bibr">Pletcher and Walsh, 2012</xref>). Electrochemistry is also central to interfacing electronics with biology, for example, to enable brain-machine interfaces via neural sensing and stimulation as well as for electroceuticals (
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">Famm, 2013</xref>; 
 <xref rid="bib39" ref-type="bibr">Silversmith et al., 2021</xref>). Implementation of these technologies, along with many others, relies on a body of scientists and engineers trained in fundamental and applied electrochemistry to make the requisite scientific discoveries and engineering innovations in the laboratory and translate those to devices employed at scale.
</p>
