<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Global energy consumption has continued to increase with the economic growth of emerging countries, and the emission of greenhouse gases has increased. To suppress greenhouse gas emissions without impeding the economic growth of emerging countries, it is essential to shift from the thermal power generation to the renewable energy generation.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> Because the power generation by renewable energies usually fluctuates drastically, the large-scale power energy storage is necessary. In addition, electric vehicles (EVs) are also paid much attention owing to decreased emission of carbon dioxide. Currently, the lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) are used for the electric motors of EVs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>
 </sup> and the next-generation LIBs with high energy densities are developed.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> At the same time, the increase of cost and the shortage of lithium sources are predicted after LIBs are widely applied to these large-scale applications. Then, sodium-ion batteries (SIBs) are attracting attention as substitutes for LIBs because of abundant sodium resources.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
 </sup> The configuration of SIBs is originated from the concept that the lithium ion in the LIBs is replaced with the sodium ion. Sodium ion shuttles between positive electrodes and negative electrodes in SIBs in the same manner as in LIBs. The candidates of negative electrode materials of SIBs are carbonaceous materials, titanium-based materials, phosphorus, or tin.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>
 </sup> Among these materials, carbonaceous materials are the most attractive as they are commercialized for LIBs. The most famous candidate for carbon negative electrode material in SIBs is amorphous carbon because the reactivity of sodium ion and graphitic materials is anomalously small and sodium ion cannot insert into graphite but inserts deeply into amorphous carbon.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
