<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The kinetics of lithium-ion transfer at the interface between graphite negative electrodes and electrolyte solutions seemed to be influenced by the interaction between lithium ions and solvents, counteranions, or solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) in common organic electrolyte solutions, organic electrolyte solutions with SEI-forming additives like vinylene carbonate or fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC), and ionic liquid-based electrolyte solutions, respectively.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> As for ordinal ethylene carbonate (EC)-based electrolyte solutions, the rate-determining process in the interfacial lithium-ion transfer seemed to be the desolvation process of lithium ions.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> On the other hand, the kinetics of sodium-ion transfer at the interface between CNS electrodes and electrolyte solutions is complicated. In the previous study, the interaction between sodium ions and organic solvents was expected to be weaker than the interaction between lithium ions and solvents.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> On the contrary, the activation energies of the interfacial sodium-ion transfer at the interface between graphitized CNS electrodes and electrolyte solutions were as large as those of interfacial lithium-ion transfer.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> In addition, the activation energies were dependent on the composition of electrolyte solutions.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> However, the interfacial sodium-ion transfer resistances of CNS electrodes measured in the previous study were much larger than the interfacial lithium-ion transfer resistances even if amorphous CNS electrodes, which seemed to have many reactive sites, were used with FEC-based electrolytes. Therefore, discovering the proper electrolytes to decrease the sodium-ion transfer resistances of amorphous CNS electrodes is still necessary.
</p>
