<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par43">Thom Brooks, an American-British philosopher and legal scholar, is less pessimistic than Heatley. He represents a middle position in between pessimism and optimism concerning mitigation. He describes himself as “a realistic optimist” (Brooks, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">2021</xref>, 88). However, as I interpret him, his ‘realism’ actually seems to be a kind of pessimism. This is how Brooks summarizes his view:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par44">I have argued that existing ways of thinking about the climate–specifically as a problem in search of a “solution”–is deeply flawed. The climate cannot be stopped from changing and there is no off button, but we can influence how much (or less) it changes. So there is no end-state fixed solution, no happily ever-after. If only we consumed much less or made polluters pay for their pollution, these efforts will not prevent an environmental catastrophe in future … But this inevitability of future catastrophe is not a reason to do nothing or see our efforts as pointless … We need to mitigate more … We need to invest and develop urgently in new adaptive technologies (Brooks, 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">2021</xref>, 82–83).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>Three things are important here. First, we see an element of mitigation pessimism. We cannot prevent climate change. A future environmental catastrophe is inevitable. Even if we can influence the degree of disaster to some extent, we cannot solve the problem once and for all. Brooks criticizes what he conceives as the “orthodox” view on sustainability, namely that sustainability is a permanent state of total security. As a more realistic alternative, Brooks suggests the more modest goal of “impermanent sustainability.” Climate change lacks a fixed solution. We must learn to live with climate change and continually readjust our measures (Brooks, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">2021</xref>, 66–67). Second, there is an element of mitigation optimism. We should not see our efforts as meaningless. We can, at least to some extent, influence how much the climate changes. Third, as Heatley, Brooks puts equal emphasis on mitigation and adaptation. We should do all we can to mitigate climate change and to adapt to its adverse effects. Notice also that Brooks’ focus concerning adaptation is on technologies, as with Heatley, not on psychological or cultural adaptation, as with Bendell and Scranton.
</p>
