<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The microporous structure of the obtained carbonaceous materials was evaluated by N
 <sub>2</sub> adsorption. Measurements were carried out using a Micromeritics ASAP 2010 Accelerated Surface Area and Porosimetry System at 77 K. The specific surfaces were determined by analyzing the N
 <sub>2</sub> adsorption isotherm from the Brunauer–Emmett–Teller (BET) equation (Brunauer et al., 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">1938</xref>) and Density Functional Theory (DFT) model (Nič et al., 
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>) using a Micromeritics and Quantachrome software. The BET and DFT results were compared using Kaneko (Kaneko et al., 
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">1992</xref>) and Dubinin (Nguyen and Do, 
 <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>) equations. Micro-Raman measurements were carried out in a Horiba Jovin Yvon LabRAM HR800 system at room temperature. The samples were excited by a 633 nm He–Cd laser on an Olympus BX 41 confocal microscope with a × 40 objective. A charge-coupled device detector was used to collect the scattered light dispersed by a 2,400 lines mm
 <sup>−1</sup> grating (micro-Raman) with a spectral resolution of 1.5 cm
 <sup>−1</sup>. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) spectra were recorded using a Fisons MT500 spectrometer equipped with a hemispherical electron analyzer (CLAM2) and a non-monochromatic Mg K
 <sub>α</sub> X-ray source operated at 300 W. Spectra were collected at a pass energy of 20 eV (typical for high-resolution conditions). The area under each peak was calculated after subtraction of the S-shaped background and fitting the experimental curve to a combination of Lorentzian and Gaussian lines of variable proportions. Binding energies were calibrated to the C 1s peak at 285.0 eV. The atomic ratios were computed from the peak intensity ratios and reported atomic sensitivity factors. Morphological characterization was performed by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) using a JEOL JSM-7600F. For these observations, the powder samples were placed on an adhesive conductive carbon disk.
</p>
