<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Additional risks for climate mortality are related to gender, race and ethnicity, employment, and socioeconomic status. These are factors that are related to our national health disparities and are influenced by the determinants of health. These factors also cut to structural and social barriers for some groups within the U.S. population. Occupational risks of outdoor work and physical labor make men more vulnerable to climate change heat mortality [
 <xref rid="B64-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>,
 <xref rid="B86-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>,
 <xref rid="B87-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">87</xref>,
 <xref rid="B98-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>] and more likely to die from accidents and injury related to climate change [
 <xref rid="B39-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>] and dehydration [
 <xref rid="B28-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. However, other studies found that gender risk is more closely related to cause of death [
 <xref rid="B28-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>] and race with non-White women having higher risk of death [
 <xref rid="B35-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. Hispanic males [
 <xref rid="B88-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">88</xref>,
 <xref rid="B98-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>] and Black people were found to have higher risks of heat-related morbidity [
 <xref rid="B88-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">88</xref>]. Hispanic workers also had higher mortality than Native American [
 <xref rid="B98-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>], and non-Hispanic workers in all industries [
 <xref rid="B88-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">88</xref>]. Socioeconomic status, which is closely tied to occupation, racial and ethnic disparities, also influences climate change mortality as income affects adaptation to the environmental impacts of climate change [
 <xref rid="B21-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B50-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>,
 <xref rid="B72-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>].
</p>
