<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The electrolyte choice influences the Zn deposition morphology via a variety of processes—It determines the anisotropy of the energy landscape of the crystal facets, it influences the interface reaction kinetics, and it affects the rate and stability of mass transport processes. Here, we focus on the interphases formed by electrolytes in Zn batteries. We classify interphases as solid, by-product layers or precipitates that form a physical boundary between an electrolyte and an electrode, e.g., the SEI first proposed by Peled (
 <xref rid="R85" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>85</italic>
 </xref>) in 1979 to interpret the behavior of alkaline metal in nonaqueous electrolytes. The SEI has received enormous attention because of its hypothetical role in the formation of moss-like Li metal deposition (
 <xref rid="R84" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>84</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R86" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>86</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R87" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>87</italic>
 </xref>). While it is generally agreed that the SEI between the electrically conductive metal and the ionically conductive electrolyte notably complicates the transport phenomena at the interface, why and how it serves to regulate the morphology of metal electrodeposits remains controversial. One school of thought is that electrons access the arriving metal ions by tunneling through the SEI, another is that ions access electrons from the underlying metal via transport through the SEI (
 <xref rid="R88" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>88</italic>
 </xref>). In either scenario, a SEI that is simultaneously heterogeneous and insulative (in terms of electron and/or ion transport) would results in heterogeneous metal deposition by inducing preferential growth along local high-diffusivity pathways (
 <xref rid="R84" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>84</italic>
 </xref>). It is therefore important to reduce, even eliminate, the heterogeneity of the SEI layer and to promote the formation of a uniform, thin SEI that allows fast but homogeneous transport. As a point of departure toward this goal, the formation mechanisms of SEI in the electrolytes need to be understood.
</p>
