<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To date, a handful of reviews have been published on energy storage and conversion applications involving metal carbide and nitride-based nanostructured electrodes [
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. In particular, a number of reviews have summarized the synthetic strategies for and the role of MXenes in energy storage and conversion based on studies published before 2017 [
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. Very recently, Jun et al. provided a complete overview of MXene compounds for environmental and electrochemical storage applications [
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>], while the mechanisms of delamination and the role of MXene electrodes in dictating the cycling properties of LIBs were examined thoroughly by Zhang et al. [
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. However, these studies have not addressed the evolution of TMCs/TMNs into 2D layered TMCs/TMNs (i.e., MXene-based compounds) in the context of LOBs, and the electrochemical performance and storage properties of these batteries have not been summarized in detail. Therefore, a review that specifically focuses on nanostructured TMC/TMN cathode catalysts for LOBs has been long overdue. Because the role of anodes and electrolytes in LOBs have been extensively reported elsewhere [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,
 <xref rid="B29-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>], we do not address these in the present review; rather, we provide a comprehensive review of the electrochemical, physicochemical, and storage properties of both bulk and 2D layered TMCs and TMNs, counting the carbides and nitrides of Ti, V, Fe, and Mo and their composite counterparts, when used as active cathode catalysts in rechargeable LOBs. 
</p>
