<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In summary, we have determined the potential limits of graphene monolayer electrodes in neat 12CE upon cathodic and anodic sweeps and elucidated apparent electron transfer kinetics of the outer-sphere ferrocene/ferrocenium couple. We suggest that the observed lower stability in the cathodic regime is linked to electrochemical formation of radicals during choline reduction, which attack and degrade the monolayer graphene. By comparison to common glassy carbon bulk electrodes, we have found that the two-dimensional nature of our graphene electrodes critically impacts DES electrochemistry. For potentiodynamic Zn deposition from ZnCl
 <sub>2</sub> in 12CE, for instance, a significant 
 <italic>iR</italic> drop over the length of the graphene electrode, which is enhanced by the aforementioned radical attack, resulted in spatially graded amounts of deposited Zn. The spatial inhomogeneity of the zinc deposits and the graphene degradation are interrelated via graphene’s two-dimensional nature in which defects generated in the topmost (and only) layer decrease the overall electrode conductivity. This is in stark contrast to bulk carbon electrodes such as glassy carbon or HOPG for which the overall conductivity is hardly affected by defects in the topmost atomic layer and for which generated defects might even increase their electrochemical activity. For graphene in DESs, both the graphene degradation and the spatial inhomogeneity of deposits can however be avoided by potentiostatic deposition at less cathodic potentials. This was demonstrated by uniform electrodeposition of Ge from TBAGeCl
 <sub>3</sub> in 12CE onto graphene monolayer electrodes without any degradation of the graphene. Combined, our work highlights that while some aspects of the electrochemical behavior of graphene in 12CE are similar to those of bulk carbon materials such as glassy carbon or HOPG, other aspects in the graphene/12CE system are unique, because of graphene’s two-dimensional nature. These findings merit consideration for processing of graphene and related carbon (composite) materials in choline chloride-based DESs and for the application of these materials in such electrolytes.
</p>
