<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A vast majority of Arctic avifauna are migratory and use the region seasonally to breed, taking advantage of the short but strong burst of resources available in the summer months. Demographic rates respond to spatially and temporally variable environmental conditions, thus requiring detailed information on a species’ spatial distribution throughout the annual cycle to understand those relationships. Processes acting upon individuals may cause immediate or lagged responses in demographic rates across seasons, creating carry‐over or cross‐seasonal effects (Norris &amp; Taylor, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0066" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>; Sedinger &amp; Alisauskas, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0082" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>). Responses may also vary by age or sex or may differ across demographic rates (Rushing et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0075" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Understanding changes in environmental conditions throughout the annual cycle and their effects on demographic rates is therefore critical for predicting species’ responses to climate change. However, a large portion of what we understand to be climate effects on Arctic avifauna is related to conditions just prior to and during the breeding season (e.g., snow melt dates, phenological mismatches with weather conditions or food resources), or with conditions experienced in temperate or tropical latitudes during the nonbreeding season (Deinet et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0018" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Fox &amp; Leafloor, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0028" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Ganter &amp; Gaston, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0031" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Smith et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0088" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>). Currently, our understanding of these effects on avian species endemic to the Arctic is extremely limited (Ganter &amp; Gaston, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0031" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>). This limitation is often due to a lack of demographic and spatially relevant environmental data (but see e.g., Sedinger et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0084" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>).
</p>
