<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Waterfowl are among the most abundant avifauna on Arctic coastal and tundra habitats during the breeding period (CAFF, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0010" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>). Though most species leave the Arctic following the breeding season, most sea ducks (Tribe: Mergini), and more specifically eiders (
 <italic toggle="yes">Somateria and Polysticta</italic> genera), remain in the Arctic throughout the annual cycle (Ganter &amp; Gaston, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0031" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Savard et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0079" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Spectacled eiders (
 <italic toggle="yes">Somateria fischeri</italic>) are an endemic Arctic species and can be found in the Pacific Arctic (Bering and Chukchi Seas), Alaska, and Russia, a region experiencing drastic ecosystem change in response to climate change (Huntington et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0040" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>). A large sea duck, spectacled eiders spend most of the annual cycle in high latitude coastal and open‐ocean marine habitats and are often associated with sea ice (Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Savard et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0079" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Sexson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0086" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Their nonbreeding range remained largely unknown until 1995 when surveys identified large flocks in openings in the sea ice in the mid‐Bering sea (Petersen et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0068" ref-type="bibr">1999</xref>). The global population of spectacled eiders winters near St. Lawrence Island and migrates to breeding grounds in the coastal tundra wetlands of Alaska and Russia (Sexson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0085" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>). Following marked declines in the western Alaska breeding population the species was listed as threatened under the Endangered Species Act (ESA, as amended 1973) in 1993 (U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0091" ref-type="bibr">1993</xref>).
</p>
