<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Spectacled eiders use remote areas throughout the annual cycle making it particularly challenging to conduct comprehensive surveys or studies of demography. Several studies have focused on independent analyses of data sets to model population dynamics and demography of spectacled eiders (e.g., Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Dunham et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0020" ref-type="bibr">2021</xref>; Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>); however, estimating abundance and demographic rates has remained challenging. Evidence suggests that all four eider species demonstrate demographic responses, changes in abundance, and distribution shifts related to climate change and environmental conditions encountered throughout the annual cycle (e.g., Barry, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0006" ref-type="bibr">1968</xref>; Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Fournier &amp; Hines, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0027" ref-type="bibr">1994</xref>; Frost et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0029" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Sexson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0086" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Žydelis et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0096" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>). Variation in adult survival, breeding propensity, spring arrival dates, clutch size, annual nest success, and duckling survival of closely related common eiders (
 <italic toggle="yes">S</italic>. 
 <italic toggle="yes">mollissima</italic>) has been linked to environmental conditions experienced during both breeding and nonbreeding seasons (Coulson, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0013" ref-type="bibr">1984</xref>; Savard et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0079" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Waltho &amp; Coulson, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0092" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Recent studies suggest shifts in the Bering sea ecosystem have affected adult survival rates and the molting distribution of spectacled eiders (Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Sexson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0086" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>); however, relatively little is known about the effects of changes in environmental conditions on recruitment or population dynamics.
</p>
