<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Sea ice is a critical component of spectacled eider wintering habitat (Eamer et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0021" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Macias‐Fauria &amp; Post, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0062" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). The Bering sea is dominated by seasonal pack ice, densely packed ice that may drift in response to currents, wind, and storms. Pack ice in the mid‐Bering sea, where spectacled eiders winter, is dynamic and highly variable within and across years (Wang &amp; Overland, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0093" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Polynya and open leads in sea ice benefit spectacled eiders offering access to benthic prey and providing roosting habitat (Bump &amp; Lovvorn, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0009" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>; Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). Concentrated sea ice can dampen the effects of waves from frequent major storms which results in good roosting habitat (Cooper et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0012" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>). While extensive ice cover may restrict spectacled eider access to benthic prey and optimal foraging areas (Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0060" ref-type="bibr">2003</xref>), by contrast, declining sea ice cover has been linked to declines in abundance and shifting distributions of benthic communities, including the preferred prey species of spectacled eiders (Grebmeier, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0035" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>; Grebmeier et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0036" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Lovvorn et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0059" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0061" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Sea ice conditions in the Bering Sea are expected to become increasingly variable and sparse (Huntington et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0040" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>; Wang &amp; Overland, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0093" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>) with deleterious effects on the habitat for spectacled eiders and other species that are dependent on this marine ecosystem (Smith et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0087" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).
</p>
