<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To better understand the effects of climatic change on spectacled eider demography and population dynamics, we developed an integrated population model of the full annual cycle that combined multiple sources of data collected from the western Alaskan breeding population. Here, we use the integrated population modeling framework to (1) estimate demographic parameters (age‐specific survival rates, breeding probability, and productivity), (2) evaluate which demographic rates contribute most to annual population growth, and (3) investigate the effect of environmental conditions on demographic rates throughout the annual cycle. Recently, Christie et al. (
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>) documented a nonlinear relationship between sea ice conditions and adult female survival. We were interested in repeating and extending this analysis within an integrated framework. Thus, we evaluate the hypothesis that adult survival will vary in response to extreme sea ice conditions experienced during the wintering period. Similar to Christie et al. (
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>), we predicted that adult female survival would be highest in years with intermediate sea ice conditions and decline in years with extremely high or low sea ice conditions, because of restricted access to food versus reduced roosting habitat, respectively. Because the spatial distribution of first‐year birds is generally unknown, we examined the effect of the Arctic oscillation (AO), an important indicator of regional conditions, on first‐year survival to account for general environmental conditions experienced throughout the full annual cycle. Predation pressure and weather conditions (e.g., precipitation) can have strong impacts on annual nest success (DeGregorio et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0017" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Flint et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0025" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Mallory, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0063" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Therefore, we predicted that annual nest success would decline in years with poor weather conditions (e.g., high precipitation) and in years with high predation rates (e.g., increased fox presence). Furthermore, Lovvorn et al. (
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0058" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>) documented reduced body condition of spectacled eiders during winter in years with extensive sea ice cover thus, we predicted that annual nest success would be highest in years with average sea ice conditions and decline in years following extreme sea ice conditions in a pattern similar to adult survival. The underlying mechanism for this could involve incubation constancy, whereby females with higher body condition take fewer and shorter recesses from incubation (Blums et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0008" ref-type="bibr">1997</xref>; Gloutney &amp; Clark, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0032" ref-type="bibr">1991</xref>), in turn providing fewer cues to predators and visual exposure of their eggs, respectively. The results presented here provide useful insight for conservation and policy planning regarding the species’ current and future conditions related to climate change.
</p>
