<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Wang (2017) [
 <xref rid="B18-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] propose to classify the environmental technologies into 5 types:
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p>Eco-efficiency technology, the aim of this technology is reducing pollution by reducing the amount of required power and material in input to the process maintaining the same level of production; The purpose can be achieved by installing more energy-efficient equipment, by modifying the process, etc. The main advantages are related to the environmental and economic benefits: in fact, thanks to the use of eco-efficient technologies, significant economic savings are possible;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Low-carbon energy technology, the aim of these kind of technologies is to operate a transition to Low-carbon energy technology (biofuel, wind, solar, etc.) from the conventional energy sources (coal, oil, and so on). Using these technologies, it is expected to protect the climate thanks to the lowest carbon emission quotas. However, there are two main problems:
    <list list-type="order">
     <list-item>
      <p>Higher costs of procuring or generating low carbon energy than conventional energy;</p>
     </list-item>
     <list-item>
      <p>Integrating low-carbon energy into existing energy supply systems can disrupt the current operational process.</p>
     </list-item>
    </list>
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Green design technology, the aim of these kind of technologies is to reduce the pollutant contents of the products modifying, in particular, the design of the products (generally using more environmentally sustainable materials). The polluting contents of the product are usually measured on the basis of the life cycle analysis. Looking at technology from the demand side, “green” products are likely to become more attractive to environmentally conscious consumers. By analyzing the technology from the side of the company, we have that the design for regeneration or circulation can improve the recovery value of the products. Therefore, these technologies can have advantages both from an environmental point of view and from an economic point of view;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Pollution control technology, these kind of technologies (call also end of pipe) aims to eliminate the pollution at the end of the process with appropriate instruments. Pollution control technology usually involves burning, recycling, filtering, and catalyzing pollutants. Typical pollution control technologies include electro-filters, bag filters, scrubbers (dry and wet), use of activated carbon, SNCR, or SCR systems [
    <xref rid="B25-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
    <xref rid="B26-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>];
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Management system technology, these kind of technologies try to reduce pollutants upstream, before their formation [
    <xref rid="B27-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>] adapting the way operations are handled. This is generally achieved through monitoring, reporting of pollution events and through employee training programs to raise awareness of climate change issues.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Fawzy et al. [
    <xref rid="B19-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>] state that there are three main ways to mitigate climate change:
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Use of de-carbonization technologies and techniques in order to reduce CO
    <sub>2</sub> emissions. These include the use of renewable energy instead of fossil fuels, the use of nuclear energy, the storage and use of carbon capture. These are, in the first case, well-established technologies;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Use of so-called negative emissions technologies. These are recent technologies, which have not yet been studied in detail. These technologies are able to absorb CO
    <sub>2</sub> present in the atmosphere. These include bioenergy carbon capture and storage, biochar, enhanced weathering, direct air carbon capture and storage, ocean fertilization [
    <xref rid="B28-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>];
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Technologies based on the principle of altering the balance of terrestrial radiation through the management of solar and terrestrial radiation. Such techniques are deducted forced radiative geoengineering technologies, and the main objective is stabilization or temperature reduction. At present, radiative techniques of forced geoengineering are studied only from the point of view of scientific research and are not included in policy frameworks.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
