<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The existing literature suggests that medical students are aware of the health hazards associated with climate change [
 <xref rid="cit0017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>] and the Fridays For Future-movement, a global strike movement that started in August 2018, when Greta Thunberg began a school strike for climate in Sweden [
 <xref rid="cit0018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>], demonstrates how the younger generation can drive action on climate change. However, we feel it would be relevant to find out whether medical students also feel a responsibility to inform society about the effects of global climate change and take on the role of a climate advocate. After all, education on climate crisis and planetary health could encourage patients to become active against climate change themselves [
 <xref rid="cit0019" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. In addition, future doctors could potentially help their patients develop appropriate strategies to reduce the health risks of climate change at an individual level [
 <xref rid="cit0002" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="cit0020" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. In a similar way, health professionals contributed substantially that smoking today is considered a harmful behaviour, leading to the assumption that systematic education of physicians could also result in more educated patients regarding climate change [
 <xref rid="cit0021" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. In a definition published in 2012 [
 <xref rid="cit0022" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>], the European Health Literacy Consortium emphasized that health literacy also means that people can make independent judgments and decisions in everyday life in the areas of disease prevention and health promotion that ultimately maintain or improve their quality of life. Thus, educating patients about the many health hazards of climate change (just like educating them about the dangers of smoking) can be seen as an opportunity to turn patients into health literates.
</p>
