<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Four different uveitic processes associated with various pathologies have been related to a wide range of environmental factors, as can be seen in 
 <xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-ijerph-18-07197">Table S1</xref>. These groups are: 
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>(I).</label>
   <p>Infectious uveitis: Toxoplasmosis, Tuberculosis, Campylobacter, Chlamydia, Ocular Herpes simplex (VHS) and Zoster (VHZ), West Nile Fever, Borreliosis and Rickettsiosis, Shigellosis, Salmonellosis; the World Health Organization offers information about several pathogens and their infectivity [
    <xref rid="B62-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>,
    <xref rid="B63-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>], including those which are engaged in ocular diseases; a higher frequency of infectious uveitis has been highlighted during the summer [
    <xref rid="B64-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>], plus a change in patterns, incidence and prevalence [
    <xref rid="B65-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(J).</label>
   <p>Non-infectious uveitis associated with systemic diseases: Rheumatoid arthritis (RA), Ankylosing spondylitis (AS), Sarcoidosis, Multiple Sclerosis (MS), Inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD—Crohn and ulcer colitis), Behçet’s disease, Giant cells arteritis (Horton’s disease), Necrotizing systemic vasculitis.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(K).</label>
   <p>Connective tissue diseases: Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE), Dermatomyositis.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>(L).</label>
   <p>Uveitis merely as ocular disease, without associated systemic pathologies: Fuchs’ heterochronic Uveitis, Posner-Schlossmann syndrome, Intermedia uveitis and pars planitis, Birdshot choroidopathy, Vogt-Koyanagi-Harada syndrome (VKH), White Dots Syndromes [
    <xref rid="B66-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">66</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
