<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>When compared to air pollution, the link between COVID-19 and climate change is extremely ambiguous. Since COVID-19 events were detected in 2019, there was no clear evidence of climate change's effect on COVID-19, which is typically a long-term event (
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>). There was a recent review about climate change and the COVID-19 epidemic in Rodó et al. (
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>). They stated that both absolute humidity (AH) and temperature have been linked to influenza outbreaks and facilitated epidemic progression. In tropical regions, SARS-CoV-2 appears to have a higher airborne survival and transmission rate than the influenza virus. A blockade of aerosol transmission in the case of influenza virus has been described for temperature variations above 30°C. Whereas, the direct effect of the pandemic-driven response will be negligible, with a cooling a global temperature of around 0.01 ± 0.005°C by 2030 (
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>). This result was supported by the concept of anthropause that suggested that reduced human mobility during the pandemic will reveal critical aspects of our impact on animals, providing important guidance on how best to share space on this crowded planet (
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>). The global temperature signal, however, is anticipated to be small as a result of the pandemic's short-term dynamics. Another evidence that might correlate the relationship between climate and COVID-19 is using meteorological factors including the temperature, Relative Humidity (RH), AH, and Wind Speed (WS). Most studies in many countries, including Thailand, Singapore, India, and China, found a positive relationship between temperature and the daily number of COVID-19 cases (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>). Several research, however, found a negative association between temperature and COVID-19 cases. Wu et al. (
 <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>) and To et al. (
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>), for example, discovered that rising temperatures were associated with a decrease in daily new cases of COVID-19 in Brazil and Canada. Other variables, such as RH (%), AH (g/m
 <sup>3</sup>), and WS (m/s), had a positive relationship with the number of COVID-19 cases in many countries, including Thailand and Turkey (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>). Furthermore, relative humidity was found to be negatively correlated with daily new COVID-19 cases by Wu et al. (
 <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>). Another research provided experimental results demonstrating that lower relative humidity promotes influenza virus transmission, confirming this weather effect (
 <xref rid="B41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>). The SARS coronavirus's stability at low humidity can support its spread in communities in subtropical climates (such as Hong Kong) during the spring (
 <xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). For WS, the relationship with COVID-19 was identical to those of humidity and temperature, which have both positive (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>) and negative (
 <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>) relationships. WS, on the other hand, may potentially affect SARS-CoV-2 in an indoor rather than outdoor environment among symptomatic and asymptotic cases due to sneezing and coughing in population-dense areas.
</p>
