<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0260">Under the current levels of production, both consumer and producer prices will increase in the future. Adaptation strategies will increase groundnut yields at the farm level and could reduce the unit cost of production. The higher price and reduced production cost will provide an incentive to farmers to adopt yield increasing technologies and management options on larger areas. This will result in increasing groundnut production in India. Further the economic model projected a growing consumer demand for groundnut (shelled), confectionery groundnut, and oils in India, other south Asian countries, and the rest of the world. India is the second-largest exporter of groundnuts and its products after China (
 <xref rid="bb0020" ref-type="bibr">Birthal et al., 2010</xref>), and Indian groundnuts are competitive in international markets (
 <xref rid="bb0165" ref-type="bibr">Reddy and Bantilan, 2012</xref>). It is reasonable to expect that Indian farmers will continue to expand groundnut production by adopting various adaptation options to increase production to partially offset/minimize the negative impacts of climate change on yields, and also capitalize on the growing demand in India and the rest of the world. This will help India retain its position in the international groundnut market. From this study, it was also evident that endogenous behavioral responses such as food demand, area and other production factors are found to be very critical in differentiating final yield impacts from initial exogenous climate shocks. Hence it is essential to combine climate, crop, and economic models to estimate changes in yields and other parameters. The final yields estimated under this study captured the soil, climate, and crop management interactions, as well as market effects. Including socio-economic parameters while studying the climate change impacts will help policymakers and international donors to better understand the consequences of targeted actions in their priority setting exercises. However, the study has some limitations as models are not very effective in capturing extreme weather events, changes in pests and diseases, and ozone levels (
 <xref rid="bb0115" ref-type="bibr">Lobell and Gourdji, 2012</xref>).
</p>
