<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0225">We observed that projected reductions in groundnut yields due to climate change by 2050 are larger for some FPUs under pessimistic climate scenario and positive for the majority of FPUs except the Ganges basin under optimistic scenarios. The positive response is mainly due to increased mean annual rainfall amounts and CO
 <sub>2</sub> fertilization. Further high year to year variation in rainfall coupled with high intensity rainfall events in the Ganges basin might have resulted in reduction in groundnut yields. The pessimistic scenario also shows some yield increase in the Godavari, Luni, and Krishna basins and negative impact in the Ganges, Indus, and Tapti basins. The negative impacts in these FPUs were attributed mainly due to relative high increase in both minimum and maximum temperatures compared to baseline scenarios in other FPUs (
 <xref rid="f0050" ref-type="graphic">Supplementary Fig. 4</xref>). 
 <xref rid="bb0225" ref-type="bibr">Williams and Boote, 1995</xref>; 
 <xref rid="bb0220" ref-type="bibr">Weiss, 2000</xref> found that optimum temperature for quick vegetative development in groundnut was between 25 and 30 °C and 35 °C for flower appearance and pegging (
 <xref rid="bb0145" ref-type="bibr">Prasad et al., 2003</xref>). Both GCMs predict an increase in mean maximum and minimum temperatures of more than 3–4 °C during the crop growth period. Several temperature tolerance studies in various field crops showed that increased temperatures during crop growth accelerates phenological development and advances the flowering date (
 <xref rid="bb0350" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2009</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bb0350" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2015</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bb0230" ref-type="bibr">Ye et al., 2020</xref>). Similarly, in groundnut, high temperatures might have resulted in faster crop senescence and poor seed filling due to increased demand for sink for assimilates because of other yield-limiting conditions (
 <xref rid="bb0110" ref-type="bibr">Kumar et al., 2012</xref>;
 <xref rid="bb0195" ref-type="bibr">Singh et al., 2014a</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bb0200" ref-type="bibr">Singh et al., 2014b</xref>). In the current study, analysis of model output data across locations revealed that change in the duration of crop growth phases and hastening of crop maturity, decrease in the number of pods per plant and seed size were the main reasons for low yields in groundnut.
</p>
