<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Li-ion batteries (LIBs) have been successfully employed in a wide range of applications, such as electric vehicles, microelectronic devices, etc., due to their remarkable properties such as high energy density, lack of memory effect, long cycle life, low self-discharge and high thermal resistance [
 <xref rid="B1-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. A large variety of carbon-based materials for LIBs have been widely investigated, such as graphene, fullerene and carbon nanotubes (CNT) [
 <xref rid="B4-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. For instance, a high capacity of a sandwich-like and porous NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>@reduced graphene oxide (rGO) nanocomposite serving as anode material was reported by Huang’s group [
 <xref rid="B11-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Kumar et al. synthesized octahedral iron oxide nanocrystals on reduced graphene oxide nanosheets by a microwave-assisted process [
 <xref rid="B12-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Zhang et al. demonstrated that electrodeposition can be used to prepare NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>/graphene [
 <xref rid="B13-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], while Chen et al. prepared graphene hybrid nanosheet arrays via a one-pot procedure [
 <xref rid="B14-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]; these synthesized graphene electrodes delivered good electrochemical performances. More recently, rapid research progress has been made in exploring flexible anode materials delivering high storage capacity and remarkable long-term cyclability [
 <xref rid="B15-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. As an allotrope of carbon, CNT electrodes offer several outstanding properties, such as excellent flexibility, fast charge transport, large surface-to-volume ratio, good chemical stability, high electrical conductivity and high reversible capacity [
 <xref rid="B18-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="B23-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B26-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Several methods to synthesize CNT have been demonstrated, e.g., chemical vapor deposition (CVD) [
 <xref rid="B25-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>], pyrolysis [
 <xref rid="B28-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>], arc discharge [
 <xref rid="B29-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,
 <xref rid="B30-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], laser ablation [
 <xref rid="B31-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] and electrolysis [
 <xref rid="B32-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. These methods allowed the growth of CNT with various morphology, structure and properties. 
</p>
