<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>As a potential flexible anode material, our previous report showed that the CNT reached a higher specific capacity (more than 700 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup>) compared to a traditional graphite anodes (372 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup>) [
 <xref rid="B33-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]. Also, Yoon et al. [
 <xref rid="B34-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>] reported that heat-treated CNT can deliver a reversible capacity of 446 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 0.5 C, with a low Initial Coulombic Efficiency (ICE) of 9.6%. Zhou et al. [
 <xref rid="B35-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>] reported that CNT showing bamboo-like structure delivered a reversible capacity of 135 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> with ICE of 17.3%. Li et al. studied a high-concentration, nitrogen-doped CNT anode providing reversible capacity of 494 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> [
 <xref rid="B21-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>], while Welna et al. [
 <xref rid="B36-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>] demonstrated that vertically aligned MWCNT-based anodes showed an excellent lithium storage capacity of 980 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> in the initial cycle which stabilized after first few cycles, delivering a discharge capacity of 750 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup>. Despite CNT exhibiting remarkable features as flexible anode materials, major challenges, such as the huge surface area of the CNT promoting a high capacity loss in the first initial cycles, needs to be first tackled [
 <xref rid="B37-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="B38-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. Consequently, CNT-based electrodes have a low ICE due to the solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) film formation upon the initial lithiation. This SEI film formation consumes a high amount of Li ions during the first discharge, which further limits the electrochemical performance of the cells, particularly when the CNT anode is coupled with the cathode material in full-cell configuration [
 <xref rid="B39-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B41-polymers-12-00406" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>].
</p>
