<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Given the great promise these catalysts hold, it is of importance to explore approaches for obtaining them in a sustainable fashion. A reasonable starting point would be to use inexpensive and readily available materials as sources for carbon, nitrogen, and iron, as opposed to sometimes expensive and/or toxic chemicals. In this regard, biomass is an attractive renewable natural resource because it is typically rich in carbon and nitrogen, and some forms contain metal elements such as iron or cobalt. These metal elements are key to the formation of highly active catalytic centers for ORR.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
 </sup> Progress has been made in this direction. Doped carbon ORR catalysts have been made from plants,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> plant products,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> biomass wastes of animal or human origin,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> fungi,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>
 </sup> and microorganisms.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>
 </sup> Of particular interest among these biomass resources are plants because some plants are able to selectively store metals.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup> Therefore, they can be used to remove toxic metals from contaminated soil or water (phytoremediation)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref>
 </sup> or enrich valuable metals from mineral wastes (phytomining).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>
 </sup> It is envisioned that doped carbons with high catalytic activity can be obtained from these metal-rich plants.
</p>
