<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The relationship between air pollution and coronavirus is ambiguous, which was indicated by both positive and negative correlation in the current studies (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1</xref>). Many studies have revealed that air pollution increases the COVID-19 mortality rate, whereas COVID-19 lockdown could reduce air pollution level at the same time. There is some evidence from recent studies revealing that increased risk of COVID-19 infection is associated with exposure to higher air pollutant levels including PM
 <sub>2.5</sub>, PM
 <sub>10</sub>, CO, NO
 <sub>2</sub>, SO
 <sub>2</sub>, and O
 <sub>3</sub>. For example, Wu et al. (
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>) and Cole et al. (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>), have found that long-term exposure to PM
 <sub>2.5</sub> was associated with a substantial 11% increased risk of cardiovascular death and hospital admissions. In addition, according to a study conducted in Milan, Italy, all recorded daily new COVID-19 cases were positively correlated with the average surface PM
 <sub>2.5</sub> and the daily maximum PM
 <sub>10</sub> (
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>). Several studies discussed the relationship between O
 <sub>3</sub> and NO
 <sub>x</sub> and COVID-19 but it was unclear in those studies. The current research discovered both a negative (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>) and a positive (
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>) correlation between NO
 <sub>x</sub> and COVID-19 in various parts of the world. However, as the role in flagging SARS-CoV-2 transmission, O
 <sub>3</sub> was importantly correlated with COVID-19 (
 <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>). Unfortunately, there has been relatively little research into the relationship between CO and SO
 <sub>2</sub>. Sangkham et al. (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>) discovered that increases in CO and SO
 <sub>2</sub> were correlated with decreases in the daily number of COVID-19 cases, while another study recently indicated that 1 g/m
 <sup>3</sup> CO is associated with a 15.11% increase in the daily count of confirmed COVID-19 cases (
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>). Meanwhile, a SO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration of 10 g/m
 <sup>3</sup> was associated with a 7.79% decrease in the regular number of reported cases in China's 120 cities (
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>). As a result, there is insufficient evidence for conclusive findings for CO and SO
 <sub>2</sub> in the current study, leading to these variables being both negatively and positively associated with SARS-CoV-2 transmission. At the same time, some studies indicated that COVID-19's indirect effect could help alleviate the problem of air pollution. For example, Mostafa et al. (
 <xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>) reported a strong correlation between COVID-19 lockdown and a 15–33% reduction in NO
 <sub>2</sub> and 5% reduction throughout CO in Egypt. Kumari and Toshniwal (
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>), studied a similar situation that occurred in India. They estimated that the COVID-19 lockdown could reduce PM
 <sub>10</sub>, PM
 <sub>2.5</sub>, NO
 <sub>2</sub>, and SO
 <sub>2</sub> concentrations by 55, 49, 60, and 19%, respectively, in Delhi and Mumbai. This finding was corroborated by Wetchayont (
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>), who discovered that several air pollutant concentrations, including PM
 <sub>2.5</sub>, PM
 <sub>10</sub>, O
 <sub>3</sub>, and CO, showed a significant decline during the COVID-19 outbreak in Bangkok, Thailand.
</p>
