<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The archaeology of climate change arises from the history of close collaborations between archaeologists, natural scientists, and climatologists. It builds on prior efforts to document an archaeology of environmental change (e.g., ref. 
 <xref rid="r92" ref-type="bibr">93</xref>) and harnesses 21st-century increases in computing capacity and the widespread adoption of machine-learning and modeling techniques. Computational archaeology, the use of computer-based analytical methods to study the archaeological record, is uniquely situated to leverage these developments and forms an intrinsic part of climate change research in archaeology. Early research on the impact of climate change on human systems tended to adopt an inductive approach, focusing on correlating changes in the archaeological record with climate events. Modeling approaches are used both inductively and deductively. Models can be designed to test hypotheses generated from anthropological or evolutionary theory about the sensitivity of human systems to environmental change across a range of temporal and spatial scales. They can focus on the mechanisms underlying human–environment interactions and explore their biological, social and ecological ramifications [i.e., human niche construction (
 <xref rid="r93" ref-type="bibr">94</xref>)]. Complex systems approaches provide a framework for this type of modeling, with established methods for exploring mechanistic linkages across spatial and temporal scales, how human systems react to environmental tipping points, and how patterns emerge at the population level from the collective actions of individuals (
 <xref rid="r94" ref-type="bibr">95</xref>). This includes methods for evaluating the adaptive capacity of human systems, for example by simulating the effects of changing decision rules about land use, reproduction, or mobility in response to environmental change. Cross-cultural analysis of the human past illustrates the diverse adaptive choices people have made and computational modeling allows us to further experiment with the impacts of those choices using specific high-resolution environmental reconstructions.
</p>
