<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>By way of example, the Hominin Dispersals Research Group conducts multidisciplinary research on the archaeology of climate change within an integrative, collaborative research framework. The group tests anthropologically driven research hypotheses using the archaeological record, natural archives, and climate models. Ethnographic information about the decision-making processes used by contemporary foragers, for example, was used to hypothesize that climate variability, which affects the ability to predict the distribution of resources and thus the outcome of foraging and mobility decisions, would have been a significant element of ecological risk to which past foragers will have been sensitive. High-resolution climate model outputs, developed for the project (
 <xref rid="r95" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>), were used to quantify climate variability on a subannual scale relevant for forager decision-making. Climate proxies from archaeological sites were used to test the downscaled climate model producing valuable information about the relationship between biogenic isotope signatures and climate (
 <xref rid="r96" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>). A suite of environmental variables, including climate variability, was then used to test the hypothesis using the archaeological record of Western Europe during the Last Glacial Maximum. The results of this experiment show that seasonal patterns of climate variability are key predictors of the spatial behavior of past human foragers (
 <xref rid="r97" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>). The resulting model of habitat suitability was then used to design an agent-based model to test how habitat suitability structures patterns of human land use, population structure, connectivity, and patterns of gene flow (
 <xref rid="r98" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>) with implications for cultural reproduction that are still being explored. The implications of the habitat suitability model for the adoption of different human mobility strategies were then tested using the archaeological record and lithic retouch frequencies in a diachronic study (
 <xref rid="r99" ref-type="bibr">100</xref>). The results of this collaborative research program demonstrate the value of a multidisciplinary approach for each of the disciplines involved. Climate records and climate proxies provide detailed, multiscalar information about a diversity of environmental contexts and anthropologically driven research questions result in new interpretations of the archaeological record while allowing broader hypotheses about the mechanisms underpinning human–environment dynamics, e.g., the role of stochasticity as a factor in human decision-making, to be tested.
</p>
