<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Natural archives provide a record of ecosystem structure prior to large-scale anthropogenic modification, i.e., a “baseline” against which the scale of human disturbance can be measured (
 <xref rid="r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). This, in turn, highlights the potential vulnerabilities and long-term sustainability of past human adaptations. Evidence for past anthropogenic disturbance in the Neotropics, for example, is best understood by considering the ecosystems with which the archaeological data interact (
 <xref rid="r117" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>). Archaeological perspectives are emerging as increasingly important in informing decision-making in the context of maximizing food security for the world’s growing population (
 <xref rid="r118" ref-type="bibr">119</xref>). The study of early farming communities offers concrete examples of the contribution archaeology can make to sustainability. Early farming communities provide models for sustainable food production, land and water management under a range of climate conditions that can be applied to contemporary situations (
 <xref rid="r119" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>). On the other hand, the fates of early farming communities, played out over the long term, also illustrate the fact that “sustainability” is a historically contingent concept (
 <xref rid="r119" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>). Archaeological models for the development of more sustainable, locally scaled adaptations to ensure food security in the coming decades include the readoption of multicropping agriculture based on the “three sisters” (i.e., corn, squash, beans) in northeastern North America (
 <xref rid="r120" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>) and strategies for mitigating risk in the event of potentially disruptive weather events such as El Niño (
 <xref rid="r121" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>). Archaeology’s contribution in this sense is twofold, in that it documents both cultigens and the tools and techniques used to cultivate and process them (
 <xref rid="r122" ref-type="bibr">123</xref>). Similar studies combining climate and human behavioral modeling with experimental farming have been conducted in the American Southwest in collaboration with Hopi maize farmers (
 <xref rid="r123" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>
 <xref rid="r124" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r125" ref-type="bibr">126</xref>) and the long-term coevolutionary relationship between Indigenous people and food webs in Australia (
 <xref rid="r126" ref-type="bibr">127</xref>).
</p>
