<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<table-wrap id="Tab3">
 <label>Table 3</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Research themes and core concepts identified within key research focussing on ‘Sensemaking’ presented for each focus level (whether the articles examined the managerial, organisational or general societal populations)</p>
 </caption>
 <table frame="hsides" rules="groups">
  <thead>
   <tr>
    <th align="left">Focus Level</th>
    <th align="left">Research Theme</th>
    <th align="left">Core Concepts</th>
    <th align="left">References</th>
   </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
   <tr>
    <td align="left" rowspan="6">Managerial</td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Making Sense</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Individuals social process of making sense (or sensemaking) of new issues or information that are complex, surprising or confusing. Process is evolving and shifts over time with the introduction of new information. E.g. market information for developing strategy; technological information;</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Ongoing</italic>- Ongoing process, dynamic and evolving
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Construction</italic>- Sense constructed over time. Meaning of sustainability needs to be constructed and shared in a setting
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Communicating</italic>- Language constructs reality. Common vocabulary enhances understanding e.g. along supply chain. Role of discourses
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Categorising</italic>- Fitting new information in structures or new categories for decision-making
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Shaped</italic>- Sensemaking process is shaped by others e.g. managers shape the sensemaking process of others when they make sense and set goals or strategies. Shaped by individual’s knowledge structure
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Trade-offs</italic>- All issues cannot be prioritised at once. Paradox need to be understood before being managed
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Interpretation</italic>- The process of translation of new information into knowledge
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>van der Heijden &amp; Crammer (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR81">2017</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Khan (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">2018</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Fontana (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2019</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Bien &amp; Sassen (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">2020</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Child (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">2019</xref>)
     </p>
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Giving Meaning</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Sense giving refers to the process of disseminating new views and shaping meaning. E.g strategy implementation</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Sharing</italic>- Sense is shared through communication and action to give meaning and create a shared understanding
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Communicating</italic>- Language communicates reality. Common vocabulary enhances understanding. New meme’s or narratives
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Acting</italic>- Action translates meaning and develops shared understanding
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Change Agents</italic>- Role of change agents in shifting action over time. A change agent is a sensemaker who’s actions and sensemaking process shape a shared view
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Cyclic</italic>- Process of gradual cyclic change
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Transfer</italic>- Sense transferred between actors
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Influencing</italic>- An active, conscious process. Executives can influence from top down
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>van der Heijden &amp; Crammer (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR81">2017</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Khan (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">2018</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Waddock (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>)
     </p>
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Factors Influencing Sensemaking</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Sensemaking influenced by practical and social factors. Degree of influence may depend on individuals position in the company. E.g. of Influences: Individual influences or collective influences; negative influence of perceived hypocrisy; social circles; emotions and desire for social status; decision makers maybe more likely influenced by financial factors while also shaped by cultural social conventions. shaped by past sector issues e.g. Rana Plaza incident. Individuals connected with the environment e.g. farmers may derive meaning from it. Factors may be individual; organisational or from outside the organisation</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Shaping</italic>- Factors continuously shaping sensemaking process. Individuals knowledge structure shapes the sensemaking process
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Trade-offs</italic>- Actors may be aware of the negative financial payback but still proceed based on perceived elevation of their social status derived from the investment. Business expectations and moral purpose
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Creative</italic>- Constructing a new meaning requires active imagination
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>Fontana (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2019</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Waddock (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Fassin et al. (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2011</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Babua et al. (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">2020</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Tisch &amp; Galbreath (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR77">2018</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Aguinis &amp; Glavas (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">2019</xref>)
     </p>
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Sensemaking in Investment</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Managers must make sense of new innovations before they are willing to invest. E.g. Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED)</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <italic>Change</italic>
     <italic>Agents</italic>- Executives as change agents
    </td>
    <td align="left">Fontana (
     <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2019</xref>)
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Patterns of Sensemaking</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Patterns of sensemaking found to exist linked to individuals influences. e.g. opportunistic sensemaking; win–win sensemaking; hygienic sensemaking; philanthropic sensemaking</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <italic>Categorised</italic>- Patterns of sensemaking observed after decision makers have reviewed information and balanced trade-offs
    </td>
    <td align="left">Fontana (
     <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2019</xref>)
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Sensemaking Leader</italic>
     </p>
     <p>“The leader as shaman has three central roles: healer, connector, and sensemaker in the service of a better world” Waddock, 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>
     </p>
     <p>Leaders towards action on climate change need to recognise the need to shift, conceptualise the change and actively cultivate a new way</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Redefining</italic>- Leaders can shift the discussion and culture towards sustainability and responsibility (from growth and profit). Changing values, business strategy and culture. Shaping the shift to values other than profit may be easier in SME
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Leading</italic>- Leading the change through capability development, investment and sensegiving
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>Waddock (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Fassin et al. (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2011</xref>)
     </p>
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left" rowspan="3">Organisational</td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Frames on Sensemaking</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Organisational sensemaking shaped by mental models thereby operating in a perceived environment</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <italic>Influenced</italic>- Shaped by frames
    </td>
    <td align="left">Basu &amp; Palazzo (
     <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">2008</xref>)
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Organisational Sensemaking</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Basu and Palazzo (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">2008</xref>) proposed organisational sensemaking involves three processes: (1) Cognitive (firms relationship with stakeholders and views about the external environment); (2) linguistic (explaining reasons for decisions or actions with others); and (3) conative (adopted behaviour)
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Determining</italic>- Sensemaking process determines a company’s character
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Communicating</italic>- Sensemaking can be demonstrated by a company’s use of language
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>Basu &amp; Palazzo (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">2008</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Green &amp; Peloza (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">2015</xref>)
     </p>
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Process of Organisational Sensemaking—Making Collective Sense</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Although sensemaking is completed at an individual level social relationships may lead to community level sense. Organisational sensemaking occurs through a process involving change agents, communication and action. A shared meaning is constructed through social interaction – colleagues come to see their environment in a common way</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Enactment</italic>- Perception and action. Approaches for operationalizing sense giving–pragmatic strategy (within goals) or systemic strategy (within systems and policy) (van Der Heijden et al., 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR82">2010</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Change agents</italic>- Mediators in translating company sense
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Communicating</italic>- Social interactions and communications share sense. Sense can also be shared across platforms based on issues
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Sharing</italic>- A shared meaning is constructed through social interaction. Collective sense shared through community
     </p>
     <p>
      <italic>Action</italic>- Action driven sensemaking. Shared view created through action. Beliefs shape actions and actions shape beliefs
     </p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>Tisch &amp; Galbreath (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR77">2018</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>van Der Heijden et al. (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR82">2010</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Štumberger &amp; Golob (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR76">2016</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Benn et al. (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">2013</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Selsky &amp; Parker (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">2011</xref>)
     </p>
     <p>Dwyer &amp; Hardy (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">2016</xref>)
     </p>
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left" rowspan="2">General Population</td>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Influences in </italic>
      <xref rid="Sec16" ref-type="sec">
       <italic>Sensemaking</italic>
      </xref>
     </p>
     <p>Sensemaking influenced by practical and social factors including experience</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <italic>Shaping</italic>- Factors shaping the sensemaking process dependent on ecological embeddedness and degree of experience in similar situation
    </td>
    <td align="left">Whiteman &amp; Cooper (
     <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR92">2011</xref>)
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td align="left">
     <p>
      <italic>Patterns of Sensemaking</italic>
     </p>
     <p>Patterns of sensemaking found to exist linked to individuals influences</p>
    </td>
    <td align="left">
     <italic>Categorised</italic>- Patterns of sensemaking observed
    </td>
    <td align="left">Whiteman &amp; Cooper (
     <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR92">2011</xref>)
    </td>
   </tr>
  </tbody>
 </table>
</table-wrap>
