<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Beyond the interphase is the electrolyte, which influences the electrodeposition via physical (mass transport, electroconvection, etc.) and chemical mechanisms (reaction kinetics, SEI formation, etc.) as already discussed (
 <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4</xref>). Most of the effort devoted to the modification of aqueous electrolytes fall into three subcategories as illustrated in the blue block. Electrolyte additive is perhaps the most extensively explored direction through the recent decades as evidenced by the large volume of works published on it. The additives can work chemically—e.g., trace amount of Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> additive codeposits with Zn, promotes the growth of (002) basal plane, and suppresses the dendrite initiation (
 <xref rid="R176" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>176</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R178" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>178</italic>
 </xref>) —or physically—e.g., 0.5 to 2 weight % (wt %) of PEG additive (molecular weight, 8 × 10
 <sup>6</sup> g/mol) reduces the average flow velocity, eliminates regions of high local velocity, and thereby extends the overpotential range where the electrodeposition remains stable (
 <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6G</xref>, top) (
 <xref rid="R72" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>72</italic>
 </xref>). A general, physically based framework for understanding the effects of additive on electrodeposition morphology is established by Haataja 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (
 <xref rid="R179" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>179</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R180" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>180</italic>
 </xref>). It is shown that small quantities of molecular additive species will preferentially adsorb onto and accumulate near surface protrusions and thereby stabilize the electrodeposition in a regime below a critical flux 
 <italic>J</italic>* (
 <xref rid="F6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6G</xref>, bottom). In reality, the additives can undergo additional, chemistry-specific interactions with the electrodeposits. Despite the obvious diversity of the additives, we note that most of their work mechanism can be understood when one refers to the previous sections of the present work.
</p>
