<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par55">Combined with patterns of sensitivity and future exposure, adaptive strategies may arise. Therefore, from a management point of view, the areas with high ecosystem services value, high exposure, and high sensitivity such as the Nyingchi, Sannan, Hengduan Mountains, the surrounding area of Qinghai Lake should have special protection, since ecosystem services in these regions experience higher climate disturbance and deviate from the equilibrium state more easily. The rapid urbanization also may weaken resistance to future climate change. In this context, it would be relevant to limit urban expansion. The establishment of protected areas or the construction of ecological corridors is considered as an effective mitigation measure (Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">2018a</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">b</xref>). However, according to the current distribution of protected areas, their effect on ecosystem services is likely reduced. The current distribution has a big gap for ecosystem service conservation, and only 15% of priority areas with high ecosystem service and biodiversity value are covered by protected areas (Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">2020</xref>). Also, the results of exposure revealed that low proportion of the negative exposure are covered by existing protected areas for CS, WR, and HQ, respectively (Fig. S12). This shows that the existing protected areas have important conservation gaps for ecosystem services and future exposure, especially in the southeastern of the study area (Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">2019</xref>). The distribution of the protected areas needs to be optimized. Given interlaced distributions of positive exposure and negative exposure (Fig. S9), some future management options to improve the ecosystems could be established such as grazing exclusion and ecosystem restoration (e.g., grasslands, forests) that can increase the resilience to future climate change (Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">2018b</xref>; Wang et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR99">2018</xref>). In regions with low exposure but high sensitivity, the future climate may be stable. However, ecosystem services here may be sensitive to small disturbances. Therefore, management strategies, including planting trees with particular traits (e.g., vegetative reproduction and disease tolerance), can be adopted (Millar et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">2007</xref>). For the regions with high intensity in climate change velocity (e.g., Nagqu and Golmud), ecosystems will be subjected to different climate conditions than they experienced today (Fig. S9). In these regions, the delimitations of areas with a reduced human footprint that could serve as climate refugees to plants would be essential (Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">2018a</xref>). Considering the natural system’s regulate ability (Pielke et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR71">2011</xref>), high input–output ratio, and relatively stable climate, no additional adaptation measures are required in low exposure and low-value areas such as Bayingolin.
</p>
