<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig4">
 <label>Fig. 4</label>
 <caption>
  <title>Holocene changes at the North Water as evidenced by marine and lake multi-proxy records.</title>
  <p>The blocks shaded in grey indicate periods of polynya instability. The main phases of human prehistory in Northwest Greenland are represented by bars. Stars on the individual proxy time -series indicate points of significant change based on generalised additive model (GAM) statistics (see ‘Methods’ and Supplementary Figs. 
   <xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>–
   <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">15</xref>), and dashed vertical lines denote significant changes in more than one proxy at the same time. 
   <bold>a</bold> Marine primary production as indicated by the fluxes of 
   <italic>Chaetoceros</italic> resting spores. 
   <bold>b</bold> Marine primary production as indicated by fluxes of diatoms (excluding 
   <italic>Chaetoceros</italic> resting spores). 
   <bold>c</bold> Fluxes of the sea ice biomarker IP
   <sub>25</sub>. 
   <bold>d</bold> Fluxes of the ice-marginal zone indicator HBI III (z triene). 
   <bold>e</bold> Principal component 1 for the marine record proxies (Supplementary Fig. 4 and Supplementary Table 
   <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). 
   <bold>f</bold> Principal component 1 for the lake record proxies (Supplementary Figs. 
   <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>, 
   <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref> and Supplementary Table 
   <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). 
   <bold>g</bold> Principal Components 1 and 2 for the lake diatom assemblages (Supplementary Fig. 
   <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>). 
   <bold>h</bold> Changes in Cadmium (Cd) to Titanium (Ti) ratios tracing the level of Cd-enrichment of the lake sediments by bird guano. The dark line shows a LOESS smoothed curve. 
   <bold>i</bold> δ
   <sup>15</sup>. 
   <bold>j</bold> A combination of total cholesterol flux, and the ratio of cholesterol to cholesterol plus β-sitosterol (greyscale) indicates relative bird colony size. RWP Roman Warm Period, DA Dark Ages cold period, MCA Medieval Climate Anomaly, LIA Little Ice Age, LD Late Dorset.
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41467_2021_24742_Fig4_HTML" id="d32e1236" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
