<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xml:lang="EN" article-type="news"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Cent Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Cent Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">oc</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acscii</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Central Science</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">2374-7943</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2374-7951</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">8323111</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.1c00819</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>The Hub</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Climate Change Could Alter Undersea Chemical Communication</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Wilke</surname><given-names>Carolyn</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>15</day><month>07</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><day>28</day><month>07</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>7</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1091</fpage><lpage>1094</lpage><history/><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; 2021 American Chemical
Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>Permits non-commercial access and re-use, provided that author attribution and integrity are maintained; but does not permit creation of adaptations or other derivative works (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>oc1c00819</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>oc1c00819</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta><notes id="notes-d4e21-autogenerated"><title>&#x0200b;</title><p>In collaboration with <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://cen.acs.org/index.html">C&#x00026;EN</ext-link>.</p></notes></front><body><p id="sec1">A pair of spiny lobsters locks
antennae as they battle on the gravel-strewn bottom of an aquarium.
The two grapple, grabbing legs and jousting with their long spines. Their
aggressive actions extend beyond the show of force: the crustaceans
also fire off chemical signals by peeing at each other.</p><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc1c00819_0003" id="GRAPHIC-d7e74-autogenerated" position="float"><caption><p>Small changes
in pH change how female shore crabs (<italic>Carcinus maenas</italic>) care for their eggs. Credit: Mike Park/University of Hull.</p></caption></graphic><p>&#x0201c;They&#x02019;re actively signaling as
they&#x02019;re fighting,&#x0201d; says Charles D. Derby, a sensory
biologist at Georgia State University whose lab studies these underwater
wrestling matches, along with other crustacean behaviors. Lobster
urine, released from the face near the base of the antennae, contains
an array of compounds, including <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.026492">chemical cues</ext-link> to an animal&#x02019;s
sex and social status.</p><p>Lobsters are just one of myriad marine
animals that rely on molecular missives. Behaviors such as finding
meals, choosing habitats, avoiding predators, seeking sex, and engaging
in social encounters &#x0201c;are all driven by chemistry, at least
in part,&#x0201d; Derby says. By playing key roles in how critters
act and relate to each other, chemical signals affect the distribution
of organisms in an ecosystem. Chemoreceptors are found not only in
noses or mouths; in marine animals, they also show up on fins, limbs,
or, as in lobsters, antennae that they flick back and forth.</p><p>A changing climate may make chemical communication for sea creatures
more challenging. By the year 2100, the pH of the ocean&#x02014;currently
about 8.1&#x02014;is expected to drop to 7.7 if atmospheric carbon
dioxide continues to rise. Over the past decade, research has revealed
how sensitive chemoreception systems are and how they may take a hit
from human activities that cause pollution, warming waters, and ocean
acidification. For instance, higher CO<sub>2</sub> levels in the water
cause juvenile sea bass to <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cen.acs.org/environment/climate-change/Fish-struggle-smell-acidic-oceans/96/i31">lose sensitivity to some smells</ext-link>. In the wild, that could
make it harder for the fish to find food and can render them more
vulnerable to predators, says Peter C. Hubbard, an electrophysiologist
at the Center of Marine Sciences in Portugal. And for migratory fish,
such as salmon, lowered olfactory sensitivity may mean difficulty
in navigating rivers for spawning.</p><p>Many studies have reported
changes to fish olfaction and behavior with increased CO<sub>2</sub> levels. Recently, a group of marine scientists has <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2021/05/does-ocean-acidification-alter-fish-behavior-fraud-allegations-create-sea-doubt">raised doubts</ext-link> about the data in some of these papers and
the methodology the studies used to test behavioral changes in fish
due to increased CO<sub>2</sub>, a controversy that has cost the field
some of its credibility.</p><p>But many researchers agree that acidification
would impact ecologically and <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cen.acs.org/articles/95/i20/shellfish-adapt-ocean-acidification.html">economically important species</ext-link> through changes to the
water&#x02019;s chemistry. That makes it important to investigate the
underlying mechanisms and the magnitude of the effects. Understanding
such mechanisms could help make sense of confusing, difficult-to-replicate
behavioral findings. So scientists continue to work to untangle the
basic workings of marine chemoreception, from identifying signaling
molecules to finding the receptors that they bind.</p><sec id="sec2"><title>A chemical language</title><p>The molecular words that form the ocean&#x02019;s chemical language
present a scientific puzzle. &#x0201c;The language is very, very complex,&#x0201d;
says Julia Kubanek, a marine chemist at Georgia Institute of Technology.
Potentially thousands of molecules are important for conveying information to
ocean organisms, she says; yet, many remain unknown.</p><p>Improved
analytical techniques are helping pin down those molecules. Kubanek
and colleagues have observed that when tiny predatory
crustaceans called copepods are around, single-celled organisms called dinoflagellates
boost their production of toxic compounds for defense. Using chemical
separation techniques paired with NMR spectroscopy and mass spectrometry,
the team traced the trigger for the toxicity uptick to a <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1420154112">family of lipids</ext-link> in the copepods&#x02019; waste.</p><p>Since then, one of Kubanek&#x02019;s
collaborators, Erik Selander of the University of Gothenburg, has
found that every copepod he&#x02019;s studied makes these lipids. Compounds
such as these had previously gone unrecognized because they&#x02019;re
so dilute in the water, Kubanek says. Now, &#x0201c;people are working
on studying ocean chemistry at the single molecule level, as opposed
to just bulk concentrations of types of organic compounds.&#x0201d;</p><p>Kubanek&#x02019;s team has also used metabolomics to analyze blue
crab urine, which has allowed the researchers to <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10886-016-0771-2">home in on two compounds</ext-link> that cause their mud crab prey to freeze up and stop foraging. Genetics
and bioinformatics are also helping to decipher the vast chemical
vocabulary of sea creatures, including organisms that are difficult
to cultivate. &#x0201c;We don&#x02019;t have to grow massive culture
flasks,&#x0201d; Kubanek says. &#x0201c;We can just get a small sample,
sequence these partial genomes, and start to infer their chemistry.&#x0201d;</p></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Body
and brain</title><p>In addition to identifying the chemicals that creatures
send out, scientists are looking at how those molecules are sensed
by other animals and trying to unveil the specific proteins that act
as receptors and their roles in biological processes and behavior.
Kubankek says that hundreds to thousands of mammalian receptors are known but
that &#x0201c;we&#x02019;re way behind&#x0201d; for aquatic animals.</p><p>Lab studies of fishes&#x02019; response to CO<sub>2</sub>, for example,
have reported anxiety or strange behaviors, such as being attracted
to predators&#x02019; smells. In this area, researchers aiming to replicate
these <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1461-0248.2009.01400.x">behavioral</ext-link><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0809996106">studies</ext-link> haven&#x02019;t
always reached the same <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1903-y">conclusions</ext-link>.</p><p>One theory to explain behavioral changes suggests modifications
to the nervous system. A team&#x02014;which includes members whose
other papers have been disputed&#x02014;put forth the idea that fish
respond to high CO<sub>2</sub> concentrations by shifting the concentration
of ions in the fluid that surrounds the brain. This could <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nclimate1352">change the activity of
receptors</ext-link> for the neurotransmitter GABA and
alter sensing and behavior based on chemoreception. Separately, other
researchers have found <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2013.2509">evidence for this theory</ext-link> by using chemicals that block GABA binding. Hubbard&#x02019;s
team is now working to probe this theory more directly
by measuring concentrations of ions in the cerebrospinal fluid and,
eventually, inside fishes&#x02019; neurons.</p><p>Also, the lining
of a fish&#x02019;s nose links directly to the brain via the olfactory
nerve. Z&#x000e9;lia Velez of the Center of Marine Sciences, Hubbard,
and colleagues monitored the response of the olfactory nerve in juvenile
sea bream to elevated CO<sub>2</sub>. Unlike behavioral tests, which
can be more prone to artifacts of the experimental design or even
the mood of the fish, Hubbard says, these tests capture how acidification
impacts physiology. Under elevated CO<sub>2</sub> conditions, the
scientists observed a <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.00731">decreased neural signal</ext-link> in response to amino acids, which are thought to serve as food cues.</p><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc1c00819_0001" id="GRAPHIC-d7e177-autogenerated" position="float"><caption><p>At
higher CO<sub>2</sub> levels, sea bream show decreased neural response
to amino acids, which serve as food cues for the fish. Credit: Joao
Encarna&#x000e7;ao.</p></caption></graphic><p>The team has also sought
to separate the effects of increased CO<sub>2</sub> and changes in
acidity. For instance, to create acidic conditions without using CO<sub>2</sub>, the researchers add hydrochloric acid to water that flows
by the fishes&#x02019; nostrils. Or, to lower the acidity when CO<sub>2</sub> is added, they use sodium hydroxide. Both increased CO<sub>2</sub> and decreased pH <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.238485">changed the fishes&#x02019;
olfactory sensitivity</ext-link> to certain amino acids. The researchers
were surprised to find that for some amino acids, &#x0201c;the effects
of the CO<sub>2</sub> itself are higher than [the effects of] the
pH,&#x0201d; Velez says. The mechanism behind these changes isn&#x02019;t
fully clear, but the scientists hypothesize that the increased CO<sub>2</sub> may decrease the intracellular pH of olfactory neurons by
interfering with an enzyme involved in regulating pH.</p><p>This and
other work suggest that climate change may have complicated impacts
on animals&#x02019; sensing. &#x0201c;We don&#x02019;t know how each
species is going to react to these changes,&#x0201d; Velez says. Some
fish, such as those that dwell near CO<sub>2</sub> vents, can tolerate
high concentrations of CO<sub>2</sub>. Other animals may be less resilient.
Velez and her colleagues are studying more species, including top
predators such as sharks, to further explore the potential impacts
of acidified waters.</p></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>Modified molecules</title><p>Climate change
could alter not only animals&#x02019; ability to sense molecules but
also the molecules themselves.</p><p>At a lower pH, with more hydrogen
ions around, some molecules or functional groups pick up a proton.
This addition can change a molecule&#x02019;s conformation and charge
distribution, sometimes enough that a protonated form of a molecule
may not bind to a receptor in the same way as the deprotonated version.</p><p>Knowing that marine pH could drop from 8.1 to 7.7 by the turn of
the century, Christina C. Roggatz, a marine chemical ecologist at
the University of Hull, and her colleagues decided to investigate
whether signaling molecules were sensitive to pH in this range. The
team picked a few peptides that mimic molecules that female shore
crabs use as cues to care for their eggs. The eggs release the molecules
when they need oxygen, prompting their mother to swing them from side
to side to increase ventilation. Later, the molecules trigger the
female to send the eggs into the water so that all the larvae hatch
at the same time, Roggatz says. The actual signaling molecules aren&#x02019;t
known, but the synthetic stand-ins promote the same behaviors.</p><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc1c00819_0002" id="GRAPHIC-d7e225-autogenerated" position="float"><caption><p>Shapes
of peptides (GHK and GGR) that mimic chemical cues used by crabs shift
when pH is lowered from current ocean levels (8.1) to those predicted
at the turn of the century (7.7). As the ocean turns more acidic,
such molecular changes could alter crab behavior. Credit: Christina
C. Roggatz.</p></caption></graphic><p>NMR spectroscopy revealed that
certain functional groups on the synthetic mimics become predominately
protonated when the pH drops to 7.7. The scientists also determined
each group&#x02019;s p<italic>K</italic><sub>a</sub>, the pH at which
half the population of that molecule will be protonated and half deprotonated.
Using quantum chemical calculations, the researchers <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.13354">predicted changes</ext-link> to the molecules&#x02019; structures and charge distributions. Neutral
forms of the three peptides were more compact than the protonated
forms, which were more planar and gained large positively charged
regions.</p><p>Those changes correlate with crab behavior. When the
crabs were exposed to protonated peptides, &#x0201c;the mom crabs wouldn&#x02019;t
ventilate the eggs as regularly,&#x0201d; Roggatz says. To induce the
same ventilation behavior, it took up to 10 times as much protonated
as unprotonated peptides, she adds.</p><p>Roggatz and her colleagues
are hunting for other molecules with groups sensitive to the pH expected
under acidifying conditions. Some functional groups, such as amines,
phenols, and imidazoles, are particularly prone to change.</p><p>&#x0201c;I
potentially am interested in every single molecule,&#x0201d; Roggatz
says. &#x0201c;But the problem is we actually don&#x02019;t know that
many&#x0201d; molecules with defined ecological functions. Many studies
use poorly characterized mixtures, sometimes extracts from marine
critters or even squished-up organisms, as proxies for molecules that
affect biology and behavior. The compounds could potentially be peptides,
nucleic acids, or fatty acids, making identification even more difficult.</p><p>How widespread the effects on signaling molecules may be is unclear,
Roggatz says. Some chemical cues may even <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10886-021-01276-9">become more potent</ext-link>. &#x0201c;What I have found so far is that when the molecule is sensitive,
the changes are potentially devastating.&#x0201d;</p><p>Along with
the changes to chemoreception and signaling molecules that may accompany
acidification, creatures will likely contend with effects due to rising
temperatures and hypoxia, a decrease in oxygen levels. &#x0201c;It&#x02019;s
going to be difficult to really predict what the outcome will be,&#x0201d;
particularly for different animals, Hubbard says.</p><p>The way CO<sub>2</sub> is <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cen.acs.org/articles/91/i41/Diving-Deeper-Souring-Oceans.html">changing the chemistry of the water</ext-link> &#x0201c;might have
a really, really big impact on biodiversity,&#x0201d; Velez says. Some
effects may cascade through ecosystems if top predators are impacted.
By studying effects at multiple levels of the food chain, researchers
hope to inform policy makers about changes in conservation efforts
that can protect ecosystems. Even though scientists don&#x02019;t understand
all the details of the processes they&#x02019;re studying, Velez adds,
if people don&#x02019;t act to reduce emissions, species may disappear.</p></sec><sec id="sec100"><title>Carolyn Wilke is a freelance contributor to</title><p><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cen.acs.org/"><italic>Chemical &#x00026; Engineering News</italic></ext-link>, <italic>the weekly newsmagazine of the American Chemical
Society.</italic></p></sec></body></article>