<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par21">The morphology of the samples was characterized by transmission electron microscope (TEM, FEI Tecnai G220) with an accelerating voltage of 200 kV and field-emission scanning electron microscope (FE-SEM, JEORJSM-6700F). The HAADFSTEM images were obtained by JEOL JEM-ARM200F at an accelerating voltage of 200 kV. The crystal phases present in each sample were identified using powder X-ray diffraction(XRD) patterns were recorded on a Y-2000X-ray Diffractometer with copper Kα radiation (λ = 1.5406 Å) at 40 kV, 40 mA. The X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurements were performed with an ESCA LAB 250 spectrometer on a focused monochromatic Al Kαline (1486.6 eV) X-ray beam with a diameter of 200 μm. The Raman measurements were taken on a Renishaw spectrometer at 532 nm on a Renishaw Microscope System RM2000. The N
 <sub>2</sub> adsorption/desorption curve was carried out by BET measurements using a Micromeritics ASAP 2020 surface area analyzer. The Fe and Mn K-edge X-ray absorption near edgestructure (XANES) and the extended X-ray absorption fine structure (EXAFS) were investigated at the SXRMB beamline at the Canadian Light Source. References, such as Fe and Mn foils, are used to calibrate the beamlie energy and for comparison to samples. Fluorescence detection was performed using a 7-element Si drift detector for samples and the total electron yield was used for measurement of samples with high concentration, such as references. The EXAFS raw data were then background-subtracted, normalized and Fourier transformed by the standard procedures with the IFEFFIT package. The Mössbauer measurements were performed using a conventional spectrometer (Germany, Wissel MS-500) in transmission geometry with constant acceleration mode. A 57Co(Rh) source with activity of 25 mCi was used. The 5 velocity calibration was done with a room temperature α-Fe absorber. The spectra were fitted by the software Recoil using Lorentzian Site Analysis.
</p>
