<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Twitter:</bold> @RutNdjab, @ATricco, @hwitteman
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Contributors:</bold> RN, CF, ACT, HOW contributed to the design of the study. CB, RN, LPB, RAPR and HOW contributed to the systematic search of the literature and selection of studies. RR, HOW, LC conducted data analysis and interpretation. RR and HOW drafted the first version of the article with early revision by CB, LC and RN. All authors critically revised the article and approved the final version for submission for publication. RR and HOW had full access to all the data in the study and had final responsibility for the decision to submit for publication.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Funding:</bold> This study was funded by the Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR) FDN-148426. The CIHR had no role in determining the study design, the plans for data collection or analysis, the decision to publish, nor the preparation of this manuscript. ACT is funded by a Tier 2 Canada Research Chair in Knowledge Synthesis. HOW is funded by a Tier 2 Canada Research Chair in Human-Centred Digital Health.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="COI-statement">
  <p>
   <bold>Competing interests:</bold> None declared.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Provenance and peer review:</bold> Not commissioned; externally peer reviewed.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Supplemental material:</bold> This content has been supplied by the author(s). It has not been vetted by BMJ Publishing Group Limited (BMJ) and may not have been peer-reviewed. Any opinions or recommendations discussed are solely those of the author(s) and are not endorsed by BMJ. BMJ disclaims all liability and responsibility arising from any reliance placed on the content. Where the content includes any translated material, BMJ does not warrant the accuracy and reliability of the translations (including but not limited to local regulations, clinical guidelines, terminology, drug names and drug dosages), and is not responsible for any error and/or omissions arising from translation and adaptation or otherwise.
  </p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
