<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par46">Let us turn to the other extreme of the pessimism/optimism spectrum, namely radical mitigation optimism. Here we find the authors of 
 <italic>An Ecomodernist Manifesto</italic>. Accepting a pessimistic view of climate change as an unmitigated or poorly mitigated process, ecomodernists nevertheless expect positive social transformation by means of high-tech innovation. The authors of 
 <italic>An Ecomodernist Manifesto</italic> represent a variety of academic fields, including ecology, physics, economics and philosophy. Most are Americans, but some originate in Australia and one author in India (Asafu-Adjaye et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2015</xref>). They express their optimism as follows:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par47">We offer this statement in the belief that both human prosperity and an ecologically vibrant planet are not only possible but also inseparable … [W]e embrace an optimistic view toward human capacities and the future (Asafu-Adjaye et al., 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2015</xref>).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>In stark contrast to Scranton’s pessimistic view of the Anthropocene, the authors of 
 <italic>An Ecomodernist Manifesto</italic> have a much brighter outlook:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par49">[K]nowledge and technology, applied with wisdom, might allow for a good, or even great, Anthropocene (Asafu-Adjaye et al., 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2015</xref>).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>Key to successful mitigation of climate change is technology:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par51">Meaningful climate mitigation is fundamentally a technological challenge. By this we mean that even dramatic limits to per capita consumption would be insufficient to achieve significant climate mitigation … In the long run, next-generation solar, advanced nuclear fission, and nuclear fusion represent the most plausible pathways toward the joint goals of climate stabilization and radical decoupling of humans from nature (Asafu-Adjaye et al., 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2015</xref>).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>The goal of “climate stabilization” is linked to the goal of “decoupling of humans from nature,” not to the goal of most environmentalists of harmonizing human society with nature. By decoupling we will preserve the environment and at the same time increase human prosperity. This decoupling is to be achieved by means of technological development and intensification of, for example, urbanization and agriculture (Asafu-Adjaye et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2015</xref>).
</p>
