<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par54">A completely different type of optimism we find in David Boyd’s book 
 <italic>The Optimistic Environmentalist</italic> (2015). Boyd, a Canadian environmental lawyer, presents his view as follows:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par55">My goals in writing this book are to provide an antidote to the plague of ecological negativity; to give people a sense of optimism that a greener, cleaner, and happier future is possible; and to inspire to act. A bright future isn’t a 99 to 1 longshot, but rather the odds-on favourite … [M]y conviction that a sustainable and prosperous future lies within our reach is based on a sober and balanced examination of the facts about humanity’s past environmental successes, current trends, and future probabilities (Boyd, 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">2015</xref>, xxiii).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>It should be noted that climate change and mitigation of climate change are not central to Boyd’s book and not given priority over other ecological issues such as pollution, biodiversity and living in harmony with nature. However, while recognizing “the potentially catastrophic effects of climate change” caused by fossil fuel use, he indicates a mitigation optimist stance by stressing that “the transition to clean, renewable energy is inevitable and accelerating” (Boyd, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">2015</xref>, 25–26). This said, it is still clear that Boyd argues for green optimism in general rather than mitigation optimism more specifically. He expects “a future where the human impact on the planet is reduced to sustainable levels and the ravaged ecosystems of today are restored to flourishing levels of diversity and abundance” (Boyd, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">2015</xref>, xxv). As indicated by the quotation above, his green optimism is based on three types of argument: examples of historical successes such as regulations against species extinction and the 1987 Montreal agreement to protect the ozone layer, examples of current trends such as the renewable energy revolution (solar and wind power) and the increasing popularity of organic food, and examples of likely further developments in, for instance, electric transportation and energy-efficient building (Boyd, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">2015</xref>).
</p>
