<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par57">Another optimistic approach with a more direct focus on mitigation of climate change than Boyd’s and with an emphasis also on economic justice can be seen in a recent book by the British economist Ann Pettifor (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>). In the spirit of Roosevelt’s New Deal in the US in the 1930s, she argues for a UK Green New Deal similar to the US Green New Deal suggested by Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and Ed Markey (Pettifor, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, 7–20). The following quotation clearly illustrates the difference between the more traditional green approach to climate change mitigation (such as Boyd’s) and the Green New Deal:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par58">Environmental advocates tend to focus on individual (‘change your lightbulbs’) or community (‘recycle, reuse, reduce, localise’) action. We have been slow at understanding and promoting the need for radical systemic change across sectors and at a global and national level; that is, change that involves state action … To tackle climate change we need simultaneously to tackle the root cause of growing toxic emissions: a self-regulating, globalised financial system … Once we switch off the ‘tap’ of ‘easy money’ will it be possible to switch off the flow of oil and other fossil fuels (Pettifor, 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, 8–9).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>We see here that Pettifor stresses the role of the state in mitigation of climate change and not merely, as environmentalists (including Boyd) often tend to do, the role of individuals and the community. The fundamental factor behind climate change is the global financial system that upholds the fossil fuel industry. In order to successfully mitigate climate change the state needs to take control over, regulate and reform this financial and monetary system. This is how Pettifor expresses optimism concerning this basic mitigation measure:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par60">There is hope; and it rests not on a utopian vision of humanity, but on our knowledge of human genius, empathy, ingenuity, collaboration, integrity and courage. We know that it is possible to reform the globalised financial system because we have done it before–and in the relatively recent past … To transform the current economic and financial system we must ignore defeatists on both the left and right of the political spectrum… (Pettifor, 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, xvi–xvii).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>It is not too late to mitigate climate change on the basis of such a reformation of the financial system. It can be done, because a similar reformation was done “in the relatively recent past,” namely by Roosevelt’s dismantling of the gold standard in the 1930s as part of the New Deal (Pettifor, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, 48–50). The economic goal of the Green New Deal is a ‘steady state’ economy (circular economy) in which mitigation measures are integrated with measures for economic justice (Pettifor, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, 66–67). This economic system is mixed in the sense that the state undertakes certain collective activities and the market facilitates exchange of goods and services within the steady state framework (Pettifor, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, 99). The Green New Deal is described as a “democratic eco-socialist” project (Pettifor, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2019</xref>, 59).
</p>
