<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The initial consequences of climate change for Australian flora and fauna have been well documented in recent years and include range shifts, population declines, altered migration rates, and altered selection pressure [
 <xref rid="B34-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>,
 <xref rid="B35-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,
 <xref rid="B36-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>,
 <xref rid="B37-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="B38-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. Changes to the physical environment have resulted in catastrophic cascading ecosystem effects and negative feedback loops [
 <xref rid="B39-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. The impacts of climate change are evident across a range of habitats and environments, from the oceans [
 <xref rid="B41-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>] to the tropics [
 <xref rid="B42-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>] and even into the arid and alpine zones [
 <xref rid="B43-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. Montane species are being forced into higher altitudes as temperatures increase and will inevitably be forced “off the mountain top” [
 <xref rid="B44-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. Species with specific habitat and climatic tolerance ranges are predicted to be vulnerable to rising temperatures [
 <xref rid="B45-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]; mechanistic models of future climate conditions predict a reduction in reproductive output of green sea turtles (
 <italic>Chelonia mydas</italic>) associated with marine heatwaves [
 <xref rid="B46-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]. Conradie et al. [
 <xref rid="B47-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>] predict that by 2100, zebra finches (
 <italic>Taeniopygia guttata</italic>) will be exposed to acute lethal dehydration risk for several weeks of the year in over 50% of the species’ current range. Climatic extremes have already resulted in massive diebacks of mangroves [
 <xref rid="B48-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>] and seagrass [
 <xref rid="B49-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. Furthermore, less resilient species with specific habitat requirements are becoming increasingly vulnerable due to shifts in their climatic niche. For example, only 30% of the current distribution of 
 <italic>Banksia marginata</italic>, a highly fragmented but ecologically significant plant species, overlaps with the projected distribution under climate change by 2080 [
 <xref rid="B50-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>].
</p>
