<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par27">Using our framework, we demonstrate that biotic factors such as trophic interactions and temperature-dependent competition are important in shaping species’ eco-evolutionary response to climate change—in fact, they can be as influential as the ability of species to adapt to new local climates or to disperse to new habitats. With trophic interactions and temperature-dependent competition, species have broader ranges and coexist to a higher degree, in comparison to the baseline model without the aforementioned dynamics. In addition, temperature-dependent competition significantly reduces global species loss. With constant competition as in our baseline scenario, competitive exclusions occur to a higher extent, a result in line with van Eldijk et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>, showing that evolutionary rescue of one species leads to a competitive exclusion and extinction of another species. The importance of biotic interactions for shaping species’ response to climate change is well-known
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. Our work complements these studies by further demonstrating the significance of biotic interactions in an eco-evolutionary setting as well. The mechanisms behind this are predator-mediated coexistence
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> (in the case of trophic interactions), and reduced interspecific competition with increasing trait distance
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. Note that this last mechanism is not guaranteed to promote diversity, since the level of difference in mean temperature optima required for significant reductions in competition might mean that species have local growth rates that are too suboptimal for persistence. Thus, the ability of this mechanism to boost diversity depends on whether species are able to tolerate suboptimal climates sufficiently to avoid local competition.
</p>
