<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par18">Sandy beach ecosystems are especially vulnerable and appear on the verge or have already exceeded a tipping point, especially for armored beaches (e.g. refs. 67,68), where 99% of the existing upper beach zone habitat is projected to be lost with just 0.5 m of SLR (range of all beach types = 51–99%, mean = 74%). The majority of beaches are projected to decline in overall width with increasing SLR. Importantly, the loss of beach width will not be evenly distributed across intertidal zones. Upper beach zones are projected to experience the greatest declines in width and losses with SLR. Although often narrow in width, these upper intertidal zones are vital components of biodiversity and ecosystem function
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">69</xref>
 </sup>. The sandy upper intertidal zone is associated with the distributions of key beach organisms, biodiversity and ecosystem functions, including the accumulation of macrophyte wrack and the wrack-associated invertebrate community
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">69</xref>
 </sup>. This often narrow zone supports ~ 45% of total intertidal invertebrate biodiversity, provides prey resources for birds and fish, and plays a vital role in detrital processing and nutrient cycling
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR68">68</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR73">73</xref>
 </sup>. These key upper beach zones are already scarce and/or ephemeral for many beaches in the study region with consequent loss of biodiversity and ecosystem function (e.g. refs. 
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR74">74</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR75">75</xref>
 </sup>). When seawater regularly reaches the bluff toe, armoring structure or beach limit, drift macrophyte wrack and the rich intertidal biodiversity, ecosystem functions and prey resources that macrophyte supports, as well as critical habitat for fish and wildlife are eliminated from the beach ecosystem. The upper intertidal transition, the zone where native coastal strand vegetation develops that can enhance resilience by trapping and storing sand and building dune topography
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR76">76</xref>
 </sup>, also is eliminated.
</p>
