<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par21">However, tidal marshes have more recently been in decline across the coast of California due to urbanization and land management practices, with a 48% loss of habitat across southern California since 1850, including a 62% decline in Santa Barbara County
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR80">80</xref>
 </sup>. Accelerating sea levels world-wide and limits to landward mobility will further increase tidal inundation of marshes leading to changes in key physical and biological properties known to structure marsh plant communities and habitats
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR81">81</xref>
 </sup>. As demonstrated in this study, major changes are forthcoming or already underway in Carpinteria salt marsh, and this regionally scarce ecosystem may pass a tipping point with less than 0.25 m of SLR with the significant loss of high salt-marsh and transition habitats and the functions these habitats provide. Similar losses of existing vegetated marsh by the end of the century have been projected for other tidal marshes region-wide
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR82">82</xref>
 </sup> and are consistent with global studies linking early warning signals to marsh collapse
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">83</xref>
 </sup>. The precise timing of habitat evolution will depend on the rate of SLR and the accretion rate of the marsh surface, but ultimately, with limited landward accommodation space, this vegetated marsh will be converted to mudflat. While specific tipping point dates are tidal marsh-specific and depend on local hydrology, sediment supply, and topography, urbanized tidal marshes are the norm along the California coast and other populated settings. This study, therefore, may serve as a proxy for the response of similar tidal marsh systems world-wide. Mitigating and adapting to the anticipated vulnerability of this ecosystem to climate-related impacts are a key planning and management priority for local, state, and federal agencies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR84">84</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR86">86</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
