<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <bold>Instruments</bold>: We used a questionnaire which aimed to examine [
 <xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>] the expected consequences of global climate change for FYMS [
 <xref rid="cit0002" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>], their perceived individual responsibility and their attitudes towards an [
 <xref rid="cit0003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>] additional professional responsibility as future doctors (with a mission to also educate patients about climate change and its health implications). As we were unable to find an extant instrument addressing this or comparable subject matters, we developed the questionnaire for our specific sample ourselves (thus creating a tailored evaluation tool): In accordance with Artino et al. [
 <xref rid="cit0034" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>], the first step was to conduct a nonsystematic literature search in PubMed. Although there was a large body of research on the topic (i.e., broadly defined attitudes toward climate change in the context of medical education), there was no study that examined this specific aspect in medical students and no study could be found in which a questionnaire was developed on the topic. Thus, the literature search supported the need to develop a new instrument. To develop such a questionnaire and to better define the construct of attitudes toward climate change in medical students, we formed an expert group of physicians and psychologists and surveyed final-year medical students on the topic. In a next step, we developed the items and then obtained feedback on the items through expert validation (i.e., by the formed expert group). Within the expert group, we used cognitive interviewing to ensure that respondents understood the items as they were intended. Otherwise, rephrasing was necessary. Last, we conducted pilot tests with the participating FYMS. The resulting questionnaire consisted of 12 items and three dimensions , with four items exploring FYMS´ knowledge of the expected consequences, three items assessing their feelings of individual responsibility, and five items on their sense of professional responsibility. For all items, a graphic rating scale was used (0–100). The anchor points in the scale were labeled 
 <italic>not applicable at all</italic> (0) versus 
 <italic>absolutely applicable</italic> (100). The 12 questions are shown in (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f0001">Figure 1</xref>) as well as in (
 <xref rid="t0002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). 
</p>
