<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par26">Therefore, the exploration of inexpensive, highly efficient, and durable electrocatalysts is necessary to promote the practical application of these renewable resources [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. At present, precious metals are considered to be the most active electrocatalysts such as Pt, Ru, Ir, and their alloys, but high cost, scarcity, and lack of bifunctional catalysis have seriously hindered their commercialization [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Therefore, the pursuit of bifunctional, stable and inexpensive electrocatalysts is urgently needed for the demand of commercialization. Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) are promising alternative candidates of which Co
 <sup>2+</sup> in Co
 <sub>x</sub>P
 <sub>y</sub> provides OH
 <sup>−</sup> adsorption center and converts it into products, while negative P center accelerates OH
 <sup>−</sup> adsorption to Co
 <sup>2+</sup>, resulting in low cost, excellent performance, high efficiency, and good durability [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. Many researchers have made great efforts to design CoP
 <sub>x</sub> nanostructures with diverse and high electrocatalytic activity. Since the activity depends largely on their surface properties, many research focused on the structure engineering of electrocatalysts to expose catalytic active sites as much as possible, for example various nanostructured TMPs, including nanoparticles [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], nanowires [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>], nanotubes [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>], and nanorods [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>] are developed and most of them showed good electrocatalytic performance. There have been many reports that high-efficiency and strong cobalt-based materials were considered as a promising OER electrocatalyst due to its high efficiency, high abundance, and good stability in recent years. Cobalt phosphide (CoP) is one of the TMPs families. Due to the novel characteristics of CoP, its application in battery electrocatalysis and photocatalysis has received extensive attention. It provides a large number of active sites for electrochemical reaction to promote electrocatalytic activity [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]. CoP not only solves the problems of insufficient reserves, high price, and poor stability of Ru and Ir electrocatalysts, but also has good catalytic performance for OER [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. In addition, CoP has neutral alkali resistance and is advantageous for electrochemical stability. However, the conductivity of CoP is poor, which seriously affects its electrocatalytic activity [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>].
</p>
