<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this endeavor, Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Si@Cu as an anode material for LIBs was prepared via RF magnetron sputtering. This work involves the deposition of Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub> on Si film as a possible solution to the cracking of the Si anode that results in poor electrochemical performance, which ultimately hinders the practical application of Si-based anodes in LIBs. Additionally, Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Cu and Si@Cu films were prepared for comparison. The pristine anode material was characterized using a series of analytical techniques: spectroscopy (Raman, XPS, EDX), microscopy (SEM and TEM), XRD analysis, and topography. Characterization results, mainly that of XRD and XPS, confirmed the successful deposition of Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub> on Si@Cu film through RF magnetron sputtering. Various electrochemical tests were conducted to evaluate its performance in a half-cell (vs. Li
 <sup>+</sup>/Li) and full cell, including CV and GCD. Upon cycling, the Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Si@Cu anode was found to perform better, with higher specific charge/discharge capacities, at lower current densities (100 and 200 mA/g). The most significant finding in this work was the superior performance of Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Si@Cu as LIB anode material compared to Si@Cu. The Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Si@Cu anode achieved 90% capacity retention after 50 cycles, whilst only 20% of the capacity was retained for Si@Cu. Furthermore, excellent efficiency (100% up to 20 cycles) and reasonably high specific capacities were attained for Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Si@Cu in a full cell with LFP, which already outperforms many commercial batteries today. Nevertheless, more work needs to be done in enhancing the specific capacity as the experimental value achieved in this work is still relatively low compared to the theoretical capacity. Post-mortem analysis was conducted to identify and assess any changes that occurred to the Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>@Si@Cu anode after cycling and during the lithiated/delithiated stages. The formation of Li
 <sub>3</sub>N was confirmed by XRD and XPS analysis in the lithiated and delithiated phases of the anode, which can be indicative of the role of Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub> as a protective barrier for Si.
</p>
