<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par17">We find that the factors that influence the suitability of coffee, in general, vary with those that give geographical typicality. We find that there is an almost equal contribution of temperature and precipitation factors in determining the suitability of coffee in Ethiopia, confirming findings from other studies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup>. Conversely, in a global study, temperature factors were identified mainly as determinants of Arabica coffee suitability
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup> while in a national study elsewhere identified mostly precipitation-based factors in determining suitability
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. Such variations are explained by differences in scale and geography respectively, indicating that the potential for coffee can be influenced by local and regional factors. This explains our finding that specialty coffee types are influenced by different factors giving them different chemical properties and profiles. For example, Tolessa, et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>
 </sup> finds that coffee specialty cup quality attributes (overall cup preference, acidity, body, flavour and aftertaste) were influenced more by altitude. It is important to note that the altitude is not a direct production parameter for coffee but strongly influences climatic and soil characteristics that in turn influence the coffee quality. The reasons for higher quality at higher altitude is the slow coffee bean development associated with cooler high-altitude temperatures, which allow for slow bean filling and can result in more flavour profiles and body
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. In addition, coffee cultivars are different for each specialty coffee zone
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>
 </sup> and yet coffee varieties respond differentially to climate change impacts
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
