<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Research in energy storage and energy conversion systems is important to develop technologies that can contribute to resource sustainability and long-term development of human society by studying new electrode materials with high energy and power densities. Group IA alkali–metal sulfur (Li–S and Na–S) batteries have been investigated extensively due to their high energy density and energy storage properties
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>. Na–S batteries have charge/discharge mechanisms similar to Li–S batteries that involve a two-electron redox per sulfur atom, which is why its theoretical sulfur capacity will also be 1672 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. Similar to Li–S, Na–S batteries offer high energy density, power density and energy efficiency, and are nontoxic with good cycle life. An advantage of Na–S batteries over Li–S batteries is the low cost and high abundance of the raw materials that make them suitable for large-scale production
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>. In the last decade, two operating temperature ranges of Na–S batteries have been studied: high-temperature 270–350 °C and room temperature. At high operating temperatures, the molten sodium metal and sodium polysulfides (NaPSs) are known to be corrosive and can cause vigorous reactions between the molten sodium and molten sulfur through a broken separator film
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>. Safety concerns are very important for energy storage technologies, as exemplified by the recent fire incident at NGK Insulator Ltd. related to a Na–S battery
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. In contrast, at ambient temperatures, Na–S batteries are safer, more durable and offer lower operating costs and thus have been studied by many research groups
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. Nevertheless, Na–S batteries face problems, including: (1) the dissolution of NaPSs in the electrolyte causing high capacity fade; (2) formation of sodium metal dendrites during charging that inevitably lead to short-circuits; and (3) the low utilization rate of the sulfur cathode, that constrains the electrochemical reactions to a certain distance from the current collector and limits the cell capacity.
</p>
