<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">In recent years, polar materials, including MnO
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>, TiO
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>, alpha-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>, and SiO
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup> have been shown to strongly interact with polysulfides and effectively bind them to the cathode to attain reversible electrochemical cycling. Nevertheless, most of the metal oxides and hydroxides are semiconductors with poor electronic conductivities, resulting in low rate capabilities. Suitable sulfur hosts should have both strong polysulfide attraction and good electronic conductivity
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. Moreover, since the interaction between solid polar (non-hollow) materials and NaPSs is created only on the surface as single-layer chemical adsorption, such solid structures can only capture a small amount of NaPSs; NaPSs away from the surface can still dissolve in the electrolyte and shuttle between the electrodes (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. A promising approach is to construct a polar hollow architecture, which can physically block the path of outward diffusion, thus encapsulating the polysulfides in the wide inner space of the cathode (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>). As a result, hollow polar S hosts can more efficiently block NaPSs diffusion than other structures, such as nanoparticles and flakes. In addition to the above strategies, the use of host materials that effectively catalyse the conversion of long-chain NaPSs (Na
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>, 4 ≤ 
 <italic>x</italic> ≤ 8) to short chain NaPS is a particularly promising approach to inhibit NaPSs diffusion
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup>. Due to the insulating properties of sulfur and NaPSs, the electrochemical discharge/charge process is sluggish. For non-catalytic hosts such as carbon, carbon nanotubes, carbon nano fibers, carbon hollow nanospheres, and double-shell carbon microspheres, the conversion of NaPSs is slow and the intermediate polysulfides can easily dissolve into the electrolyte. However, due to the use of the catalytic S host, such as electronically conducting transition metal sulphide hosts can effectively act as electrocatalysts to accelerate the redox kinetic of long chain NaPSs (Na
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>, 4 ≤ 
 <italic>x</italic> ≤ 8) and efficiently convert to solid phase S and Na
 <sub>2</sub>S/Na
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>). Consequently, the use of catalytic materials as sulfur carriers in the construction of advanced Na–S batteries could be a promising approach.
</p>
