<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Following by Thotiyl et al., a detailed study on the deterioration of TiC and other Ti binary compound electrodes was conducted by Kozmenkova et al. They characterized the surface phenomenon of model chemical and electrochemical systems using in-situ and ex-situ experiments [
 <xref rid="B70-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">70</xref>], in the process demonstrating the formation of a passivation layer during the ORR. A two-electrode cell system was fabricated by having TiC, lithium foil, porous Celgard separator immersed with 1 M lithium bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonylimide (LiTFSI) in a 1-ethyl-3-methy limidazoliumbis-(trifluoromethylsulfonyl)imide as cathode, anode, and electrolyte, respectively. The assembly was kept between two stainless steel (SS) plates, and the SS plate on the cathode side had a small hole to allow the in-situ analysis to be conducted. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f003">Figure 3</xref>a presents a schematic of the in-situ spectroscopic analysis of the solid-state lithium-conducting electrolyte built in an electrochemical cell. The interaction between the TiC and the ORR products and intermediates was analyzed in-situ to avoid the formation of by-products when in contact with liquid electrolytes. In the XPS chamber, the intensities of Li 1s and O 1s were observed to increase during galvanostatic discharge, indicating the advance of discharge products over surface layer of the cathode (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f003">Figure 3</xref>b–i) [
 <xref rid="B70-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">70</xref>]. The surface of the TiC was stabilized by a protective coating layer of TiO
 <sub>2</sub>. Because TiO
 <sub>2</sub> has a wide bandgap (3 eV), it places kinetic limitations on the electrons during the ORR. To overcome this limitation, the thickness of the cathode has to be optimized to offer both an acceptable electron transport rate and genuine surface protection. 
</p>
