<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Avalanches are major natural hazards in snow-covered mountain areas, threatening people and infrastructure. Avalanche accidents in the 20th century were characterized by natural disasters and by an increasing number of recreational fatalities following the emergence and growth of winter tourism (
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). Weather events with several days of intense precipitation, both snow and rain, produced numerous catastrophic avalanches in many mountain ranges, affecting inhabited areas and transportation corridors (
 <xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr">Brugger et al., 2021</xref>). With major investments in mitigation measures, such as defense structures in starting zones and snow sheds to protect infrastructure, especially highways and railways, fatalities in settlements and on roads have decreased in highly populated areas, such as the European Alps (
 <xref rid="ref61" ref-type="bibr">Schweizer et al., 2021</xref>). Avalanche accidents affecting populated areas and transport routes are still common in some Asian and South American countries (
 <xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr">Brugger et al., 2021</xref>). In Europe and North America, avalanche accidents now primarily involve winter recreationists. The increasing popularity of outdoor winter activities has led to increased numbers of accidents (
 <xref rid="ref24" ref-type="bibr">Haegeli et al., 2011</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref55" ref-type="bibr">Procter et al., 2014</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref74" ref-type="bibr">Techel et al., 2016</xref>), most commonly caused by dry-snow slab avalanches (
 <xref rid="ref63" ref-type="bibr">Schweizer and Lütschg, 2001</xref>). At least 90% of avalanches that involve injury or death are triggered by recreationists. When victims are completely buried, fewer than half of them survive (
 <xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">Brugger et al., 2001</xref>). If not found and extricated within about 35 min, victims die mostly of asphyxia (about 70%), because of obstruction of the upper airway or from the face being surrounded by impermeable snow (
 <xref rid="ref70" ref-type="bibr">Strapazzon and Brugger, 2018</xref>). Subjects are more likely to die in high-density avalanche debris (
 <xref rid="ref24" ref-type="bibr">Haegeli et al., 2011</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref73" ref-type="bibr">Strapazzon et al., 2017</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ref71" ref-type="bibr">2021</xref>).
</p>
