<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Genomics can provide critical new data to inform conservation management of threatened species under climate change in two key ways. Neutral variants—changes to the DNA sequence that have no effect on the viability of the individual—can be analysed to understand population processes such as gene flow, changes in population size, and population structure. Meanwhile, functional variants—DNA sequence changes that have fitness consequences—can be analysed to identify genetic diversity and patterns of local adaptation across potential source populations. Such knowledge may contribute to facilitating assisted range shifts, identifying suitable source populations for translocations and restoration carrying genotypes adapted to conditions at the recipient site [
 <xref rid="B15-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], and enhancing local adaptation to climate change stress. An important application of conservation genomics is to inform species translocations, the facilitated movement of a species to an area within its historical range or to a new location with a suitable current or projected climate and habitat [
 <xref rid="B78-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">78</xref>]. Traditionally, conservation managers conduct translocations to establish insurance populations, increase population size, and encourage heterogeneity [
 <xref rid="B79-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">79</xref>,
 <xref rid="B80-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">80</xref>]. However, Sgro et al. [
 <xref rid="B81-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">81</xref>] argue that translocation should be considered not only as a method of increasing population sizes in threatened species but also as a means of creating “evolutionary resilience” to climate change. Assisted migration and genetic rescue are types of species translocation that may have the potential to offset the effects of climate change [
 <xref rid="B82-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">82</xref>,
 <xref rid="B83-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">83</xref>]. Furthermore, evolutionary rescue via processes such as targeted gene flow, another type of translocation, and gene editing, the process of altering DNA coding sequences to remove deleterious/insert advantageous alleles, may provide conservation solutions in the face of anthropogenic environmental shifts by quickly and efficiently improving the resilience of a population to external stressors [
 <xref rid="B84-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">84</xref>,
 <xref rid="B85-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">85</xref>,
 <xref rid="B86-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>]. These techniques are summarised in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="life-11-00653-f001">Figure 1</xref>. It is important to note that many of these technologies and approaches are still in the early stages of development, and while their potential uses are promising, limitations remain that are discussed further in subsequent sections of this review.
</p>
