<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>MAB is likely to mutate into genomic-assisted parental selection (GAPS) [
 <xref rid="B114-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">114</xref>] and Backcrossing (GABC) [
 <xref rid="B115-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">115</xref>] as the preferred strategies for the introgression breeding (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="genes-12-00783-f001">Figure 1</xref>i) of abiotic stress tolerant genetic alleles from crop wild relatives that have not undergone the domestication syndrome. Even though these scopes tend to underrate GWAS, fine-mapping is still needed for future usage of more target gene editing strategies (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="genes-12-00783-f001">Figure 1</xref>j) such as CRISPR-Cas9 [
 <xref rid="B75-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">75</xref>], for which a precise location of (few) major target genes is mandatory. This technique allows editing or disrupting target genes and regulator elements with a proven effect on the phenotypes. It originates from a natural system that provides bacteria with adaptive immunity to virus [
 <xref rid="B75-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">75</xref>] that is co-opted to shuffle genetic variants already present in nature. Because of this, CRISPR-Cas9 does not strictly lead to genetically modified organisms (GMOs) 
 <italic>s.s</italic>. As a proof of concept, the feasibility of this technology for drought tolerance has been validated in model plant species such as 
 <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> [
 <xref rid="B116-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">116</xref>], and crops with consolidated tissue culture protocols like tomato [
 <xref rid="B117-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">117</xref>,
 <xref rid="B118-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>]. It has even demonstrated its potential for multi-trait quantitative editing [
 <xref rid="B119-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">119</xref>] in orphan crops like groundcherry (
 <italic>Physalis pruinosa)</italic> [
 <xref rid="B120-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>]. However, its applicability in species with recalcitrant tissue culture is still limited, and most plants with enhanced tolerance phenotypes have displayed a trade-off with reduced crop yield [
 <xref rid="B12-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. A promising approach to uncouple abiotic stress tolerance from plant growth is to edit tissue-specific pathways for target drought traits [
 <xref rid="B121-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>] that could be improved to obtain heat and drought tolerant varieties more efficiently [
 <xref rid="B122-genes-12-00783" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>].
</p>
