<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This integrative review was guided by Whittemore and Knafl’s [
 <xref rid="B16-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>] framework which includes (1) problem identification; (2) literature search; (3) data evaluation; (4) data analysis; and (5) presentation. Problem identification was to address the question: What are the factors that contribute to climate change-related mortality? The literature search strategy included three databases—PubMed, Web of Science, and Scopus—with a filter by date, country, and keywords. The search terms were “Climate change”, “Mortality”, “United States”, and “Human” (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="ijerph-18-08220-f001">Figure 1</xref>). We also excluded any results containing the keywords “Plants”, “Trees”, “Europe”, “Economics”, and “Policy”. We further limited our search to literature from the United States, published between 2010 and 2020 in English. The original search yielded 69 articles from PubMed, 130 articles from Scopus, and 108 articles from Web of Science. Next, the titles and abstracts of the resulting articles were read and any articles that did not match purposes of identifying the factors that influence climate change-related mortality in the United States in the past decade were removed. Most articles excluded at this stage were related to animals, air pollution, economics, and other countries. Articles that linked climate change and mortality with air quality or air pollution were included; those that only addressed only air quality or air pollution were removed. After this screening, 66 articles from PubMed, 74 articles from Scopus and, 60 articles from Web of Science remained. These articles were then uploaded into a Zotero (a free and open-access reference management software program, version 1, Corporation for Digital Scholarship, Vienna, VA, USA), library to determine duplicate articles from the search. After all duplicates were removed, 135 articles remained. Data analysis included four researchers reading all the 135 abstracts and deciding to include or exclude each paper. Articles were removed if they did not meet any of the original search criteria or if they did not address climate change-related mortality. Any questions about the literature were discussed among the researchers. As with integrative reviews, theoretical or review articles were included since they contained important background information about climate mortality and often made connections between quantitative research and climate change mortality. Thirty-seven articles were excluded after this phase, leaving 98 articles that were included in the review to identify factors that influence climate change mortality in the United States. The final step of this review, the presentation phase is presented in the results section, 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="ijerph-18-08220-f001">Figure 1</xref> and 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="ijerph-18-08220-f002">Figure 2</xref>, and 
 <xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-ijerph-18-08220">Appendix A</xref> at the end of this article.
</p>
