<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recent advances in battery technologies have permitted the development of rechargeable lithium ion batteries with high energy density, high power density, durability, long term cycle life, and low loss in capacity with cycling. The intent of this article is to provide inspiration to undertake research to advance “beyond lithium battery concepts”, specifically towards borohydride solid-state electrolytes. However, today lithium ion batteries are dominating the market. Lithium ion batteries boast specific power densities of ~500 W/kg and specific energy densities of up to 200 kWh/kg (values reported using 50% efficiency estimates) [
 <xref rid="B1-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. These lithium ion batteries use an organic liquid electrolyte to ensure high ionic conduction. Safety remains a concern for these materials because of the organic materials in the electrolyte layer [
 <xref rid="B2-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-03239-f001">Figure 1</xref>a schematically shows currently used batteries with an organic liquid electrolyte layer to transport the Li
 <sup>+</sup> ions. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-03239-f001">Figure 1</xref>b schematically shows the essential components of an all solid-state battery—containing a solid electrolyte layer between the electrodes. For the all solid-state lithium ion battery, it is important for Li
 <sup>+</sup> to diffuse rapidly across the electrolyte layer. Solid-state electrolytes, which have high ionic conduction, will reduce the need for organic liquid electrolytes and will, in turn, have a large impact on further growth of lithium ion battery technologies [
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Materials development in the electrolyte layer will revolutionize applications available for lithium ion battery use.
</p>
