<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>First identified in 2009 from an ear infection in Japan [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>], 
 <italic>C</italic>. 
 <italic>auris</italic> has since spread globally, with reports from every continent [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Little is known about the origins of 
 <italic>C</italic>. 
 <italic>auris</italic>; however, its phylogentic relatives have been isolated from the environment [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref011" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], and it is hypothesized to have a nonhuman environmental reservoir with possible dispersal by birds [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. This yeast is considered the first “novel” pathogen to have evolved in response to climate change [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>], although this remains speculative and awaits conclusive evidence; alternative hypotheses for its emergence include expanded farming and aquaculture resulting in increased contact with humans, and environmental contamination with fungicides [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref011" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. 
 <italic>C</italic>. 
 <italic>auris</italic> is particularly problematic in healthcare settings where it colonises and spreads to cause nosocomial outbreaks, and it is remarably resistant to antifungals and disinfectants [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Fortunately, 
 <italic>C</italic>. 
 <italic>auris</italic> is relatively low in virulence and has only caused infection in people suffering from severe comorbidities [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Four major genomic clades have been identified for 
 <italic>C</italic>. 
 <italic>auris</italic> and these are associated with particular geographic regions: clade I (South Asian), clade II (East Asian), clade III (South African), and clade IV (South American) [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Clade II appears to infect the ear only, whereas the other clades have caused invasive infections [
 <xref rid="ppat.1009503.ref014" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>].
</p>
