<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Analyses of daily death rates have shown that both low and high temperatures are associated with increases in cardiovascular disease mortality
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup>. Although this general overall pattern is consistently observed around the world, the regional climate and the cultural and technical adaptation to cold and heat influence the temperature at which the fewest deaths occur. Non-optimal temperature was newly included into the Global Burden of Disease estimation and accounted for 1.96 million deaths globally, with (so far) a larger burden coming from low than from high temperatures
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. Under the current situation of climate change, the relative importance of extreme weather is changing. Indeed, we were able to observe changes in the heat-related risk of myocardial infarction even in Augsburg, Germany
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>. On the basis of data from the KORA Myocardial Infarction Registry, we assessed the effect of cold and heat on the onset of myocardial infarction in two time periods: 1987–2000 and 2001–2014. During the first period, myocardial infarctions were triggered by cold exposure only. However, during the second period, we observed significant effects of temperatures &gt;18 °C on the risk of myocardial infarction. The increased risk was attributable to the greater vulnerability to cardiovascular disease of individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus or hypertension. This observation indicates that the health effects of altered temperature exposure are already detectable now and confer an additional burden on vulnerable subgroups of the general population. In the future, we predict that the effects of heat exposure on health will outweigh the reduced effects of cold exposure on health and will produce a substantial burden of non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarctions under the uncontrolled climate change scenarios that are currently the most likely
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
