<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<app-group>
 <app id="app1-nanomaterials-11-00672">
  <title>Supplementary Materials</title>
  <p>The following are available online at 
   <uri xlink:href="https://www.mdpi.com/2079-4991/11/3/672/s1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://www.mdpi.com/2079-4991/11/3/672/s1</uri>, Figure S1: TEM images of silver nanowires at different magnifications. Figure S2: UV-Vis absorption spectrum of silver nanowires in water. Figure S3: Energy-dispersive X-ray spectrometry (EDS) mapping of silver nanowire membrane treated by CV with 15 cycles at 20 °C. SEM of the CV-treated silver nanowire membrane (a). The element distribution of Ag (green) and Cl (red) in this area (b,c). EDS spectrum of silver nanowire membrane treated by CV with 15 cycles at 20 °C (d). Figure S4: The current–potential curve (a), potential–time curve (b), current–time curve (c), and charge–time curve (d) of the silver nanowire membrane during electrochemical treatment. Figure S5: SEM images of silver nanowire membranes treated electrochemically at different temperatures: 16 °C (a), 18 °C (b), 20 °C (c), 22 °C (d), 24 °C (e), and 26 °C (f). Figure S6: SERS spectra of raw substrate (red) and substrate washed by sodium borohydride (blue). The black line is background. Table S1: The AEF of substrates prepared at different temperatures with the probe molecule of PATP. Figure S7: SERS intensities of PATP on the treated substrate at 1077 cm
   <sup>−1</sup> form sampling in five locations. Figure S8: SERS intensity mapping of PATP on the treated substrate at 1077 cm
   <sup>−1</sup> (right) and optical microscope image of the sampling area (left). Figure S9: The calibration curve of the detection of crystal violet (a), tetramethylthiuram disulfide (b), perchlorate (c), malachite green (d), fluoranthene (e), and nitrate (f). Figure S10: The conventional Raman spectrum of crystal violet and PATP. Figure S11: The conventional Raman spectra of malachite green (a), fluoranthene (b), and potassium nitrate (c). Figure S12: SERS spectra of treated (cycle number: 15; temperature: 20 °C) and untreated substrate when detecting crystal violet (a), thiram (b), sodium perchlorate (c), malachite green (d), fluoranthene (e), and potassium nitrate (f). Table S1: The AEF of substrates prepared in 15 cycles at different temperatures with the probe molecule of PATP. Table S2: The AEF of substrates prepared in different CV cycles at 20 °C with the probe molecule of PATP. Table S3: The AEF of substrates prepared in 15 cycles at 20 °C on detecting different analytes. Table S4: A comparison of performance of the developed SERS substrate with other sensors reported in the literature for the detection of crystal violet. Table S5: Determination of crystal violet in various spiked pond water samples using the developed SERS substrate.
  </p>
 </app>
</app-group>
