<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In general, 2D layered TMNs are highly electronically conductive compared to their 2D layered TMC counterparts and suitable for the majority of electronic storage devices. However, its practical applications are largely hindered by their complicated preparation process. According to earlier report by Shein et al., the threshold energy required for the conversion of M
 <sub>n+1</sub>N
 <sub>n</sub> is comparatively higher than that of Mn+1Cn from their corresponding MAX (M
 <sub>n+1</sub>AlN
 <sub>n</sub> and M
 <sub>n+1</sub>AlC
 <sub>n</sub>) phase [
 <xref rid="B140-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">140</xref>]. It is important to notice that acidic solutions are not opt to remove the ‘A’ phase (Al, Sn) from MAX for 2D layered TMNs due to its less cohesive energy, which leads to make them unstable when it dissolved in HF solution and failed completely. Hence, the synthesis of 2D layered nitride based MXenes (2D TMNs) are highly complex and cost-effective [
 <xref rid="B141-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">141</xref>,
 <xref rid="B142-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">142</xref>]. Owing to these factors, only a few 2D layered TMNs have been reported. Urbankowski et al. have successfully derived the Ti
 <sub>4</sub>N
 <sub>3</sub> MXene from Ti
 <sub>4</sub>AlN
 <sub>3</sub> using molten fluoride salt as etchant at 550 °C [
 <xref rid="B143-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">143</xref>]. Ti
 <sub>2</sub>N based MXenes have been successfully exfoliated by Bhuvaneswari et al. using KF and HCl as the selective etchants [
 <xref rid="B144-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">144</xref>]. Additionally, an ammonization of TMCs to convert into TMNs have also reported recently [
 <xref rid="B145-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">145</xref>]. Furthermore, a scalable-salt templating processed 2D molybdenum, tungsten, and vanadium nitride films have prepared and studied experimentally and computationally by Xiao et al. [
 <xref rid="B146-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">146</xref>]. 
</p>
