<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Besides complex synthesis process, these TMNs possess outstanding mechanical and electrical properties and better chemical and thermal stabilities, and finds application in diverge fields such as storage and conversion devices, sensors, electronics, fuel cells, and catalysis [
 <xref rid="B141-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">141</xref>]. However, the reports on 2D layered TMNs as cathode catalysts for LOB are very limited. For instance, as discussed earlier (
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3dot3dot2-nanomaterials-10-02106">Section 3.3.2</xref>), Sun et al. have fabricated N-doped carbon incorporated vanadium nitride (VN) cathode catalysts with significantly enriched catalytic activity for OER-ORR processes for LOBs. Because of their high nitrogen content and appreciable electric conductivity, the prepared catalyst assembled LOB cells have delivered the outstanding capacity of 8269 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> with a GCD voltage gap of 0.88 V [
 <xref rid="B102-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">102</xref>]. On the other hand, the 2D carbonitride based FeCo-N-C catalyst have been considered as a potential cathode material for LOBs because of its highly active sites. Interestingly, this microporous Fe, Co doped catalyst has offered durable cycling stability up to 75 cycles with the maximum discharge capacity as high as 17,200 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> at a low current rate [
 <xref rid="B147-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">147</xref>]. Shukla et al. recently further evaluated sulfide functionalized vanadium and titanium based cathode catalysts include V
 <sub>2</sub>NS
 <sub>2</sub> and TiN
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> for energy storage devices through the first principle DFT methodology [
 <xref rid="B148-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">148</xref>]. Zhao et al. have obtained a very good electrocatalytic activity as well as long-term durability while using Pt supported graphitic C
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub> catalysts for LOBs [
 <xref rid="B149-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">149</xref>]. Although 2D layered TMNs are capable to offer excellent reaction sites for OER/ORR processes, thereby leading to provide high specific capacity, it is hard to decompose their bi-products (lithium peroxide) and complex experimental processes restrict them from commercialization.
</p>
