<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par22">In other words, a plausible causal chain must be articulated, connecting the action of the responsible party to the bad outcome, which is reflected in observations (i.e., to what actually happened). This can be considered a scientific hypothesis. For the case of damage from permafrost thaw, for example, the causal chain would run from greenhouse gas emissions, to global warming, to regional warming, to permafrost thaw, and finally to the structural damage (e.g., buildings or roads). The first element in this chain is where the liability originates. The last step in the chain would need to be established from local experience and engineering expertise. Everything in between follows from well-established climate science. For example, according to the Technical Summary of the Working Group II report of the IPCC AR5 (IPCC 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">2014</xref>, Table SPM.A1, Polar regions), the observed impacts of climate change include:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par23">Widespread permafrost degradation, especially in the southern Arctic (
   <italic>high confidence</italic>, major contribution from climate change).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>In this case, as permafrost thaw is a slow onset change and is closely linked to regional warming (reflected in the high confidence level), the causal linkage is quite direct. In contrast, for the case of wildfires, the link between regional warming and wildfires is mediated by other meteorological factors such as humidity, precipitation, and windiness, as well as by non-meteorological factors such as forest management and pests, and there is also a random factor involved (ignition). Thus the IPCC attribution in this case is expressed instead as an increase in wildfire 
 <italic>risk or likelihood</italic> (IPCC 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">2014</xref>, Table SPM.A1, North America), and is given only a medium confidence level:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par24">Increased wildfire frequency in subarctic conifer forests and tundra (
   <italic>medium confidence</italic>, major contribution from climate change).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>The establishment of causality through a chain of steps is accepted practice in climate science and climate impacts (Hegerl et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">2010</xref>), and is especially important for connecting the science of IPCC Working Group I (physical climate) to Working Group II (impacts). However, the level of confidence in each step depends on the impact or harm being assessed (see NAS 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">2016</xref>).
</p>
