<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par27">This means that as well as the primary explanation (or primary hypothesis), all plausible alternative explanations for the bad outcome must be articulated. This concept is very Bayesian: to quote Jeffreys (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">1961</xref>, p.58): “We get no evidence for a hypothesis by merely working out its consequences and showing that they agree with some observations, because it may happen that a wide range of other hypotheses would agree with those observations equally well. To get evidence for it we must also examine its various contradictories and show that they do not fit the observations.” In the case of climate impacts, these alternative explanations would include natural climate variability, aspects of climate change not included in the primary hypothesis, and any non-climate factors affecting the impact. The full landscape of possible explanations is depicted in a generic way in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> (see Shepherd 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2019</xref>), for the case of attribution to greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Here, “global warming” refers to global-mean surface temperature increase, “regional warming” refers to those aspects of climate change tied to global warming through well-understood thermodynamic mechanisms (such as Arctic amplification), and represents the primary causal explanation, while “dynamical conditions” refers to more uncertain aspects of climate change such as those related to atmospheric circulation regimes, which are strongly affected by natural variability. Permafrost thaw would be considered the “hazard” and the structural damage the “impact,” the latter being affected by both the exposure and vulnerability of those structures to the hazard. In this schema, wildfires would be considered an impact (since affected strongly by non-meteorological factors), and 
 <italic>wildfire risk or likelihood</italic> (a function of various meteorological factors, e.g., Wotton 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">2009</xref>) the hazard. Note the vulnerability may itself be affected by climate change; e.g., the increase of pest outbreaks in boreal forests (see IPCC 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">2019</xref> SPM A5.2 for high latitudes) can make those forests more prone to wildfire, in which case that causal influence would also need to be included (e.g., Figure 6 of Lloyd and Shepherd 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">2020</xref>). 
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par28">
    <italic>Third, tests that could help discriminate between the different explanations should be considered or conducted. It is recognized that in many cases, it is infeasible to perform direct tests</italic>.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
