<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par31">This step is intended to reflect the fact that in scientific assessments, many different lines of evidence are used (see, e.g., Mastrandrea et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">2011</xref> for the IPCC guidelines). Although some lines of evidence might be considered preferable or ideal, they are not always available, and a variety of independent, individually weak lines of evidence can add up to strong evidence (again, a very Bayesian concept). In tort law cases, if useful evidence is deemed inadmissible, then it may become impossible for the plaintiffs to prove their case (Cranor 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">2005</xref>). The quotations from Weyant in Section 
 <xref rid="Sec2" ref-type="sec">2</xref> appear to suggest that only a fully quantitative modeling chain from the global down to the local scale, including the human-managed element, could demonstrate the required causality. However, this would be setting the bar much too high, since consensus scientific committees such as the IPCC do not require such a standard. Setting such a bar would exclude nearly all published extreme event attribution studies, which generally stop at the hazard, and do not consider the local scale. It would also exclude case studies, which by their very nature are deterministic and not expressed in terms of quantitative probabilities. Yet singular, deterministic causation is a perfectly sensible philosophical concept (Cartwright 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2016</xref>). The storyline approach to extreme event attribution is essentially a case study approach, and was endorsed by a consensus scientific committee (NAS 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">2016</xref>). Moreover, the forensic approach to evidence used in the ecosystem expert community to understand environmental catastrophes, including wildfires, as singular events is well aligned with the storyline approach (Lloyd and Shepherd 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">2020</xref>). 
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par32">
    <italic>Fifth, it must be shown that the bad outcome is more probable with the accountable cause than without it. This requires a consideration of alternative explanations of the observed association, including chance and confounding factors</italic>.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
