<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par53">We used ecosystem services indicators (e.g., NPP for CS) that explain the ecosystem service partially. Therefore, more models are needed to properly assess ecosystem services (Inacio et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">2020</xref>). For instance, NPP does not consider soil carbon sequestration, one of the largest carbon sinks (Guenet et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">2018</xref>). Also, WR was based on a runoff coefficient from literature review conducted by Ouyang et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR113">2016</xref>) and not on field data from the study site. Even though the application of these coefficients was due to the data limitations that may produce uncertainties in the estimations and the studies considered in Ouyang et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR113">2016</xref>) were extensive, field data is necessary to have better ecosystem services assessment. HQ model was validated using tree cover density (%) and above ground-biomass carbon. The best results were identified using above ground-biomass carbon, showing that the health of the ecosystems is more related to biomass carbon than with tree cover. The lack of a better validation can be attributed to the different base data resolution and years used (Table 
 <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>) and the same issues were identified in other studies (e.g., Gomes et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2021</xref>). Other uncertainties may arise as a consequence of future national and global policies. It is clear that substantial efforts are being taken at the national (e.g., Yu et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR108">2021</xref>) and international level (e.g., Cortes et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">2021</xref>) to restore the ecosystems increase carbon sequestration. Different global strategies are trying to pave the road for a more sustainable world (e.g., UN Sustainable Development Goals, UN Decade on Restoration). Nevertheless, it is not certain that global crises will not occur in the future, such as the current COVID-19 pandemic that will affect global goals and shift political options to solve urgent issues (Barbier and Burgess 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">2020</xref>; Miksa et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">2020</xref>; Tonne 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR96">2021</xref>). Although our work has these limitations, we developed a spatially explicit analysis framework for the sensitivity and exposure of ecosystem services to climate change. We compared the exposure risks under different climate scenarios on the Tibetan Plateau, which provides an important reference for regional ecological security.
</p>
