<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We calculated the number of days with &gt;95% ice cover (extreme ice days) within the core wintering area during the wintering period as an index of sea ice severity. The core wintering area was identified based on utilization distributions of satellite‐tagged individuals from 1993–1997 and 2008–2012 and confirmed by aerial surveys of the wintering area (Petersen et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0068" ref-type="bibr">1999</xref>; Sexson et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0085" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>). Observed sea ice concentrations were extracted from the core area that spans four grid cells (25‐km resolution) derived from passive microwave satellite imagery using the Bootstrap Algorithm and provided by the National Snow and Ice Data Center. For comparison, we calculated the number of days with &lt;15% ice cover as a metric of extreme low sea ice conditions (Christie et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0011" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>). However, we found that extreme ice days and extreme low sea ice conditions are highly correlated (
 <italic toggle="yes">r</italic> = −0.84, Pearson's correlation coefficient). Given this strong relationship, we chose to include only the standardized number of days with &gt;95% ice cover (hereafter; ice days) and interpret negative deviations from the mean to be representative of low sea ice cover. We included a quadratic effect of “ice days” for adult survival and nest success and modeled the effects using linear models on the logit link scale. Though hatch‐year birds are expected to use the same wintering areas and are thus subject to similar conditions, we expected that due to inexperience, survival would be sensitive to environmental conditions throughout the annual cycle. Thus, we included a linear term for the effect of the Arctic Oscillation on first‐year survival using a linear model on the logit link scale (NOAA, 
 <xref rid="ece37873-bib-0065" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).
</p>
