<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Whether the advantages of DESs can also be translated in the context of electrochemical applications of graphene remains however largely unexplored. While a few, mostly computational studies investigated DES/graphene interfaces,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref>
 </sup> at present only very limited experimental reports on the electrochemical behavior of graphene in DESs are available. So far, DESs were employed to electrochemically exfoliate graphene from graphite,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref38">38</xref>
 </sup> to covalently functionalize graphene(−oxide),
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref>
 </sup> and to explore the potential application of a DES as an electrolyte in graphene-based supercapacitors.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref>
 </sup> Fundamental characterization of the electrochemical behavior of a defined graphene monolayer in a DES remains however missing. In addition, the applicability of DESs to produce graphene-based hybrid materials by electrochemical means has not been explored yet. Such hybrid materials have been suggested for corrosion protection
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref44">44</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref>
 </sup> of steel, for energy storage
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref46">46</xref>
 </sup> in the case of, for example, graphene/zinc (Zn), or as anode materials in Li-ion batteries
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref47">47</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref>
 </sup> in the case of, for example, graphene/germanium (Ge). All of these bulk composite materials have either been prepared in aqueous media or from the gas phase. While the former procedures may suffer from possible side reactions, for example, hydrogen evolution, which can affect the chemical integrity of graphene as well as the morphology of the composites, the latter method is highly involved and probably difficult to control in a scaled-up procedure. The feasibility of preparing such graphene composites by electrodeposition from cheap and environmentally friendly nonaqueous electrolytes such as DESs has not been explored to date. A detailed understanding of the reactivity of the graphene/DES interface is in this context crucial for a rational selection of fabrication strategies but remains completely missing in the literature.
</p>
