<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To address this, we show here for the first time how centimeter-scale graphene electrodes made from graphene monolayer films
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref49">49</xref>
 </sup> that were produced by chemical vapor deposition (CVD) and transferred onto insulating SiO
 <sub>2</sub>/Si supports, interact with the common DES choline chloride/ethylene glycol of 1:2 molar ratio (12CE) under typical electrochemical conditions, including identification of the graphene/DES potential window and determination of apparent electron transfer kinetics. For comparison, we contrast the observed electrochemical behavior of our graphene electrodes with the behavior of widely used standard glassy carbon electrodes under the same conditions. We also explore how our graphene films can be decorated with metal (Zn) and metalloid (Ge) nanostructures by electrodeposition from DES electrolytes.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref>
 </sup> We have chosen choline chloride/ethylene glycol (12CE) as an archetypal example of DES electrolytes. 12CE fulfills all criteria for technical applications. Its components are cheap and environmentally friendly, while the mixture is easy to prepare, and it shows the highest ionic conductivity at room temperature among such types of electrolytes.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> Consequently, 12CE probably is the most extensively studied DES for electrochemical applications.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> Moreover, also features of the double layer structure at carbon electrodes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref>
 </sup> and some of its mechanistic implications, for example, for the electrodeposition of Zn,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref>
 </sup> have been reported. The double layer structure of three choline chloride-based DESs showed similar features,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>
 </sup> and therefore, the resulting charge transfer behavior is highly likely to be similar as well, particularly for outer sphere redox probes, such as ferrocene.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref54">54</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
