<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The current review has a number of implications for policymakers and intergovernmental organizations such as the World Health Organization. While WHO is increasingly directing its attention to the health impacts of climate change, mental health has generally remained absent from these conversations. For example, as part of the Health and Climate Change Country Profile Project WHO 2019–2020 cycle, WHO reported that only three (i.e., Antigua and Barbuda, United Arab Emirates, and Solomon Islands) out of the 10 recently reviewed countries included mental health and well-being outcomes as part of their climate-sensitive health outcomes monitoring systems [
 <xref rid="B117-ijerph-18-04486" ref-type="bibr">117</xref>]. This is in stark contrast with other conditions such as vector-borne and waterborne disease, for which monitoring systems were in place for nine out of the 10 recently reviewed countries. The current review highlights the need for monitoring systems to systematically include mental health as part of their indicators in order to ensure precise monitoring and availability of data at the national level. Additionally, it indicates the importance of including climate change as an important determinant of mental health in policy documentation and action plans, such as in the future extension of the WHO Mental Health Action Plan 2013–2020 [
 <xref rid="B118-ijerph-18-04486" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>] to 2030. Importantly, future work might want to explore whether existing WHO documentation and intervention plans for humanitarian settings such as the mhGAP-HIG [
 <xref rid="B119-ijerph-18-04486" ref-type="bibr">119</xref>], the Building Back Better framework [
 <xref rid="B120-ijerph-18-04486" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>], and scalable psychological interventions [
 <xref rid="B121-ijerph-18-04486" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>] are applicable in the context of climate change or whether more specific adaptations are needed. Finally, WHO’s recent work on the integration of mental health and psychosocial support (MHPSS) within disaster risk reduction efforts [
 <xref rid="B122-ijerph-18-04486" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>] might represent an important opportunity to integrate climate change within MHPSS.
</p>
