<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Even though the distribution of these salamanders does not appear to be greatly affected by climate change in the near future, species with small distributions are usually at high risk for extinction, and SDM predictions become less reliable for species with smaller distributions (Schwartz et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0076" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>); therefore, it is important that 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. vandykei</italic>, 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. stormi,</italic> and 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. asupak</italic> be closely monitored. Factors that may influence 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon</italic> salamanders are those pertaining to moisture and solar radiation. Given the importance of moisture for a species that spends significant amounts of time and breeds underground, soil composition, salinity, pH, nutrient composition, and moisture retention could be essential for the habitat of 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon</italic> salamanders. Though some studies have considered soil type and rock coverage in assessing species distributions (Suzuki et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0088" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>), none have studied a correlation between climatic variables such as precipitation with soil composition and retention, and how that may impact subterrestrial species response to climate change. This will be especially important for species with small ranges that are currently at risk on some level (e.g., 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. stormi</italic>, and 
 <italic toggle="yes">P. larselli</italic>; Table 
 <xref rid="ece37735-tbl-0001" ref-type="table">1</xref>). Finally, we downloaded spatial layers of protected areas (UNEP‐WCMC &amp; IUCN, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0091" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>) and found that a total of 551 (32%) of our GPS coordinates fell within some sort of protected area (Table 
 <xref rid="ece37735-tbl-0001" ref-type="table">1</xref>) and recommend a concerted effort in maintaining currently protected areas in the PNW.
</p>
