<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Early research utilizing borohydrides in the electrolyte layer was done with the addition of organic liquid carriers [
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Work published by researchers at the Toyota Research Institute of North America (Ann Arbor, MI) [
 <xref rid="B20-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>] used organic liquid phases tetrahydrofuran (THF) and dimethoxyethane (DME) with Mg(BH
 <sub>4</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub> and LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> mixtures as electrolytes in operational batteries and showed reasonably high full cell electric potential and cycle life. Work using Mg(BH
 <sub>4</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub> and LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> was followed by use of carboranes, e.g., (C
 <sub>2</sub>BH
 <sub>10</sub>H
 <sub>11</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>Mg, in diglyme and tetraglyme solvents as electrolytes [
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>] which demonstrated a wide electrochemical window of 3.6 V [
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Similar data were collected in our laboratory at Rowan University in order to determine whether particle morphology is influenced by cycling. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-03239-f004">Figure 4</xref>a shows results of three cycles for voltammetry done by on solutions similar to those used in literature [
 <xref rid="B20-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>] on 2 M LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> with 0.5 M NaBH
 <sub>4</sub> in THF solution. Microstructure changes are indeed apparent before (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-03239-f004">Figure 4</xref>a) and after (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-03239-f004">Figure 4</xref>b) cycling, and these changes could play a role in limiting the cycle life of batteries formed using these materials.
</p>
