<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Thin-film coating of PAA on the surface of the electrode was obtained by electrochemical deposition that also caused 
 <italic>in situ</italic> polymerization. Specifically, a three-electrode cell was assembled using 2 mol L
 <sup>−1</sup> Mg:2AA solution as an electrolyte, the electrode to be coated as the working electrode, an Ag/AgCl reference electrode, and a RVC counter electrode. In order to balance the electrochemical performance and the thickness, we tried a series of electrochemical experiments to control the electrodeposite of PAA. For example, we tried to control voltage, current, time, and so on. Based on the preliminary experiment result, we finally chose the CV electrodeposite method, which can form a uniform PAA layer on the carbon materials' surface. Theoretically, acrylic acid can polymerize on the electrode surface at negative potential due to the electron-induced C=C polymerization (free radical polymerization). However, using constant voltage or current underpotential deposition may result in too fast electrodeposition and form a depletion layer near the electrode; thus, the deposited PAA layer is not uniform enough. Using the CV method with the voltage spanning over -1.6 V to 1.6 V and the scan rate of 50 mV s
 <sup>−1</sup> can obtain a uniform PAA layer. It is because PAA can form on the electrode surface at a negative potential, but since the scan rate is fast, the deposited PAA layer is very thin (~0.4-0.8 nm for each cycle, as shown in Fig. 
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supplementary-material-1">S7</xref>). Besides, the depletion layer near the electrode will not form because of the positive potential range for each cycle, thus the deposition speed for each cycle is quite stable until the PAA layer become too thick. The thick PAA layer (&gt;35 nm) can block the electron out from the electrode even at a negative potential; thus, the free radical polymerization of PAA is stopped. According to our research, the optimized PAA layer thickness is ~15 nm (20 CV cycles), which can expand the ECW to ~2.4 V and maintain the fast charge-discharge properties (Fig. 
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supplementary-material-1">S23</xref>). Other protocols were also experimented, e.g., in Fig. 
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supplementary-material-1">S11C</xref>.
</p>
