<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>However, the applicability of ILs is not limited only to the areas of catalysis and synthetic chemistry, as extensive research works have demonstrated their utility in diverse fields of technology, from energy applications, electropolishing, and electrodeposition to the use of supported ionic liquid as an electrocatalyst [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. The application of ILs in the energy sector is likely the most appealing research area nowadays, especially for the development of energy conversion and storage materials and devices [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. This is driven by the continuous need for the development of innovative systems in order to overcome the issues associated with the existing materials, and hence achieve the main goal of sustainable, safe, and cost-effective systems [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. For example, lithium-ion batteries [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], despite their many advantages, still suffer from major safety issues, especially when they are employed on a large scale or high temperatures, due to the flammability of organic electrolytes. In this regard, ILs can serve as advanced materials to overcome these issues [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Another promising application could be represented by redox flow batteries (RFBs), which possess many attractive properties that make them excellent potential candidates for high energy density grid scale storage [
 <xref rid="B13-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. In this scenario, aqueous RFBs have limited cell voltage. While nonaqueous RFBs offer wider electrochemical windows, in exchange for the poor solubility of electroactive materials, which result in low energy density. In this context, the use of ILs for RFBs holds the potential to further advance this technology [
 <xref rid="B14-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>].
</p>
