<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is worth mentioning that ionic liquids with redox active moieties were know even before the modern definition of RAILs was introduced. This can be demonstrated by the work reported by Shreeve et al. [
 <xref rid="B23-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>], Kumar et al. [
 <xref rid="B24-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>] and Liu et al. [
 <xref rid="B25-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>] on the first ferrocenylmethylimidazolium and ferrocenylmethyltriazolium, the first viologen-based liquid crystalline containing “bis trifluromethylsulfonylimide” (TFSI)) as counter anion, and the first homogeneous mixture of vanadate, 2,2,6,6-tetramethyl-1-piperidinyloxy (TEMPO), acid functionalized ionic liquids, respectively. However, an enormous interest was devoted to the synthesis and application of these systems in energy in the past decade. This is driven by the need to achieve a liquid state system with high redox density. Some important recent studies on metal- and nonmetal-based RAILs are highlighted in 
 <xref rid="materials-14-03259-t001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>, and a few selected examples are discussed below. Very recently, Sagara et al. [
 <xref rid="B26-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>] reported a charge transfer (CT) RAIL prepared by mixing carbazole-based and viologen-based RAILs. In their study, it was shown that mixing the two RAILs lead to unique properties that are distinct from those of the isolated components. Wang et al. [
 <xref rid="B27-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>] synthesized a RAIL bearing the redox active 2,2,6,6-tetramethyl-1-piperidinyloxy bis trifluromethylsulfonylimide (TFSI) for potential application in lithium oxygen batteries. It was demonstrated that adding this RAIL to diethylene glycol diethyl ether (DEGDME) leads to exceptional properties compared to pure DEGDME. A family of RAILs bearing the anthraquinone sulfonate (AQS) as anionic counterpart [
 <xref rid="B28-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>] were reported with different cations including phosphonium, ammonium, imidazolium, piperidinium, and pyrrolidinium. Among them only (P14,6,6,6) was found to be liquid at RT; this can be explained by the symmetry and planarity of the AQS core, coupled with the significant pi–pi intermolecular interaction between anthraquinone moieties, which favor a long-range order rather than liquefaction. In the attempt to achieve an ideal liquid system with a density of redox species close to the solid state, an excellent work has been reported by Fontaine et al. [
 <xref rid="B29-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>] on a bi-redox IL comprising a triflimide anion bearing the redox active anthraquinone (AQ–TFSI) and a methyl imidazolium cation bearing the redox active TEMPO. Rochford et al. [
 <xref rid="B30-materials-14-03259" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>] reported the synthesis of a RAIL based on 2,5-ditert-butyl-1,4-dimethoxybenzene (DDB) and a triflimide anion. This RAIL was highly soluble in carbonate-based electrolytes and holds the potential to be an excellent functional additive in Li-ion battery electrolytes, as it can act as redox shuttle for Li
 <sub>4</sub>Ti
 <sub>5</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>/LiFePO
 <sub>4</sub> lithium-ion batteries.
</p>
