<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There are several technical challenges remaining for lithium ion batteries (in general) and, in particular, for solid-state batteries. Among those are increasing ionic conduction, broadening the electrochemical stability window, alleviating dendrite formation, and achieving high energy density. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-03239-f003">Figure 3</xref> is reproduced from the work by Lu et al. [
 <xref rid="B10-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>] and shows an assessment (in spider diagram) of how well the materials perform as battery electrolytes with respect to ionic conduction, dendrite formation, and width of the electrochemical window (which is defined by anodic reaction and electrochemical oxidation potentials) [
 <xref rid="B10-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Like Lu et al. [
 <xref rid="B10-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], many others have undertaken comprehensive engineering studies on borohydride materials, showing their promise for solid-state battery applications [
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. This overview article examines some of the scientific underpinnings for these performance metrics in borohydride solid electrolytes. The next sections of this overview article focus their discussions solely on ionic conduction and electrochemical stability in order to render detailed treatment of those topics (with some suggestions for experimental undertakings that would enhance the field). This article serves to inspire further research into the topic of borohydrides for solid-state battery applications.
</p>
