<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The incorporation of N-sites has emerged as an effective strategy for enhancing and expanding on the electrochemical performance of carbon materials. Nitrogenated carbons and nanocarbons have become important in the area of non-precious and metal-free electrocatalysts for fuel cell applications (Wong et al., 
 <xref rid="B70" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Gong et al., 
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>), while also being proposed as materials for supercapacitors in energy storage (Deng et al., 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Salanne et al., 
 <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Yang and Zhou, 
 <xref rid="B73" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). As a consequence, nitrogen incorporation strategies have been explored for a range of carbon electrode materials, including carbon nanotubes (Gong et al., 
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>; Tang et al., 
 <xref rid="B60" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>), graphene (Wei et al., 
 <xref rid="B68" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>; Qu et al., 
 <xref rid="B50" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>), graphite (Zhou et al., 
 <xref rid="B78" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>), nanofibers (Maldonado and Stevenson, 
 <xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>) and amorphous/non-crystalline carbons (Wang et al., 
 <xref rid="B67" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>; Zhang et al., 
 <xref rid="B75" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Yamamoto et al., 
 <xref rid="B72" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Dou et al., 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). Nitrogen incorporation results in complex and interrelated effects on the electrochemical properties of carbons, resulting from a combination of electronic (Behan et al., 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>), chemical and structural changes (Serp and Figueiredo, 
 <xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>; Dou et al., 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). Functional N-sites such as pyridinic-N (N
 <sub>Py</sub>), pyrrolic-N (N
 <sub>Pr</sub>), graphitic-N (N
 <sub>G</sub>), and N-oxides (N
 <sub>Ox</sub>) can be incorporated into the carbon structure (Serp and Figueiredo, 
 <xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>) resulting in reactive centers that can significantly affect interfacial interactions with redox species and intermediates (Choi et al., 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>; Guo et al., 
 <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Wu et al., 
 <xref rid="B71" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>; Behan et al., 
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">2019b</xref>) and, consequently, electrocatalytic activity. Nitrogen sites can also affect the electronic properties of carbon electrodes, as they might serve as both n-type or p-type dopants (Zhao et al., 
 <xref rid="B76" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>; Ma et al., 
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>), and can increase carbon conductivity and metallic character (Robertson, 
 <xref rid="B51" ref-type="bibr">2002</xref>; Choi et al., 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>; Behan et al., 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>; Hoque et al., 
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). Furthermore, the role of nitrogen atoms as impurities and the experimental methods used for its incorporation can affect the organization of the carbon scaffold, introducing voids, vacancies, defects and non-graphitizable regions that have dramatic effects on both capacitive and faradaic responses (Zhou et al., 
 <xref rid="B78" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>; Legrain et al., 
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Salanne et al., 
 <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Stamatin et al., 
 <xref rid="B59" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Zhang et al., 
 <xref rid="B74" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Behan et al., 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">2019a</xref>; Ng et al., 
 <xref rid="B46" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Dou et al., 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Hoque et al., 
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Jia et al., 
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Saurel et al., 
 <xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). The importance of improving our understanding and control over the interplay among disorder, functional sites, and electrochemical performance has been highlighted in the recent literature as one of the frontiers in the development of new carbon-based materials for energy technologies (Legrain et al., 
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; Zhang et al., 
 <xref rid="B74" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Bommier et al., 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Dou et al., 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; Saurel et al., 
 <xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). Therefore, there is great interest in developing approaches for achieving control over nanostructuring and chemical functionality to enable a better understanding of structure-function correlations, and novel strategies for the synthesis of smart carbons with tailored ad-/chemisorption sites at heteroatom and carbon defect centers (Salanne et al., 
 <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>; Dou et al., 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).
</p>
