<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) has been widely used to detect trace biological and chemical compounds since it was discovered. Nowadays, SERS plays an increasingly important role in various fields such as life sciences, environmental monitoring, and medical diagnosis [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. The cornerstone of SERS detection is the fabrication of high-quality SERS substrates. Generally, gold or silver plasmonic nanostructures are used to fabricate SERS substrates because they can generate high local electromagnetic fields, owing to the localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR) effect. Thus, these substrates enhance the Raman signals of molecules on the surface of substrate through electromagnetic enhancement mechanisms [
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. The activity of a SERS substrate is strongly correlated with the morphology of its constituent plasmonic nanostructures [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. A variety of SERS substrates have been customized to suit various SERS applications. In particular, flexible substrates have attracted special attention for the practical application of SERS because they can be deformed to better fit the surfaces of interest and collect hazardous materials effectively by wrapping or wiping during on-site detections [
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Moreover, these flexible substrates can be easily cut into specimens of different sizes and shapes as required and can be easily integrated with other devices [
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Common flexible SERS substrates mainly include plasmonic nanostructures and flexible substrates, such as polymer films, carbon nanotubes, graphene, cellulose, and filter paper [
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>].
</p>
