<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The energy crisis is one of the main problems facing our world today, especially energy production and storage [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Uses of fossil fuels as the source of energy production is certainly having a severe impact on ecology due to the production of greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide CO
 <sub>2</sub>, in addition, the discovery of the fossil fuel has been decreasing since 1969 [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. In addition, many developed countries are on their way to substitute fossil fuel and natural gas with biogas for economically and environmentally reasons [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. It should be also pointed out that biowaste pyrolysis is one of the most profitable methods of carbon sequestration [
 <xref rid="B5-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. So, we have to search for alternative sources for energy production and how to store this energy to be able to use it during peak demand. Lithium ion battery (LIB) and supercapacitors (SCs) are the two main devices for energy storage [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. SCs are considered the bridge between LIB (high energy density) and conventional capacitors (high power density). The supercapacitors global market size is increasing every year and it is expected to reach about $16.95 billion by 2027. SCs possess a long life time, high power density, and much shorter charging/discharging times. On the other hand, SCs face the main problem of lower energy density between 5–20 Wh/kg comparable with (LIB) [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. A supercapacitor is a device suitable for the rapid storage and release of energy; it consists of two porous electrodes immersed in electrolyte, i.e., organic, aqueous, or ionic electrolyte, and separated by a porous membrane that allows the migration of electrolyte ions [
 <xref rid="B8-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. A supercapacitor can be used in many applications like consumer electronics, memory back-up systems, and low-emission hybrid electric vehicles [
 <xref rid="B10-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Based on their mode of energy storage, supercapacitors can be classified into two types: (i) Electrochemical double layer capacitors (EDLCs), where energy storage occurs through electrostatic storage which takes place by separating of charges in a Helmholtz double layer at the interface between the electrode and electrolyte interface, so the capacitance depends on the surface area of the used electrode. (ii) Pseudocapacitors, where energy storage occurs through Faradaic electrochemical storage with electron charge transfer by redox reactions [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>].
</p>
