<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Transition metal oxides such as (RuO
 <sub>3,</sub> NiO, Co
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>, and MnO
 <sub>2</sub>) have high specific capacitance and are widely used for pseudocapacitors which store charges by faradic reaction. Among these, RuO
 <sub>2</sub> has been broadly examined as a promising applicant due to its better conductivity and high specific capacitance. However, its enormous scale application is constrained by the high cost and rarity of the Ru element [
 <xref rid="B23-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. In contrast, binary metal oxide such as (NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4,</sub> MnCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>, and ZnCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>) have low cost, abundant resource, and environmental friendliness. Especially, NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub> possesses better electrical conductivity and richer active sites than mono-metal oxides (NiO, Co
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>). Therefore, NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub> is a promising electrode material for energy storage devices including fuel cells, lithium-ion batteries (LIBs), and electrochemical capacitors (ECs) [
 <xref rid="B25-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B26-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,
 <xref rid="B28-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. R.B. Marichi et al. prepared 3D oxygen-rich carbon aerogel/NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub> which has a specific capacitance of 160 F·g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 0.5 A/g for two electrode configuration and 473 F g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 5 mV·s
 <sup>−1</sup> [
 <xref rid="B29-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Stability is another important factor in supercapacitors application, and unfortunately, metal oxides suffer from poor cycling stability. M. Eskandari et al. prepared NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>/MWCNT and NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>/PANI, the stability was 88% and 70% after a 2000 cycle, respectively [
 <xref rid="B25-materials-13-04906" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>].
</p>
