<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A more specific variation of genetic rescue is evolutionary rescue, wherein adaptive evolutionary change is introduced to a population rather than overall genetic diversity [
 <xref rid="B84-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">84</xref>]. One method of evolutionary rescue is targeted gene flow, a form of translocation that involves the introduction of new individuals with particular traits into an existing population with the aim of increasing a population’s evolutionary resilience (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="life-11-00653-f001">Figure 1</xref>). In terms of climate change threats, individuals from a population with favourable alleles, e.g., resilience to high temperatures, could be translocated to another population of the same species that is not adapted to the threat, thereby increasing the resilience of the overall population within a few generations [
 <xref rid="B99-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>]. An example of how targeted gene flow can enhance evolutionary resilience was presented in a pioneering study by Kelly and Phillips (2019) [
 <xref rid="B100-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">100</xref>], who suggested that the introduction of northern quolls (
 <italic>Dasyurus hallucatus</italic>) that avoided eating poisonous and invasive cane toads (
 <italic>Rhinella marina</italic>) to a quoll group naïve to the risks of eating the toads could result in a rapid adaptive response and, ultimately, a more resilient population. Hybrid offspring of toad-exposed and toad-naïve parents showed similar phenotypic responses to offspring of toad-exposed parents only, suggesting the presence of a dominant heritable trait for “toad-smart” behaviour. Although yet to be tested on a real-world population, the results of this study indicate that it is possible to introduce an adaptive response to a threat in a population through targeted gene flow. For targeted gene flow to be successful, however, knowledge of trait variation, heritability, and the underlying genetic variants linked to the trait are needed in order to identify suitable individuals to translocate.
</p>
