<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Within a single species, certain populations may be better adapted to environmental stressors than others. For example, genomic sequencing has revealed within-species variation in heat stress response in both animals and plants [
 <xref rid="B101-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">101</xref>,
 <xref rid="B102-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">102</xref>,
 <xref rid="B103-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">103</xref>]. This has important implications for species management under climate change. Recently, Cummins et al. [
 <xref rid="B104-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">104</xref>] used the commercial genomic sequencing platform Diversity Arrays to conduct a genome-wide analysis of the Australian crawling frog (
 <italic>Pseudophryne guentheri</italic>), which revealed signals of local adaptation and limited gene flow between populations. While individuals living in the hotter, drier regions of the species’ range were better adapted to predicted conditions in Australia under climate change, the more mesic individuals were not. Similarly, a study on greenlip abalone (
 <italic>Haliotis laevigata</italic>) revealed adaptive divergence across ~800 km of coastline that was strongly linked to minimum sea surface temperature and oxygen concentration [
 <xref rid="B105-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">105</xref>]. In both cases, targeted gene flow between populations may encourage viability in the face of rising temperatures and other environmental shifts associated with climate change. Varied resilience to high temperatures has also been observed in coral reefs across natural temperature mosaics, with corals from warmer locations exhibiting mild selection in response to heat stress events [
 <xref rid="B106-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">106</xref>,
 <xref rid="B107-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">107</xref>]. A recent study by Quigley et al. [
 <xref rid="B108-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">108</xref>] modelled the spread of temperature tolerant loci in corals in the Great Barrier Reef under natural and assisted scenarios. They concluded that adaptive variants are unlikely to spread fast enough to combat current rates of warming without human intervention. Targeted gene flow has therefore been flagged as a potential strategy to combat coral bleaching under climate change [
 <xref rid="B109-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">109</xref>]. Further, Jordan et al. [
 <xref rid="B110-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">110</xref>] identified 81 adaptive SNPs in the genome of mottlecah trees (
 <italic>Eucalyptus acrocarpa)</italic>, many of which were associated with variables of aridity, temperature, and rainfall, while Steane et al. [
 <xref rid="B111-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">111</xref>] studied the genomes of a forest tree species, 
 <italic>Eucalyptus tricarpa</italic>, across an area encompassing significant variation in aridity. Genomic divergence was found to be strongly correlated with temperature and moisture availability, evidence of local adaptation to environmental stressors associated with climate change predictions. The authors suggest that such information on the adaptive capacity of the species could be used to inform assisted migration in order to fix beneficial alleles and safeguard vulnerable populations against climate change.
</p>
