<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In particular, CRISPR technology has the potential to be used for gene drives, wherein a beneficial trait is introduced and fixed in a population far more rapidly than natural selection allows [
 <xref rid="B118-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>]. For example, populations of American chestnut trees (
 <italic>Castanea dentata</italic>) have been decimated by the invasive pathogen chestnut blight fungus (
 <italic>Cryphonectria parasitica</italic>) since the early 20th century [
 <xref rid="B119-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">119</xref>]. Researchers recently succeeded in developing transgenic American chestnut trees that demonstrate tolerance to the fungus by inserting a gene from wheat into the genome [
 <xref rid="B117-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">117</xref>]. Gene editing could also be used to introduce deleterious alleles to populations of invasive species in order to reduce fitness and/or fecundity [
 <xref rid="B114-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">114</xref>,
 <xref rid="B118-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>]. Johnson et al. [
 <xref rid="B120-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>] champion the applications of gene-editing technology for conservation, including the possibility of removing genetic disorders from a population, increasing genetic diversity following a bottleneck, or controlling the spread of invasive species. It represents a method of introducing beneficial alleles to a population that is threatened by climate change, particularly in situations where translocations are not possible [
 <xref rid="B112-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">112</xref>]. In some systems, such as coral reefs, the introduction of natural or synthetic genes may aid in increasing resilience of species vulnerable to climate change effects [
 <xref rid="B121-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>]. Zafar et al. [
 <xref rid="B122-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>] discuss the possibility of using CRISPR technologies to develop novel quantitative trait loci in plants to increase resilience to abiotic environmental stressors including drought, temperature, and salinity. Further, CRISPR microinjection performed on larvae of the reef-building coral species 
 <italic>Acropora millepora</italic> resulted in a ~50% mutation rate on all three target genes [
 <xref rid="B123-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">123</xref>]. All target genes were putatively responsive to environmental stressors.
</p>
