<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Working with plants from the Portuguese “Judia” cultivar, ref. [
 <xref rid="B81-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">81</xref>] concluded that the morphological and phenological differences among ecotypes are related to the small genetic differences and phenotypic adaptations to different climatic conditions. The chestnut tree has high adaptability to abiotic stresses, resulting from genetic and physiological bases [
 <xref rid="B26-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Specific climatic variables influenced the frequency distribution and fixation of several alleles, resulting in local adaptation processes of the populations [
 <xref rid="B15-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Therefore, there is an adaptative variation among populations from extreme conditions that define a plants’ geographical distribution according to its genetic feature. The production of genetically modified organisms is a powerful tool to develop new resistance mechanisms of resistance to the heterogeneity of the climate and the presence of pests and diseases. In this procedure, attention should be paid to potential risks and biosafety concerns. The tolerance to diseases and insects may be a major aspect of the varietal and clonal selection, thereby avoiding the excessive use of pesticides and herbicides [
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. In the case of the chestnut tree, understanding the basic genetic structure of ink disease resistance will increase the accuracy of genomic selection for disease resistance [
 <xref rid="B15-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B52-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]. Vegetative propagation disease-resistant cultivars and rootstocks are desirable for growing chestnuts as a crop. Conventional propagation and micropropagation are the vegetatively propagated method, being that micropropagation is more efficient in the large-scale production of individual genotypes [
 <xref rid="B2-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>].
</p>
