<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In general, the anode or cathode materials are characterized physicochemically through various type of spectroscopy and microscopy techniques such as field emission-scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM), high resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analyses. The microscopic analyses using FE-SEM and HR-TEM are used to probe the morphological evolution of electrode materials during the galvanostatic charge-discharge (GCD) process, which affords a vision into the favored reaction sites. The damage caused by the electron-beam of FE-SEM analysis is almost less than that caused by HR-TEM, which makes it feasible to analyze the reaction products and by-products such as Li
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> and Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>, respectively, which are highly unstable when exposed to an electron beam [
 <xref rid="B64-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>,
 <xref rid="B65-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>]. In order to avoid such risk factors, in-situ HR-TEM has employed to study the electrochemical process of Li–O
 <sub>2</sub>, which provides temporal and spatial resolution and does not mimic the cell’s environment as much as compared to other microscopic analyses. XRD study is used to determine and quantify the crystallinity of the reaction product/by-product include Li
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> and Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>. Furthermore, the electrochemical oxidation of the reaction site products can be monitored by in-situ operando-XRD analysis during GCD process. Another important technique of XPS has been used to evaluate the surface chemistry and spatial distribution of GCD reaction products, including Li
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> and Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>, and also provides the basic knowledge on these reaction products interactions with the electrolyte and electrodes. The BET analysis provides the complete understanding of porosity properties of the cathode catalysts such as pore volume, surface, and diameter and plays a key role to evaluate the discharge capacity of the LOB cell.
</p>
