<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Crop production is strongly influenced by water availability. Climate change will alter rainfall patterns, soil moisture storage, evaporation and runoff. It is estimated that more than 80% of total global crop production is supplied by rainfall, and therefore changes in total seasonal rainfall or its patterns are very important [
 <xref rid="B34-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. There is clear evidence of amplification of the global hydrological cycle, which is strongly influenced by changes in temperature. However, its impact on crop production is still very difficult to predict as it depends on other climate parameters such as the intensity and frequency of extreme weather events [
 <xref rid="B35-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. Changes in precipitation patterns may be of greater importance to agriculture than changes in temperature, especially in regions where dry seasons may be a limiting factor for crop production [
 <xref rid="B3-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. According to Lickley and Solomon [
 <xref rid="B36-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>] a drying trend is emerging in Southern and Northern Africa, parts of Latin America, Australia and Southern Europe. Moreover, the models predict significant drying for these regions as well as for the southern parts of North America by mid-century, with an increase in drought of more than 10% and a moisture deficit of more than 200 mm per year. In Mediterranean countries, cereal yields are limited by water scarcity, heat stress and short grain filling duration. Therefore, permanent crops such as olives, grapevine and citrus are of greater importance in this region. These crops are greatly affected by extreme weather events such as hail and storms, which can subsequently reduce or completely destroy yield [
 <xref rid="B34-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Due to high evapotranspiration and limited rainfall, attention should be given to the development of irrigation techniques that allow efficient and effective use of available water resources, as well as good agronomic practices that emphasize moisture conservation and thus improve crop productivity [
 <xref rid="B37-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. Lack of water in the soil can cause plants to lose their biological functions and become even more susceptible to diseases and pests [
 <xref rid="B38-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. On the other hand, the world has become wetter in large areas such as northern Europe and eastern parts of the Americas, with extreme rainfall events contributing strongly to the increase in global precipitation [
 <xref rid="B8-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Direct analysis of precipitation extremes (largest annual 1-day precipitation accumulation/largest annual 5-day precipitation accumulation) shows that extreme precipitation has increased in large parts of the world, with an increase in the potential of a typical 2-year event of about 7% over the period from 1951 to 1999 [
 <xref rid="B39-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. Due to the wet weather conditions on the Atlantic coast and in the European mountainous regions, there are cold and rainy summers that lead to yield and quality losses in various arable crops [
 <xref rid="B34-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. These wet conditions can also affect the workability of the soil and reduce the number of working days of agricultural machinery [
 <xref rid="B41-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. Overall, the exact nature of forthcoming climatic changes is still uncertain, but current projections indicate that they are very likely to have serious impacts on crops in the near future.
</p>
