<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Over the last few decades, substantial efforts have been made to develop an anion exchange membrane with excellent electrochemical performance and distinguished reliability with regard to mechanical deformation. Since the complexes of alkali metal ions with poly(ethylene oxide) (PEO) were reported by Fenton et al. in 1973, PEO-based solid films have been considered for AEMs [
 <xref rid="B11-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. However, the crystallization induced low ionic conductivity (10
 <sup>−7</sup> to 10
 <sup>−8</sup> S cm
 <sup>−1</sup> at ambient temperature) and poor mechanical properties, especially in high KOH concentration, which severely restricted the application in electrochemical devices. In order to increase ionic conductivity, a polyvinyl alcohol PVA–KOH alkaline polymer electrolyte system was developed by Lewandowski et al. [
 <xref rid="B13-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>] using ac impedance and cyclic voltammetry methods, showing a conductivity about of 10
 <sup>−4</sup> S cm
 <sup>−1</sup> at room temperature with poor mechanical properties. One promising approach to outperform the alkaline polymer electrolyte is to chemically cross-link the polymer matrix [
 <xref rid="B14-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. By introducing the cross-link bone, the electrochemical performance and mechanical properties of the alkaline polymer electrolyte can be tailored to a higher level of performance. However, cross-linked polymer membranes are prone to becoming crisp, especially in high-alkaline environments. Another effective method to improve the ionic conductivity and mechanical properties of alkaline polymer membranes is to incorporate fillers such as fiberglass [
 <xref rid="B17-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], titanium oxide [
 <xref rid="B18-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>], chitosan [
 <xref rid="B19-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>], carbon nanotubes [
 <xref rid="B20-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>], or graphene oxide-magnetite [
 <xref rid="B21-membranes-11-00224" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>] into the PVA polymer matrix.
</p>
