<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At the same time, the other climate visuals tested–the maps–were found to be the least favoured and effective of the three materials, with the combination of technical language, climate model projections, carbon scenarios, and red colouring leaving participants confused or skeptical. Maps have become popular in communicating scientific information on climate change over the past decades, as they can be particularly effective when hazards have a spatio-temporal component [
 <xref rid="pone.0252952.ref044" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. However, the use of scientific images in climate communications (e.g. maps, graphics) often depict climate change as a natural process and may not compel individual action, thus leaving viewers feeling powerless [
 <xref rid="pone.0252952.ref045" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]. In our study, people found the maps alarming or impactful, few understood them fully, and many expressed negative feelings towards them as a result. Research on climate information websites designed to share downscaled climate data have found similar results, as these sites often assume a higher level of understanding of scientific concepts and associated jargon among their users than there actually is [
 <xref rid="pone.0252952.ref015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Another common critique among participants related to the “colour ramp” of maps, which people felt was scary, confusing, or deceiving. Colour ramps portray not only the data but also evoke different emotional reactions, carrying cultural associations such as red for danger [
 <xref rid="pone.0252952.ref037" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="pone.0252952.ref046" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>], and these various design choices can trigger differentiated responses that affect the perceived credibility of climate maps and visualizations [
 <xref rid="pone.0252952.ref047" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. Compared to the video, the more complex mapped climate projections were not as comprehensible for the vast majority of participants. While the medium of video, and to a lesser degree the article, translates climate science through narrative and emotion, climate projection maps did less to translate the knowledge. Arguably, a more sequenced approach for climate communication when engaging audiences of low knowledge or concern on climate change might be: (1) video that incorporates storytelling as a tool for initial engagement; (2) articles with narrative and visual components as a second step; and (3) more complex climate maps once the audience has been engaged. Maps are a critical tool to communicate scientific information, but may require more audience knowledge and participation in decoding the information, and are perhaps most effective in combination with other climate visuals and contextual information.
</p>
