<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The impacts of climate change, which include increased climate variability, have gradual effects on food production, society, and the economy [
 <xref rid="B23-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. Agriculture is one of the sectors most sensitive to changes in climate and the corresponding impacts. For agriculture, the precipitation and temperature patterns, as well as their distribution throughout the year, and the incidence of extreme weather events, are the most critical variables in sector sustainability [
 <xref rid="B23-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B54-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>]. Over the last century, a vast literature has revealed that change in the timing of natural events, such as the rise in spring temperatures, has been affecting different plant species around the world [
 <xref rid="B54-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>]. The increasing temperatures, and strengthened intensity and frequency of extreme meteorological events, have augmented the exposure and vulnerability of each specific crop to climate change risks [
 <xref rid="B24-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B55-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. Since the second half of the 19th century, a rise in global mean air temperature has been recorded (currently almost 1.0 °C), accompanied by more frequent and severe weather extremes, largely driven by anthropogenic radiative forcing [
 <xref rid="B56-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>,
 <xref rid="B57-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>]. Heavy rainfall events have become more frequent, whereas cold temperature extremes have become less frequent during the second half of the 19th century [
 <xref rid="B56-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>,
 <xref rid="B58-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>]. Extreme events are considered as sources of crop yield variability and health vulnerability [
 <xref rid="B59-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]. Furthermore, an increase in atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration was been documented. This increase may stimulate productivity growth, but combined with other factors, such as high temperatures (heat stress), the altered precipitation patterns (water stress), accompanied by an increasing frequency of extreme weather events, may hinder crop productivity [
 <xref rid="B23-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B54-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>,
 <xref rid="B60-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]. The increased interannual temperature variability has been influenced the spring and winter periods. The events in spring have been occurring earlier in recent decades [
 <xref rid="B54-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>,
 <xref rid="B60-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>].
</p>
