<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Methodological advances, particularly in computational ecology and archaeology, and better integration of ecological and anthropological theory, have changed the situation considerably since the 20th century, however. There are still disputes as to the relative importance of the internal and external factors that collectively drive cultural change, but as Arkush points out: “our differences lie in the extent to which we stress contingency versus process, and agency versus conditions, in the making of diverse human histories” (ref. 
 <xref rid="r27" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, p. 200). An increasing number of scientists are striving to develop research frameworks that integrate environmental and human systems (e.g., refs. 
 <xref rid="r25" ref-type="bibr">26</xref> and 
 <xref rid="r28" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>
 <xref rid="r29" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r30" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>). In archaeology, integrative approaches to the study of human–environment interactions are now widely adopted, as reflected in the use of terms such as “niche construction,” “evo-devo,” “biocultural,” “socio-natural,” “socioecological,” and “ecocultural.” An emerging consensus among climate scientists also recognizes that the internal dynamics of human systems should be considered on an equal footing with the “external” natural processes with which they interact (
 <xref rid="r31" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>, 
 <xref rid="r32" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>). Interactions between human systems and the environment are seen as flowing in both directions. The archaeology of climate change capitalizes on these relatively recent developments in archaeology, in addition to developments in climate modeling (see 
 <italic toggle="yes">Climate Modeling and Environmental Reconstruction</italic>), offering an integrative, multidisciplinary framework for identifying key aspects of climate that affect human systems (and vice versa) at different spatiotemporal scales.
</p>
