<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par44">Precipitation and temperature are fundamental driving forces for ecosystem processes change and vegetation distribution and productivity, affecting CS substantially (Zhao and Running 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR110">2010</xref>; Chen et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">2014</xref>; Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">2014</xref>). Increasing precipitation will reduce water deficit stress, promote vegetation photosynthesis, increase vegetation growth (Piao et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR70">2003</xref>; Zhang et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR109">2016</xref>), and therefore enhance CS. Additionally, warming can increase NPP by boosting photosynthesis rates and plant growth (Sullivan et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR91">2008</xref>). Our results showed that CS in Guoluo, Haibei, and Yushu had a positive sensitivity to precipitation, where CS and precipitation had a growth trend (Figs. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> and S1). However, in the large area of the Hengduan Mountains, the change of CS and precipitation had the opposite trend. This is because the decline of precipitation in this area is not significant. Therefore, the effects on CS may be limited. On the other hand, implementing various ecological restoration projects such as the Grain for Green Project (initiated in 2000) improved vegetation conditions in the Hengduan Mountains (Qu et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR78">2018</xref>). This may have played an essential role in improving CS (Tao et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR95">2016</xref>; Qu et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR78">2018</xref>). Yin et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR107">2020</xref>) also confirmed that climate change had a limited impact on NPP improvement in this region. Overgrazing, sloping cropland reclamation, and forest harvest, due to population growth and urbanization, reduced CS (Yin et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR107">2020</xref>). Furthermore, soil erosion events were identified in this area due to cropland reclamation in slopes, affecting vegetation growth (Liu et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">2010</xref>; Zhao et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR111">2015</xref>).
</p>
