<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Lastly, Amanchukwu et al. [
 <xref rid="B128-materials-14-03840" ref-type="bibr">128</xref>] synthesized a new class of fluorinated ether electrolytes that combine the oxidative stability of hydrofluoroethers (HFEs) with the ionic conductivity of ethers in a single compound. Among their main results, they showed that their fluorinated ether electrolytes can achieve an ionic conductivity of 2.7 × 10
 <sup>−4</sup> S/cm at 30 °C with a higher oxidative stability of up to 5.6 V compared to classical ether electrolytes. They used two methods to determine the oxidative stability of the electrolytes. In the first approach they used a classical LSV measurement in a SS/Li cell with an applied scanning rate of 0.1 mV/s from an open circuit to 6 V. They observed good electrochemical stabilities up to 5 V. They also used potentiostatic holds (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-14-03840-f009">Figure 9</xref>), also called Potentiostatic Intermittent Titration Technique (PITT), to accurately probe the oxidative stability of the fluorinated ether electrolytes. They argue that long Potentiostatic hold experiments are less sensitive to the influence of impurities which could lead to an early increase of the current in LSV experiments not corresponding to the actual oxidation of the compound. Finally, their conclusions were made by using a stainless steel, aluminum, or Ni-rich NMC 811 electrodes with different electrolytes and by holding the potential for 3 h at increasingly higher potentials. The recorded current should decrease if no undesired Faradaic reactions occurs. Their best synthesized fluorinated ether electrolyte reached an oxidative stability of 5.6 V. Despite, the fact that this study was conducted on liquid electrolytes, the electrochemical “potentiostatic holds” method could serve as a solid base and could be extended to the ESW evaluation of Solid polymer electrolytes. For instance, Zhang et al. [
 <xref rid="B129-materials-14-03840" ref-type="bibr">129</xref>] used this method of potentiostatic holds to determine the anodic stability of different polymer electrolytes.
</p>
