<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A similarly comparative study based on potentiodynamic and galvanostatic results for several active materials was conducted by Homann et al. [
 <xref rid="B124-materials-14-03840" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>]. In their work, they consider PEO-based SPE under battery cell operation to evidence cell failure and to clear up reported ambiguities regarding oxidation stability. Then, they conducted electrochemical stability evaluations on various cathode materials that are usually used in Lithium batteries (NMC, LMO, LNMO and LFP) via LSV (potentiodynamic) and galvanostatic measurements. The onset of oxidation can be detected by an exponential (e.g., Butler–Volmer) current increase and a potential plateau, respectively. LSV measurements were conducted with an applied scanning rate of 0.1 mV/s. For the galvanostatic approach, electrodes were charged with a specific current of 15 mA/g. Preliminary evaluations were conducted by LSV on a Pt inert working electrode and revealed an Eox around 4.9 V (the choice of the cut-off current was fixed arbitrary without further explanation). However, as mentioned earlier in this review and by the present authors, the validity of this result is questionable, as the surface area of the Pt foil is small compared to that of composite battery electrodes in practical cells. Then, they decided to implement a galvanostatic approach to improve the accuracy of their measurement. Thus, LSV on a conductive carbon electrode with higher surface area was applied and a lower onset oxidative potential of 4.6 V was obtained. Moreover, to be closer to real evaluating characterizations and battery conditions, galvanostatic experiments were performed on a conductive carbon electrode, NMC, LNMO, LMO and LFP working electrodes to confirm the LSV observations. Like the LSV experiment, the galvanostatic approach revealed that the onset of oxidation occurred at 4.6 V vs. Li
 <sup>+</sup>/Li, as seen by the respective potential plateau. These results are shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-14-03840-f007">Figure 7</xref>.
</p>
