<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par34">We used a combination of δ
 <sup>15</sup>N (stable isotope of nitrogen), the ratio of Cadmium (Cd) and Titanium (Ti) concentrations in the lake sediments, concentrations and fluxes of cholesterol and β-sitosterol and diatom assemblage composition changes to assess the presence/absence and relative size of the adjacent little auk colony through time. δ
 <sup>15</sup>N differs markedly between marine and freshwater systems and has been shown to provide an unequivocal signal of marine-derived nutrients (MDN)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. Cd is also more concentrated in the marine system and thus can be used to trace seabird influence
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>
 </sup>. Cd is abundant in the seabird excrement, but it may also be present in the lake’s catchment and so the ratio Cd:Ti is used, as Ti is a proxy of catchment input to the lake. The development of soil, peat and permafrost in the catchment stores C, N and perhaps to a lesser extent Cd, reducing the quantities delivered to the lake and affecting isotope fractionation. The extremely high values of δ
 <sup>15</sup>N and cholesterol at the time of bird arrival likely reflect the absence of soil in the catchment and the unimpeded flow of bird-derived compounds into the lake. In the event that the inputs of C, N and Cd are reduced due to reduced supply as bird numbers fall, the catchment has the potential to act as a source. Thus, whilst the isotopes of N give a clear signal of bird arrival, they have the potential to be less reliable in tracking absence as a result of their storage and subsequent release. This may depend on the residence time of the lake and the degree of flushing by non-bird impacted waters. The combination of total cholesterol flux and the ratio of cholesterol to cholesterol plus β-sitosterol has been used to identify marine bird influence in freshwater systems in the Arctic (e.g. ref. 
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>
 </sup>).
</p>
