<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par35">Marine zooplankton, upon which the little auks feed, are rich in cholesterol but contain virtually no β-sitosterol. In contrast, terrestrial and freshwater primary producers contain a high proportion of β-sitosterol
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>
 </sup>. We found very high cholesterol concentrations (1497 µg g
 <sup>−1</sup>) and low β-sitosterol concentrations (15 µg g
 <sup>−1</sup>) in little auk excrement, contrasting with goose excrement collected in the same region (16 µg g
 <sup>−1</sup> of cholesterol and 159 µg g
 <sup>−1</sup> of β-sitosterol), a species which largely grazes on terrestrial vegetation. Thus, when seabirds are abundant, cholesterol values in the lake sediments can be expected to be high, and the ratio of cholesterol to cholesterol plus β-sitosterol should also be high. In the NOW region, the ratio is 10-fold higher in little auk excrement (0.99) compared with goose excrement (0.09). This ratio of cholesterol to cholesterol plus β-sitosterol has been previously used as an index of seabird influence, with a value of around 0.6 indicating that the majority of the cholesterol originates from seabirds
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>
 </sup>. This index was derived from studies of fulmar colonies in relatively oligotrophic systems, which is not the case at Annikitsoq, where the lake is situated in extremely eutrophic systems (due to the little auk colony) with lush vegetation in the catchment and freshwater algae thriving in the water column, both of which are sources of β-sitosterol. Here, the arrival of little auks, and with them large quantities of MDN, transformed nutrient availability, prompting a period of exceptionally high terrestrial and aquatic biological productivity. This is demonstrated by the fact that 2 m of peat accumulated in the catchment adjacent to the lake in just 1000 years, following little auk colonisation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">65</xref>
 </sup>, and the extremely high LOI values recorded in the lake (75% instead of &lt;10% as expected for a High Arctic lake). Therefore, in addition to the large input of marine-derived cholesterol, there was also the input of cholesterol of terrestrial and freshwater origin, which has a higher proportion of β-sitosterol. Thus, a slight drop in bird input combined with increased terrestrial production, as nutrient levels remain sufficient, would result in a lower ratio, even when birds may still be present. Thus, whilst the ratio is still a useful indicator (especially when &lt;0.4), we have not used a cut-off value signalling the dominance of seabird influence but instead simply present the index value over time. Bird absence is most likely when both cholesterol and the ratio of cholesterol to cholesterol plus β-sitosterol are low.
</p>
