<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The survival curves in continental climates show a later drop compared to those in maritime climates (
 <xref rid="ref24" ref-type="bibr">Haegeli et al., 2011</xref>). The snow characteristics and pattern of avalanche debris seem to have direct effects. Asphyxia occurs earlier in snow climates where snow has a higher density. Snow is a highly porous medium containing a large amount of interstitial air. If the upper airway is not obstructed, breathing in medium to low snow density allows longer survival than breathing in high-density snow, as higher oxygen availability slows oxygen desaturation (
 <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5</xref>). In a field study, none of participants breathing in an air pocket of 4 L in medium or low-density snow had to stop the trial due to hypoxia (i.e., SpO
 <sub>2</sub> ≤ 75%) within 30 min, while about 60% of the trials had to be interrupted when breathing in high snow density (
 <xref rid="ref73" ref-type="bibr">Strapazzon et al., 2017</xref>). Survivors of long burials may sustain critically low levels of oxygen and carbon dioxide before hypothermia can protect the central nervous system, especially in snow of low or medium density. Dense snow in avalanche debris is likely to interfere with respiration and oxygenation of completely buried victims (
 <xref rid="ref73" ref-type="bibr">Strapazzon et al., 2017</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ref71" ref-type="bibr">2021</xref>). In an animal study, pigs without sufficient exchange of respiratory gases became hypoxemic with a mixed respiratory and metabolic acidosis and increased serum potassium (
 <xref rid="ref50" ref-type="bibr">Paal et al., 2013</xref>). Wet, higher density snow was associated with rapid depletion of oxygen in human subjects buried in simulated avalanche debris (
 <xref rid="ref73" ref-type="bibr">Strapazzon et al., 2017</xref>). Wet snow was also associated with decreased cerebral oxygenation (
 <xref rid="ref71" ref-type="bibr">Strapazzon et al., 2021</xref>). These data might partially explain the differing survival curves between maritime and continental climates in Canada (
 <xref rid="ref24" ref-type="bibr">Haegeli et al., 2011</xref>). Climate change might lead to wetter snow earlier in winter in continental areas and at higher elevations with lower survival rates in avalanche burials.
</p>
