<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Insects are poikilothermic or cold-blooded animals and therefore have a limited capacity for homeostasis in response to changes in ambient temperature. They have evolved a variety of strategies to stay alive under thermally stressful environmental conditions [
 <xref rid="B95-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">95</xref>]. The most critical season for many insect pests is winter, as low temperatures can significantly increase mortality and thus reduce populations in the following season [
 <xref rid="B81-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">81</xref>]. Studies have shown that global warming is most pronounced in winter at high latitudes [
 <xref rid="B8-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Therefore, insects that undergo a winter diapause are likely to experience the greatest changes in their thermal environment [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>]. In terms of overwintering strategies, insects are generally classified into two groups: freeze-tolerant and freeze-avoidant. The first group of insects uses a physiological adaptation strategy in the form of diapause, while the second group uses a strategy in the form of behavioural avoidance or migration [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>]. Insects may enter diapause, which is an obligate or facultative, hormonally mediated state of low metabolic activity characterized by suppressed development, suspended activity, and increased resistance to adverse environmental extremes [
 <xref rid="B97-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>]. Diapause is an adaptive trait that plays an important function in the seasonal regulation of insect life cycles and is influenced by environmental factors such as temperature, photoperiod and humidity [
 <xref rid="B98-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>]. Aestivation and hibernation are two types of diapause. Aestivation allows insects to survive in environments with higher temperatures, while hibernation keeps them alive at lower temperatures [
 <xref rid="B99-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>]. In this article, we will focus only on winter diapause—hibernation.
</p>
