<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The adaptive significance of the seasonal response to photoperiodism is to shut down further development and reproduction by preparing metabolic activities for winter dormancy, even though current environmental conditions possibly be favourable [
 <xref rid="B101-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">101</xref>]. Moreover, considering the complex roles insects play in the ecosystem, many other processes are synchronous with their diapause programme, such as plant consumption, pollination, or interspecies interactions. Consequently, a single disruption of diapause as a result of anthropogenic climate change can have profound effects on the stability of the entire ecosystem. Therefore, when discussing the effects of climate change, it is important to consider the effects of climate warming on all three phases of diapause, namely diapause initiation, diapause, diapause termination, and post-diapause quiescence [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>]. For many insect species, it is likely that higher temperatures during the photoperiodic induction of diapause (usually in autumn) reduce the frequency and duration of diapause [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>]. In the European bluebottle fly (
 <italic>Calliphora vicina</italic> Robineau-Desvoidy), for example, adult flies reared at 20 °C produce a smaller number of diapausing offspring. Diapause is also shorter than in flies reared at 15 °C [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>,
 <xref rid="B102-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">102</xref>]. In cases where diapause is obligate for successful overwintering, higher temperatures are required to allow development to the next diapausing generation before severe winter conditions begin. In addition, for many temperate insect species, delaying diapause poses the risk of encountering cold stress outside diapause or before cold tolerance mechanisms are established [
 <xref rid="B101-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">101</xref>].
</p>
