<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This is believed to determine the current northern range of the Green stink bug (
 <italic>Nezara viridula</italic> L.) in Japan. Only diapausing adults of 
 <italic>N. viridula</italic> are capable of overwintering, and winter conditions (timing of diapause induction) at the northern border begin when stink bugs reach only the nymphal stages. The entire population is, therefore, doomed to decline [
 <xref rid="B103-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">103</xref>]. Further south, however, there is a sufficiently long growing season for this generation to reach the adult stage before winter, and at these sites 
 <italic>N. viridula</italic> has displaced the most recently dominant pest specie, the Oriental green stink bug (
 <italic>Nezara antennata</italic> Scott) [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>,
 <xref rid="B104-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">104</xref>]. The duration of diapause can be influenced by many factors: accumulated chilling, humidity, food, and photoperiod [
 <xref rid="B97-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>]. However, for many species, the general principle is that the duration of diapause is shorter at higher temperatures. For example, the flesh fly (
 <italic>Sarcophaga crassipalpis</italic> Macquart), a common laboratory insect used to study diapause processes, remains in diapause for 118 days at 17 °C, 70 days at 25 °C, and 57 days at 28 °C [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>,
 <xref rid="B105-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">105</xref>]. This is because warmer winter temperatures increase the metabolic rate of diapause, resulting in a shorter diapause. A comparison of metabolic rates and diapause duration under these different conditions suggests that diapause ends when energy reserves reach a critical point. When metabolic rate is high, energy reserves are depleted quickly, and when metabolic rate is low, this set point is reached much later, resulting in a longer diapause [
 <xref rid="B105-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">105</xref>].
</p>
