<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7193642</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">64085</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-64085-2</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Improved Non-Grignard Electrolyte Based on Magnesium Borate Trichloride for Rechargeable Magnesium Batteries</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>Kazuhiko</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Mori</surname><given-names>Goro</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kiyosu</surname><given-names>Takahiro</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Yaji</surname><given-names>Toyonari</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Nakanishi</surname><given-names>Koji</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ohta</surname><given-names>Toshiaki</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Okamoto</surname><given-names>Kuniaki</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Orikasa</surname><given-names>Yuki</given-names></name><address><email>orikasa@fc.ritsumei.ac.jp</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label>FUJIFILM Wako Pure Chemical Corporation, 1633 Matoba, Kawagoe, Saitama, 350-1101 Japan </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0000 8863 9909</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.262576.2</institution-id><institution>SR Center, Ritsumeikan University, 1-1-1 Nojihigashi, Kusatsu, </institution></institution-wrap>Shiga, 525-8577 Japan </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0000 8863 9909</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.262576.2</institution-id><institution>Department of Applied Chemistry, </institution><institution>College of Life Sciences, Ritsumeikan University, 1-1-1 Nojihigashi, Kusatsu, </institution></institution-wrap>Shiga, 525-8577 Japan </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label>Present Address: Laboratory of Advanced Science and Technology for Industry, University of Hyogo, 3-1-2 Koto, Kamigori-cho, Ako-gun, Hyogo, 678-1205 Japan </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>30</day><month>4</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>30</day><month>4</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2020</year></pub-date><volume>10</volume><elocation-id>7362</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>19</day><month>2</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>9</day><month>4</month><year>2020</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2020</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">The high anodic stability of electrolytes for rechargeable magnesium batteries enables the use of new positive electrodes, which can contribute to an increase in energy density. In this study, novel Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-, Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes were prepared with AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme. The Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte showed anodic stability over 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg but was chemically unstable, whereas the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte was chemically stable but featured lower anodic stability than the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte. Advantageously, the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte showed both anodic stability over 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg (possibly due to the Lewis acidic nature of B in B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>) and chemical stability (possibly due to the hard acid character of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>). B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, which was prepared by reacting boric acid with a Grignard reagent, was characterized by nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy, Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS). The above analyses showed that B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> has a complex structure featuring coordinated tetrahydrofuran molecules. <sup>27</sup>Al NMR spectroscopy and Al <italic>K</italic>-edge XAS showed that when B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> was present in the electrolyte, AlCl<sub>3</sub> and AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> species were converted to AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>. Mg <italic>K</italic>-edge XAS showed that the Mg species in B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes are electrochemically positive. As a rechargeable magnesium battery, the full cell using the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte and a Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub> Chevrel phase cathode showed stable charge-discharge cycles. Thus, B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes, the anodic stability of which can be increased to ~3&#x02009;V by the use of appropriate battery materials, are well suited for the development of practical Mg battery cathodes.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Batteries</kwd><kwd>Batteries</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2020</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">Rechargeable magnesium batteries are promising alternatives to lithium-ion batteries, featuring high theoretical volumetric capacity (3832 mAh/cm<sup>3</sup>), high safety derived from the nondendritic behavior of deposited magnesium, and the high abundance of magnesium metal compared with that of lithium<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref></sup>. However, the advantages of magnesium batteries are only possible if appropriate electrolytes and cathodes are used with magnesium metal. Although various electrolytes have been developed for magnesium batteries by several pioneering researchers, they require further improvement for practical application<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par3">Early studies have shown that plating/stripping of magnesium does not occur in the electrolytes of simple magnesium salts, such as Mg(ClO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, in conventional organic solvents owing to the passivating surface/blocking layer of magnesium<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. Aurbach <italic>et al</italic>. reported a prototype magnesium battery comprising Mg metal anodes and a Chevrel phase cathode<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. The &#x0201c;dichloro complex&#x0201d; or &#x0201c;all-phenyl complex&#x0201d; electrolyte, which is a complex solution composed of organomagnesium compounds or organomagnesium halide with a Lewis acid such as AlCl<sub>3</sub>, was used for their prototype batteries<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. Non-Grignard magnesium-based electrolytes, such as amide-<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup>, phenolate-<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>, and alkoxide-based<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup> ones, have also been developed to be used in combination with active materials such as sulfur and to decrease sensitivity to air/moisture.</p><p id="Par4">For example, Kim <italic>et al</italic>. developed [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>3</sub>&#x000b7;6THF][HMDSAlCl<sub>3</sub>] (THF&#x02009;=&#x02009;tetrahydrofuran, HMDS&#x02009;=&#x02009;hexamethyldisilazane) and used it in a Mg/S battery<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup>. Doe <italic>et al</italic>. reported a magnesium aluminum chloride complex (MACC) and showed that this electrolyte, comprising fully inorganic salts, can be used in a magnesium battery<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>. In recent years, it has also been reported that even an electrolyte without a Lewis acid causes magnesium plating/stripping. For example, Mg(TFSI)<sub>2</sub>/triglyme (TFSI&#x02009;=&#x02009;bistriflimide) showed high electrochemical stability toward oxidation and can cause reversible magnesium plating/stripping<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. A carborane-based electrolyte without a Lewis acid was also reported to exhibit high Coulombic efficiency and high anodic stability for SUS and Al electrodes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par5">Magnesium is easily corroded by AlCl<sub>3</sub> solution in thionyl chloride, although this corrosion can be suppressed by a solution of Mg(AlCl<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub> in thionyl chloride<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup>. The Coulombic efficiency of magnesium plating/stripping can be improved by conditioning of the MACC electrolyte in THF<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. Moreover, magnesium plating/stripping occurs even in the monoglyme-MACC electrolyte, the Coulombic efficiency and open circuit potential (OCP) of which differ from those of the same electrolyte in THF<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. The addition of MgCl<sub>2</sub> to Mg(TFSI)<sub>2</sub> in 1,2-dimethoxyethane significantly improved the electrochemical performance in terms of reversible magnesium deposition<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. In this case, PF<sub>6</sub><sup>&#x02013;</sup> anions passivate the Mg anodes, although reversible Mg deposition/dissolution commence via the addition of either MgCl<sub>2</sub> or LiCl<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. However, it is not yet known which of these electrolytes affect the deposition/dissolution of magnesium and anodic stability.</p><p id="Par6">The development of magnesium batteries requires magnesium electrolytes to show high anodic stability, be safe and easy to handle, and allow reversible magnesium plating and stripping. From the viewpoint of safety, it is desirable for the magnesium electrolyte to contain species that impart low flammability, low reactivity with ambient air, and other such properties<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. In addition, previous reports suggest that electrolytes containing an inorganic anion show higher anodic stability than those containing alkyl or alkoxide anions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. Therefore, this study examined magnesium salts with an inorganic anion, borate, as magnesium electrolytes. Three novel magnesium salts, Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl, Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, in triglyme and AlCl<sub>3</sub> solvents were synthesized and investigated by cyclic voltammetry (CV) and linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). In addition to electrochemical performance, chemical stability was discussed on the basis of nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) measurements. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte, which showed high anodic stability, was further studied by NMR spectroscopy, Fourier-transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy, and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS).</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Experimental Section</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Preparation of electrolytes</title><p id="Par7">The magnesium salts, Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl, Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, were prepared by reacting benzophenone, triphenylsilanol, and boric acid, respectively, with a Grignard reagent. The schematic synthetic routes of the magnesium salts used in this study are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. The detailed procedures are described in the Supporting Information. <sup>1</sup>H NMR measurements confirmed the disappearance of the O&#x02013;H proton of the reactant. Titration indicated that the ratio of magnesium and chlorine coordinated to THF was Mg:Cl = 1:1 for all magnesium salts. In an argon-filled glove box, each magnesium salt in triglyme was heated at 40&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. Aluminum chloride was added, and the reaction mixture was stirred and then cooled to room temperature. The preparation conditions are shown in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref>.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Schematic synthetic routes of various magnesium salts used in this study.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e588"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Characterization</title><p id="Par8"><sup>1</sup>H, <sup>11</sup>B, and <sup>27</sup>Al NMR spectra were recorded on a Fourier-transform NMR spectrometer (400&#x02009;MHz, JMN-ECS400, JEOL). The <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectrum of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> was measured using a filtered solution of the sample in DMSO-<italic>d</italic><sub>6</sub>. The <sup>27</sup>Al NMR spectra of AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme, B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme, AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF were measured using neat samples. The <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectra of B(OH)<sub>3</sub> and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> were measured using samples dissolved in CD<sub>3</sub>OD/CD<sub>3</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>D mixed solvent (50/50&#x02009;vol%). The <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectrum of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme was measured using a sample diluted with THF-<italic>d</italic><sub>8</sub>. Attenuated total reflection FTIR spectroscopy was performed using a Fourier-transform infrared spectrometer (Nicolet 380, Thermo Scientific). Powder X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns were measured in the range of 2<italic>&#x003b8;</italic> = 5&#x02013;50 &#x000b0; using a powder X-ray diffractometer (Miniflex 600, Rigaku) operated at a 40&#x02009;kV voltage and 15&#x02009;mA current using Cu K&#x003b1; radiation (&#x003bb;&#x02009;=&#x02009;1.5406&#x02009;&#x000c5;). XAS measurements of the liquid electrolyte were performed at beamline BL-10 of the SR Center of Ritsumeikan University (Japan). A home-made measurement cell, where the electrolytes are separated from vacuum by a silicon nitride window, was used<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. Mg and Al <italic>K</italic>-edge XAS spectra were measured in fluorescence mode using a silicon drift detector.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Electrochemical measurements</title><p id="Par9">CV and LSV were performed in an argon-filled glovebox (&#x0003c;0.1 ppm each of water and oxygen) using an electrochemical measurement system (VMP3, Bio-Logic Science Instruments). CV measurements were conducted within the potential range of &#x02212;1.0 to 3.5&#x02009;V vs. Mg at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s using a three-electrode cell. This cell has Pt (diameter (<italic>&#x003c6;</italic>): 3.0&#x02009;mm, disk, BAS Co., Ltd.), Mg (<italic>&#x003c6;</italic>: 1.6&#x02009;mm, rod, 99.95%, Nilaco Co., Ltd.), and Mg (<italic>&#x003c6;</italic>: 1.6&#x02009;mm, rod, 99.95%, Nilaco Co., Ltd.) as the working, reference, and counter electrodes, respectively, immersed in 2&#x02009;mL of electrolyte. LSV measurements were conducted within the potential range of OCP to 3.5&#x02009;V vs. Mg at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s using the same cell, but with various working electrodes. These working electrodes include Pt (<italic>&#x003c6;</italic>: 3.0&#x02009;mm, disk, BAS Co., Ltd.), glassy carbon (GC; <italic>&#x003c6;</italic>: 3.0&#x02009;mm, disk, BAS Co., Ltd.), Al (thickness: 0.1&#x02009;mm, plate, 99.999%, Nilaco Co., Ltd.), SUS304 (thickness: 0.2&#x02009;mm, plate, Nilaco Co., Ltd.), and Mo (<italic>&#x003c6;</italic>: 1.5&#x02009;mm, rod, 99.95%, Nilaco Co., Ltd.).</p><p id="Par10">The galvanostatic deposition of magnesium was carried out in a three-electrode cell under a current density of 1&#x02009;mA/cm<sup>2</sup> applied to the Pt working electrode for 50&#x02009;h. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) was performed using a field emission scanning electron microscope (S-4800, Hitachi, Ltd.) to observe the precipitate on the electrode. Synchrotron XRD measurements of plated magnesium were performed at beamline BL5S2 of the Aichi Synchrotron Radiation Center (Japan). A glass capillary with an outer diameter of 0.3&#x02009;mm was filled with the sample and sealed by a resin in an argon-filled glove box. XRD data were collected using a Debye-Scherrer optical system with a two-dimensional semiconductor detector (PILATUS 100&#x02009;K, Dectris). The wavelength of the X-ray was calibrated to <italic>&#x003bb;</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0.6995&#x02009;&#x000c5;.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Battery testing</title><p id="Par11">Cu<sub>2</sub>Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>7.8</sub> was purchased from Nippon Inorganic Colour &#x00026; Chemical Co., Ltd. Hydrochloric acid and ultrapure water were purchased from FUJIFILM Wako Pure Chemical Corporation and used as received. Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub> Chevrel phase, the active material, was prepared by chemical leaching of Cu<sub>2</sub>Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>7.8</sub> in HCl/H<sub>2</sub>O with oxygen bubbling. The electrode slurry consisted of 80&#x02009;wt% active material, 10&#x02009;wt% acetylene black (DENKA BLACK, Denka Co., Ltd.), and 10&#x02009;wt% polyvinylidene fluoride (KF Polymer L#7305, Kureha Corporation) dissolved in 1-methyl-2-pyrrolidone using a planetary ball mill. The slurry was coated onto carbon paper, which served as the current collector, and dried under vacuum at 80&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 1&#x02009;h and subsequently at 120&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 5&#x02009;h. It was reported that carbon electrode is stable during magnesium charge-discharge<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. The resulting sheet, along with those of AZ31 (thickness: 0.5&#x02009;mm, Izumi Metal Corporation) and glass fiber filter (GA100, Advantec), were cut into disks 16&#x02009;mm in diameter to form the cathode, anode, and separator, respectively. The test cell was prepared by laminating the cathode, separator, and AZ31 anode on a CR2032 coin-type cell (Hohsen Corp.), which was then filled with electrolyte. Galvanostatic charge-discharge tests were carried out at a constant current of C/50 rate and temperature of 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C using a charge/discharge unit (ABE 1024-05R1, Electrofield). The experimental conditions were based on the theoretical capacity of Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub> (128 mAh/g) in the range of 0.5&#x02013;1.9&#x02009;V vs. Mg at 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec7" sec-type="results"><title>Results and Discussion</title><p id="Par12">We first examined the electrochemical behaviors of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-, Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(a)</xref> displays the cyclic voltammograms of the electrolytes, prepared by mixing a magnesium salt with AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme, at the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle. They show reversible cathodic and anodic currents with Mg plating and stripping at 0&#x02009;V vs. Mg. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte shows the highest reversible current density for Mg plating and stripping. The cyclic voltammograms of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl- and Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolytes, consisting of magnesium salts of similar structure, exhibit similar shapes with almost the same current densities. The Coulombic efficiencies are 75.7%, 81.5%, and 64.0% for the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-, Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes, respectively. The three electrolytes have different anodic stabilities. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(b)</xref> displays the linear sweep voltammograms of the electrolytes. The linear sweep voltammogram of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte shows anodic stability close to approximately 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg. On the other hand, for the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte, a weak oxidation current is observed at 2.6&#x02009;V, and the anodic current increases at about 3.0&#x02009;V, which is close to the decomposition potential of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte. Comparison of the linear sweep voltammograms of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl- and Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolytes shows that the central element influences anodic stability. Among these electrolytes, the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte shows the highest anodic stability over 3.0&#x02009;V. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte also exhibits long-term stability. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(c)</xref> shows the cyclic voltammograms of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl- and Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolytes measured three weeks after the first measurement in the presence of 0.1 ppm each of H<sub>2</sub>O and O<sub>2</sub> in an argon-filled glove box. The Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte shows no current associated with magnesium plating/striping, while the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte shows almost the same CV curve even after three weeks.<fig id="Fig2"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) Cyclic voltammograms of Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl- (blue), Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl- (red), and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based (green) electrolytes at the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle. Measurements were taken at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s at 20&#x02009;&#x000b0;C using Pt, Mg, and Mg as the working, reference, and counter electrodes, respectively, in a three-electrode cell. (<bold>b</bold>) Linear sweep voltammograms of Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl- (blue), Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl- (red), and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based (green) electrolytes at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s at 20&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. (<bold>c</bold>) Cyclic voltammograms at the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle measured at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s at 20&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. The blue and red curves represent the first measurement and measurement after three weeks, respectively, for the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte. The green and purple curves represent the first measurement and measurement after three weeks, respectively, for the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte. (<bold>d</bold>) <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte as prepared (blue) and three weeks after preparation (red) and Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte as prepared (green) and three weeks after preparation (purple).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e907"/></fig></p><p id="Par13">The difference in stability is related to the chemical structures of the electrolytes. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(d)</xref> shows the <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl- and Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolytes as prepared and after three weeks. The <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectrum of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte from 7.20 to 7.35 ppm changes between after preparation (blue) and after three weeks (red), which suggests the structural change of the Ph<sub>3</sub>CO<sup>&#x02013;</sup> anion during preservation in the glove box. This chemical instability is hypothesized to be the cause of the change in the cyclic voltammogram of the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(c)</xref>. On the other hand, the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte shows almost the same <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectrum as prepared (green) and after three weeks (purple), which indicates that the initial structure of the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiO<sup>&#x02013;</sup> anion is maintained. Although the difference between the magnesium salts used in the electrolytes is only a single element, the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte shows lower anodic stability and higher chemical stability compared with the Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte. The shape of the CV curve of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte is nearly the same even after three weeks, which suggests the chemical stability of the BO<sub>3</sub><sup>3&#x02212;</sup> anion structure (Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref> in the Supporting Information). Chemical stability may be related to the strengths of the Si&#x02013;O, B&#x02013;O, and C&#x02013;O bonds.</p><p id="Par14">Density functional theory calculations suggest that chemical stability is related to the strength of C&#x02013;O, Si&#x02013;O, and B&#x02013;O bonds of anions determined using the hard and soft acids and bases principle (Supporting Information), further implying that the C&#x02013;O bond of Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolytes can be weakened by Ph substitution (Supporting Information). Moreover, according to previous reports, the Lewis acidic character of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> may enhance the anodic stability of the electrolyte<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref></sup>. Interestingly, elemental differences in the structure can change electrolyte properties, such as anodic stability and chemical stability. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte shows both excellent anodic stability and chemical stability despite its low Coulombic efficiency. Therefore, we will discuss this electrolyte in more detail.</p><p id="Par15">The cyclic voltammograms of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme and triglyme-THF are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(a,b)</xref>, respectively. Cathodic and anodic currents around 0&#x02009;V vs. Mg appear repeatedly in each cycle, which suggests that magnesium metal reversibly plates and strips on Pt within the CV measurement range. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme shows an overpotential of approximately 570&#x02009;mV at 1.0&#x02009;mA/cm<sup>2</sup>. Coulombic efficiency improves from 38.2% at the first cycle to 57.6% at the 30<sup>th</sup> cycle. However, it is 64.0% even at the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle, which indicates that the Coulombic efficiency of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme is not improved by the conditioning process as previously reported<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(b)</xref>, the use of a triglyme-THF mixed solvent results in improved current density, probably because THF has a lower viscosity than triglyme<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. The overpotential of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme-THF is approximately 490&#x02009;mV at 1.0&#x02009;mA/cm<sup>2</sup>. The conductivity of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte at 27&#x02009;&#x000b0;C improves from 2.15 mS/cm without THF to 3.8 mS/cm with THF. Thus, the current density is enhanced by adding THF. The Coulombic efficiency of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte increases from 43.4% at the first cycle to 62.8% at the 30<sup>th</sup> cycle. The cycle dependency of Coulombic efficiency is illustrated in Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S2</xref> in the Supporting Information. The origin of the insufficient overvoltage and Coulombic efficiency will be discussed after the characterization of the electrolyte.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Cyclic voltammograms of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in (<bold>a</bold>) triglyme and (<bold>b</bold>) triglyme-THF measured at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s at 20&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. Linear sweep voltammograms of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte with Pt (blue), glassy carbon (red), Mo (green), SUS (light blue), and Al (orange) electrodes in (<bold>c</bold>) triglyme and (<bold>d</bold>) triglyme-THF measured at a scan rate of 5&#x02009;mV/s.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e1083"/></fig></p><p id="Par16">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(c,d)</xref> show the linear sweep voltammograms of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme and triglyme-THF, respectively. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme shows anodic stability over 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg using Pt and GC. However, its anodic stability decreases to 1.6&#x02009;V using Al and 2.0&#x02009;V using SUS. This behavior is also observed in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF electrolyte. The trend in the anodic stability of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte is Al &#x0003c; SUS&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;Pt, GC regardless of the solvent. The same trend is observed in bisamide- and dialkoxide-based electrolytes, which indicates that Cl<sup>&#x02013;</sup> has an oxidatively unfavorable effect on Al and SUS<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup>. Using Mo, the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme shows an anodic stability of about 3.0&#x02009;V, while the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme-THF shows a weak decomposition current from 2.0&#x02009;V and increased current at about 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg. Pt and GC can be used as current collectors with the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte up to 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg, and SUS up to about 2.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg. Mo can be used with the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme up to approximately 3.0&#x02009;V vs. Mg.</p><p id="Par17">We confirmed that the plated product is Mg metal without dendritic formation. SEM images of plated magnesium from the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme and triglyme-THF on Pt are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(a,b)</xref>, respectively. The SEM images show that the magnesium from the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes in different solvents appears to co-exist with a few grain-like particles and flat surface. The products from either electrolyte do not show dendritic morphology. The magnesium deposited from both electrolytes does not have a well-defined crystal morphology, and its grain size appears to be smaller than 2 &#x003bc;m. The crystalline edges are not clear, probably caused by the long-term reduction during sample preparation. Density functional theory calculations revealed the cathodic instability of Mg-coordinated glyme electrolytes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>. The long-term reduction causes partial decomposition of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte, resulting in the mossy structure observed in the SEM images. Synchrotron radiation XRD measurement confirmed that the precipitate is magnesium, as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(c)</xref>. Both XRD patterns for the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes with/without THF show the peaks at the same position as those of the reference for Mg, although the scattering pattern in the (002) plane at 2&#x003b8;&#x02009;=&#x02009;15.4&#x000b0; is slightly smaller. Previous reports suggest that a small reflection of the (002) plane for magnesium represents a small grain size<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>. Plated magnesium can become polycrystalline depending on the precipitation conditions, and the change appears in the (002) plane, which is the close-packed surface of the magnesium crystal<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>. The small grain size of plated magnesium from the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes is considered to be caused by the influence of such polycrystallization.<fig id="Fig4"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>SEM images of electrodeposited Mg from the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in (<bold>a</bold>) triglyme and (<bold>b</bold>) triglyme-THF on a Pt electrode. (<bold>c</bold>) Synchrotron radiation XRD patterns of electrodeposited Mg from the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme (black) and triglyme-THF (red) compared with that of reference Mg (gray).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e1189"/></fig></p><p id="Par18">Although Mg plating and stripping with high anodic stability is observed, the Coulombic efficiency is approximately 60% at the 100<sup>th</sup> cycle. We will discuss the possibility of this Coulombic efficiency considering the chemical structure of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes inferred from FTIR, NMR, and X-ray absorption fine structure (XAFS) analyses. First, we rule out the possibility of residual B(OH)<sub>3</sub>. FTIR measurements of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> product, B(OH)<sub>3</sub> reactant, and THF solvent are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5(a)</xref>. While the absorption related to the <italic>&#x003b3;</italic><sub>O&#x02013;H</sub> peak of B(OH)<sub>3</sub> (red) at about 3200&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> is not observed in the spectrum of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, absorptions with similar shape to those of THF (green) are observed in the range of 800&#x02013;1100 and 2800&#x02013;3100&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. The absorption at the latter is attributed to the <italic>&#x003bd;</italic><sub>C&#x02013;H</sub> of THF and those at 877 and 1026&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> are attributed to the red-shifts of <italic>&#x003b4;</italic><sub>C&#x02013;C&#x02013;O</sub> (905&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>) and <italic>&#x003b3;</italic><sub>C&#x02013;O</sub> (1065&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) of THF, respectively<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref></sup>. These results imply the consumption of the B(OH)<sub>3</sub> reactant, which is also supported by the absence of the associated peak in the XRD pattern of the synthesized B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5(b)</xref>. The absence of diffraction peaks suggests that the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> salt has a disordered molecular arrangement and no other magnesium salt such as MgCl<sub>2</sub> is formed. The <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> and B(OH)<sub>3</sub> dissolved in DMSO-<italic>d</italic><sub>6</sub> are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5(c)</xref>. The broad O&#x02013;H peak at 5.8 ppm detected in B(OH)<sub>3</sub> is not observed in B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, which further proves that B(OH)<sub>3</sub> is completely consumed in the reaction, as implied by the FTIR and XRD results. The new peaks observed at 1.76 and 3.59 ppm indicate that THF remains in the synthesized magnesium salt<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref></sup>, which is also consistent with the FTIR results showing the coordination of THF to the magnesium salt.<fig id="Fig5"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) Comparison of the FTIR transmittance spectra of B(OH)<sub>3</sub> (red), B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> (blue), and THF (green) from 400 to 3800&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. (<bold>b</bold>) Powder XRD pattern of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. (<bold>c</bold>) <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> filtrate with DMSO-<italic>d</italic><sub>6</sub> (blue) and B(OH)<sub>3</sub> dissolved in DMSO-<italic>d</italic><sub>6</sub> (red). (<bold>d</bold>) <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectra of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> (blue) and B(OH)<sub>3</sub> (red) dissolved in CD<sub>3</sub>OD/CD<sub>3</sub>CO<sub>2</sub>D (50/50&#x02009;vol%).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig5_HTML" id="d29e1381"/></fig></p><p id="Par19">Although the B(OH)<sub>3</sub> itself no longer remains, the presence of the BO<sub>3</sub><sup>3&#x02212;</sup> unit is confirmed by the <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectra of B(OH)<sub>3</sub> and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, which were both dissolved in CD<sub>3</sub>OD/CD<sub>3</sub>CO<sub>2</sub>D (50/50&#x02009;vol%) (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5(d)</xref>). The main peak in the <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectrum of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> is located at around 19 ppm, which is almost the same as that of B(OH)<sub>3</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup>. The presence of this peak indicates that the BO<sub>3</sub><sup>3&#x02212;</sup> unit remains in the structure of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. The origin of the other peaks (around 2 and 32.4 ppm) are unknown at present. However, these peaks are unrelated to the solvents used for the measurement (CD<sub>3</sub>OD and CD<sub>3</sub>CO<sub>2</sub>D) because they are also detected in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes described later.</p><p id="Par20">B(OH)<sub>3</sub> is not detected in the FTIR, XRD, and <sup>1</sup>H NMR measurements, and the BO<sub>3</sub><sup>3&#x02212;</sup> unit remains in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> salt according to the <sup>11</sup>B NMR measurement. Moreover, the molar ratio of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, measured by inductively coupled plasma-atomic emission spectroscopy and Cl titration, is B:Mg:Cl = 1:3:3. These results indicate that the Grignard reagent mainly reacts with B(OH)<sub>3</sub> as a Br&#x000f8;nsted acid to form B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> does not show the ordered arrangement and disproportionated structures observed in the XRD measurement. In addition, the FTIR and <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra suggest that THF is coordinated to B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. Based on these results, the synthesized B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> salt has the structure shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6(a)</xref>, in which THF is coordinated to B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>, and a more complicated structure with a disordered network (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6(b)</xref>).<fig id="Fig6"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Plausible structures of the product from boric acid and ethylmagnesium chloride.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig6_HTML" id="d29e1507"/></fig></p><p id="Par21">Subsequently, we investigated the Al-coordinated state in B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes by <sup>27</sup>Al and <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectroscopy. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7(a)</xref> shows the <sup>27</sup>Al NMR spectra of AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme, B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme, AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF measured as neat samples. The peaks in the <sup>27</sup>Al NMR spectra of both AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme (blue) and AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF (green) without B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> are observed at approximately 106, 62&#x02013;68, and 27 ppm. On the basis of literature data, the peak at 106 ppm is assigned to the tetrahedral Al species including AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>-</sup> and that at 62&#x02013;68 ppm to the ether-coordinated AlCl<sub>3</sub> species<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>. The peak at approximately 27 ppm is assigned to a positive species, such as glyme-coordinated AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref></sup>. AlCl<sub>3</sub> ionization is expected to occur in triglyme because the dissociation of AlCl<sub>3</sub> in glyme solvents has been observed, as shown in Eq. (<xref rid="Equ1" ref-type="">1</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>:<disp-formula id="Equ1"><label>1</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$2{{\rm{A}}{\rm{l}}{\rm{C}}{\rm{l}}}_{3}\leftrightarrows {{\rm{A}}{\rm{l}}{\rm{C}}{\rm{l}}}_{2}^{+}+{{\rm{A}}{\rm{l}}{\rm{C}}{\rm{l}}}_{4}^{-}.$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M2" display="block"><mml:mn>2</mml:mn><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">A</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">C</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>3</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x021c6;</mml:mo><mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">A</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">C</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>+</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">A</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">C</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>4</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup><mml:mo>.</mml:mo></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Article_Equ1.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula><fig id="Fig7"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) <sup>27</sup>Al NMR spectra of AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme (blue), B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme (red), AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme-THF (50/50&#x02009;vol%) (green), and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme-THF (50:50&#x02009;vol%) (purple). The concentrations of AlCl<sub>3</sub> and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> in all electrolyte solutions are 1.2 and 0.2&#x02009;M, respectively. (<bold>b</bold>) <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectra of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> in CD<sub>3</sub>OD/CD<sub>3</sub>CO<sub>2</sub>D (50/50&#x02009;vol%) (blue) and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme with THF-<italic>d</italic><sub>8</sub> (red).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig7_HTML" id="d29e1739"/></fig></p><p id="Par22">In addition, AlCl<sub>3</sub> is known to dissociate easily in glyme, but not in THF<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>. Equation (<xref rid="Equ1" ref-type="">1</xref>) is deduced to shift to the left to form AlCl<sub>3</sub> species (62&#x02013;68 ppm) in triglyme-THF and to the right to form AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> species (27 ppm) in triglyme solution without THF. On the other hand, approximately one peak at about 106 ppm is observed for both B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF, which are electrolytes containing magnesium salt. The reduced peaks of pentacoordinated AlCl<sub>3</sub> (62&#x02013;68 ppm) and AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> (27 ppm) in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte suggest that these species are bound to the borate anion.</p><p id="Par23">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7(b)</xref> displays the <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectra of a B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme sample diluted with THF-<italic>d</italic><sub>8</sub> and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> sample dissolved in CD<sub>3</sub>OD/CD<sub>3</sub>CO<sub>2</sub>D (50:50&#x02009;vol%). The <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectrum of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme electrolyte shows an increase in the intensity of the broad peak at around 6 ppm with a decrease in the intensity of the peak at approximately 19 ppm compared with those in the <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectrum of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. This suggests that the former peak is due to the BO<sub>3</sub><sup>3&#x02013;</sup> species. Furthermore, these changes in the peak intensities suggest the possibility of rapid exchange of coordination of the borate anion to solvents, Cl<sup>&#x02013;</sup>, and Al species, among others.</p><p id="Par24">The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes were further characterized in terms of electronic and local structures. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8(a)</xref> shows the Mg <italic>K</italic>-edge X-ray absorption near edge structure (XANES) spectra of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes in triglyme and triglyme-THF. The two main peaks are observed at ~1309 and ~1312&#x02009;eV with a shoulder at around 1315&#x02009;eV. The peak at approximately 1309&#x02009;eV is attributed to either [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>2</sub>]<sup>2+</sup>
<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref></sup> or [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>3</sub>]<sup>+</sup> species<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref></sup>. The position of the main edge at 1312&#x02013;1315&#x02009;eV is related to the hexacoordinated solvated structure<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref></sup>. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8(b)</xref> shows the Fourier transform of the Mg <italic>K</italic>-edge extended X-ray absorption fine structure (EXAFS) oscillation of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in triglyme. The Fourier transform for this electrolyte is closest to those for Mg(ClO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>/H<sub>2</sub>O<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref></sup> and [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>3</sub>&#x000b7;6(THF)]<sup>+</sup> under applied voltage on the Mg electrode<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref></sup>. The peak at around 1.8&#x02009;&#x000c5; is expected to contain information about the Mg&#x02013;O pair. On the other hand, it is unclear whether the peak at 2.6&#x02009;&#x000c5; is the scattering peak of the Mg&#x02013;Mg pair or the peak due to the Mg&#x02013;Cl pair weakened by triglyme. However, the main edge at 1312&#x02013;1315&#x02009;eV in the XANES spectrum and the large peak at 2.6&#x02009;&#x000c5; in the EXAFS spectrum indicate that the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes include more electrochemically positive Mg ion than [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>3</sub>]<sup>+</sup>.<fig id="Fig8"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) Mg <italic>K</italic>-edge XANES spectra of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme (black) and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme-THF (red) and (<bold>b</bold>) Fourier transform of the EXAFS function of the former. (<bold>c</bold>) Al <italic>K</italic>-edge XANES spectra of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme (black), B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme-THF (red), AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme (blue), and AlCl<sub>3</sub> in triglyme-THF (pink).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig8_HTML" id="d29e1995"/></fig></p><p id="Par25">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8(c)</xref> represents the Al <italic>K</italic>-edge XANES spectra of the four electrolytes, which are AlCl<sub>3</sub> with or without B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> dissolved in triglyme or triglyme-THF. Both AlCl<sub>3</sub> electrolytes without B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> in triglyme (blue) and triglyme-THF (pink) show two edges located at 1565 (with a shoulder at around 1566&#x02009;eV) and 1568&#x02009;eV. The shoulder at 1566&#x02009;eV is smaller and the peak at 1568&#x02009;eV is larger for AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme compared with those for AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF. These results are consistent with those of <sup>27</sup>Al NMR showing a smaller peak at 62&#x02013;68 ppm (due to AlCl<sub>3</sub> species) and larger peak at 27 ppm (due to AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> species) for AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme compared with those for AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF. The Al <italic>K</italic>-edge XANES spectra of the AlCl<sub>3</sub> electrolytes with B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> show distinctly different absorption curves from those of the AlCl<sub>3</sub> electrolytes without B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> in both triglyme and triglyme-THF. The increase of the edge at 1565&#x02009;eV with the decrease of both the shoulder at around 1566&#x02009;eV and edge at 1568&#x02009;eV are consistent with the increase of the amount of AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and decrease of the amounts of both AlCl<sub>3</sub> and AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> observed in the <sup>27</sup>Al-NMR measurement. The edge at 1565&#x02009;eV, shoulder at around 1566&#x02009;eV, and edge at 1568&#x02009;eV in the Al <italic>K</italic>-edge XANES spectra are deduced to be related to AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlCl<sub>3</sub>, and AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup>, respectively.</p><p id="Par26">The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes are expected to not cause the corrosive behavior. According to a previous study using MgCl<sub>2</sub>/AlCl<sub>3</sub> electrolytes, the AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> species cause Mg corrosion with Al cementation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup>. However, our <sup>27</sup>Al NMR analysis (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7(a)</xref>) indicated that the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> electrolytes do not contain AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup>. Other detected species were solvated [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>3</sub>]<sup>+</sup>, glyme-solvated Mg<sup>2+</sup>, and AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, which reportedly do not cause corrosions.</p><p id="Par27">The results above provide information on the chemical species in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes, which can explain the origin of the low Coulombic efficiency. In the case of MACC electrolytes, Mg corrosion with Al cementation caused by AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> reduces the Coulombic efficiency<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup>. The Coulombic efficiency gradually improves during the CV cycles, which is related to the presence of Al species<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. However, due to the absence of AlCl<sub>2</sub><sup>+</sup> and no improvement in Coulombic efficiency upon CV cycling in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes, we conclude that the low Coulombic efficiency observed herein is originated by a different mechanism. Energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopic analysis of the plated Mg in this study also detected the presence of Al, which can disturb the Mg stripping. The enlarged CV profiles from Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3(a)</xref> are provided as Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3</xref> in the supporting information, in which the oxidation peaks are not related to Mg stripping but Al stripping. Based on the results of XAFS and NMR, the main species in the electrolytes are solvated [Mg<sub>2</sub>(&#x003bc;-Cl)<sub>3</sub>]<sup>+</sup>, glyme-solvated Mg<sup>2+</sup>, and AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>. The presence of AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> potentially leads to the following chemical equilibrium<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref></sup>:<disp-formula id="Equ2"><label>2</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M3">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$2{{\rm{A}}{\rm{l}}{\rm{C}}{\rm{l}}}_{4}^{-}\leftrightarrows {{\rm{A}}{\rm{l}}}_{2}{{\rm{C}}{\rm{l}}}_{7}^{-}+{{\rm{C}}{\rm{l}}}^{-}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M4" display="block"><mml:mn>2</mml:mn><mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">A</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">C</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>4</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup><mml:mo>&#x021c6;</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">A</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">C</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>7</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msup><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">C</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msup></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Article_Equ2.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula></p><p id="Par28">Compared with conventional MACC electrolytes, the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes contain excess AlCl<sub>3</sub> during preparation (Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref>), which drives the equilibrium to the right, resulting in Al plating on the electrode<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref></sup>:<disp-formula id="Equ3"><label>3</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M5">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$4{{\rm{Al}}}_{2}{{\rm{Cl}}}_{7}^{-}+3{{\rm{e}}}^{-}\to {\rm{Al}}+7{{\rm{AlCl}}}_{4}^{-}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M6" display="block"><mml:mn>4</mml:mn><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Al</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Cl</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>7</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>3</mml:mn><mml:msup><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">e</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:msup><mml:mo>&#x02192;</mml:mo><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">Al</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>7</mml:mn><mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">AlCl</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>4</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Article_Equ3.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula></p><p id="Par29">This trend is supported by the local structural change observed by Al <italic>K</italic>-edge EXAFS, as shown in Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4</xref>. The first neighbor shell of Al in the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes is expanded compared with that of AlCl<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, which shows good agreement with the literature<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref></sup>. However, the <sup>27</sup>Al NMR analysis of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes does not clearly detect the Al<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>7</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> species, which should be observed at 92 ppm. This result implies the low concentration of Al<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>7</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> despite the influence of Al plating. AlCl<sub>3</sub> concentration must be optimized to improve Coulombic efficiency.</p><p id="Par30">We have confirmed the high chemical and long-term stability of the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes and have characterized these electrolytes. Finally, the application of these electrolytes to magnesium rechargeable battery was examined. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig9" ref-type="fig">9(a,b)</xref> represent the galvanostatic charge-discharge profiles of the Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub>/AZ31 coin-type cells with B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF. Both profiles show plateaus at ~1.05 and ~1.20&#x02009;V and reversible charge/discharge cycles at a capacity of approximately 80 mAh/g for 30 cycles. The profile of the cell with the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme-THF electrolyte shows a slightly smaller gap between the charge-discharge plateaus compared with that of the cell with the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme electrolyte. These results verify that, with B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolytes, the charge-discharge cycles are repeated on cells with a Chevrel phase cathode and magnesium anode. This indicates that Mg<sup>2+</sup> insertion/de-insertion into/from the Chevrel phase with Mg plating/stripping proceeds repeatedly. In addition, it also confirms that SUS can be used with a B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte up to 1.9&#x02009;V vs. Mg. The B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-AlCl<sub>3</sub>/triglyme electrolyte can be used in higher-voltage cathodes (up to 2.1&#x02009;V vs. Mg)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref></sup>, implying that this electrolyte is useful for the development of novel cathode materials.<fig id="Fig9"><label>Figure 9</label><caption><p>Galvanostatic charge-discharge profiles of a coin-type cell with Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub> Chevrel phase cathode and AZ31 anode at C/50-rate (based on the mass of Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub>) with the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte in (<bold>a</bold>) triglyme and (<bold>b</bold>) triglyme-THF.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_Fig9_HTML" id="d29e2480"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec8" sec-type="conclusion"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par31">In this study, three novel electrolytes based on Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl, Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl, and B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> were successfully prepared, and the electrochemical properties were investigated. The Ph<sub>3</sub>COMgCl-based electrolyte showed higher anodic stability than the Ph<sub>3</sub>SiOMgCl-based electrolyte, and the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte showed the highest anodic stability among the three electrolytes. Moreover, the latter was chemically stable, which was ascribed to the Lewis acidic character of boron in B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. Analyses of B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub> showed that the Grignard reagent mainly reacted with B(OH)<sub>3</sub> as a Br&#x000f8;nsted acid and revealed that the BO<sub>3</sub><sup>3&#x02212;</sup> unit derived from B(OH)<sub>3</sub> remained in B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>. In addition, the electrochemically positive Mg<sup>2+</sup> ion is the main species present. Charge-discharge measurements performed for the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte, a Mo<sub>6</sub>S<sub>8</sub> Chevrel phase cathode, and an AZ31 anode were indicative of a reversible charge-discharge capacity, suggesting that hardly any side reaction occurred inside SUS cells with the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte at 1.9&#x02009;V. Although the B(OMgCl)<sub>3</sub>-based electrolyte did not show high Coulombic efficiency, it showed high anodic stability and can therefore be used in the development of positive electrodes for magnesium batteries.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec9"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41598_2020_64085_MOESM1_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Supplementary Information.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p>is available for this paper at 10.1038/s41598-020-64085-2.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work was financially supported by Kansai Research Foundation for technology promotion.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>K.S., K.O. and Y.O. designed the research. K.S. performed the electrochemical measurements and DFT calculation and analyzed FTIR, NMR data. G.M. and T.K. prepared the electrolytes. T.Y., K.N. and T.O. performed X-ray absorption spectroscopy measurements. Y.O. analyzed X-ray diffraction and X-ray absorption spectra. All authors discussed and commented on the manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par32">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Muldoon</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Bucur</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name><name><surname>Gregory</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Quest for Nonaqueous Multivalent Secondary Batteries: Magnesium and Beyond</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2014</year><volume>114</volume><fpage>11683</fpage><lpage>11720</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr500049y</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25343313?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25343313</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Sahadeo</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Noked</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Mapping the Challenges of Magnesium Battery</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><year>2016</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>1736</fpage><lpage>1749</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b00384</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 27088555?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27088555</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Rechargeable magnesium battery: Current status and key challenges for the future</article-title><source>Prog. Mater Sci.</source><year>2014</year><volume>66</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>86</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2014.04.001</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Prototype systems for rechargeable magnesium batteries</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2000</year><volume>407</volume><fpage>724</fpage><lpage>727</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/35037553</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 11048714?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11048714</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pour</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Gofer</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Major</surname><given-names>DT</given-names></name><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Structural Analysis of Electrolyte Solutions for Rechargeable Mg Batteries by Stereoscopic Means and DFT Calculations</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2011</year><volume>133</volume><fpage>6270</fpage><lpage>6278</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja1098512</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 21456525?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21456525</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mizrahi</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Electrolyte Solutions with a Wide Electrochemical Window for Rechargeable Magnesium Batteries</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2008</year><volume>155</volume><fpage>A103</fpage><lpage>A109</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.2806175</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Weissman</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Gofer</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Levi</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Nonaqueous magnesium electrochemistry and its application in secondary batteries</article-title><source>The Chemical Record</source><year>2003</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>61</fpage><lpage>73</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/tcr.10051</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 12552532?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12552532</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wall</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao-Karger</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Fichtner</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Corrosion Resistance of Current Collector Materials in Bisamide Based Electrolyte for Magnesium Batteries</article-title><source>ECS Electrochemistry Letters</source><year>2015</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>C8</fpage><lpage>C10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.0111501eel</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Structure and compatibility of a magnesium electrolyte with a sulphur cathode</article-title><source>Nature Commun.</source><year>2011</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>427</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncomms1435</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21829189</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>EG</given-names></name><name><surname>Kampf</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name><name><surname>Bartlett</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Enhanced oxidative stability of non-Grignard magnesium electrolytes through ligand modification</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><year>2014</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>5193</fpage><lpage>5195</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C3CC47277A</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>F-f</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>Y-s</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Nuli</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirano</surname><given-names>S-i</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A novel electrolyte system without a Grignard reagent for rechargeable magnesium batteries</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><year>2012</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>10763</fpage><lpage>10765</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C2CC35857C</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nist-Lund</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name><surname>Herb</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name><surname>Arnold</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Improving halide-containing magnesium-ion electrolyte performance via sterically hindered alkoxide ligands</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2017</year><volume>362</volume><fpage>308</fpage><lpage>314</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.07.045</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Herb</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name><surname>Nist-Lund</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name><surname>Arnold</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A fluorinated dialkoxide-based magnesium-ion electrolyte</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2017</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>7801</fpage><lpage>7805</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7TA01578J</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Herb</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name><surname>Nist-Lund</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Schwartz</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Arnold</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Structural Effects of Magnesium Dialkoxides as Precursors for Magnesium-Ion Electrolytes</article-title><source>ECS Electrochemistry Letters</source><year>2015</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>A49</fpage><lpage>A52</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.0031506eel</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Highly soluble alkoxide magnesium salts for rechargeable magnesium batteries</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2014</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>581</fpage><lpage>584</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c3ta13691d</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>TB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A facile approach using MgCl2 to formulate high performance Mg2+ electrolytes for rechargeable Mg batteries</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2014</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>3430</fpage><lpage>3438</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c3ta14825d</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Doe</surname><given-names>RE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Novel, electrolyte solutions comprising fully inorganic salts with high anodic stability for rechargeable magnesium batteries</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><year>2014</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>243</fpage><lpage>245</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c3cc47896c</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Orikasa</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High energy density rechargeable magnesium battery using earth-abundant and non-toxic elements</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2014</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>5622</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/Srep05622</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25011939?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25011939</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ha</surname><given-names>S-Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Magnesium(II) Bis(trifluoromethane sulfonyl) Imide-Based Electrolytes with Wide Electrochemical Windows for Rechargeable Magnesium Batteries</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2014</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>4063</fpage><lpage>4073</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/am405619v</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24559269?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24559269</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>New Magnesium-ion Conductive Electrolyte Solution Based on Triglyme for Reversible Magnesium Metal Deposition and Dissolution at Ambient Temperature</article-title><source>Chem. Lett.</source><year>2014</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>1788</fpage><lpage>1790</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1246/cl.140704</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Carter</surname><given-names>TJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Boron Clusters as Highly Stable Magnesium-Battery Electrolytes</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2014</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>3173</fpage><lpage>3177</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201310317</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McArthur</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name><surname>Geng</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Lavallo</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cation reduction and comproportionation as novel strategies to produce high voltage, halide free, carborane based electrolytes for rechargeable Mg batteries</article-title><source>Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers</source><year>2015</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>1101</fpage><lpage>1104</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C5QI00171D</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McArthur</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name><surname>Jay</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Geng</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Lavallo</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Below the 12-vertex: 10-vertex carborane anions as non-corrosive, halide free, electrolytes for rechargeable Mg batteries</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><year>2017</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>4453</fpage><lpage>4456</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7CC01570D</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jay</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Comparative Study of Mg(CB11H12)2 and Mg(TFSI)2 at the Magnesium/Electrolyte Interface</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2019</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>11414</fpage><lpage>11420</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b00037</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 30860349?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30860349</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Peled</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Straze</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The Kinetics of the Magnesium Electrode in Thionyl Chloride Solutions</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>1977</year><volume>124</volume><fpage>1030</fpage><lpage>1035</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.2133474</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>See</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The Interplay of Al and Mg Speciation in Advanced Mg Battery Electrolyte Solutions</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2016</year><volume>138</volume><fpage>328</fpage><lpage>337</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jacs.5b10987</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26636472?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26636472</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barile</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Barile</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name><name><surname>Zavadil</surname><given-names>KR</given-names></name><name><surname>Nuzzo</surname><given-names>RG</given-names></name><name><surname>Gewirth</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrolytic Conditioning of a Magnesium Aluminum Chloride Complex for Reversible Magnesium Deposition</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source><year>2014</year><volume>118</volume><fpage>27623</fpage><lpage>27630</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp506951b</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shterenberg</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of (CF3SO2)2N- (TFSI) Based Electrolyte Solutions for Mg Batteries</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2015</year><volume>162</volume><fpage>A7118</fpage><lpage>A7128</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.0161513jes</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shterenberg</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Salama</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Gofer</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hexafluorophosphate-Based Solutions for Mg Batteries and the Importance of Chlorides</article-title><source>Langmuir</source><year>2017</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>9472</fpage><lpage>9478</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.7b01609</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28651053?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28651053</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mohtadi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Mizuno</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Magnesium batteries: Current state of the art, issues and future perspectives</article-title><source>Beilstein J Nanotechnol</source><year>2014</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>1291</fpage><lpage>1311</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3762/bjnano.5.143</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25247113?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25247113</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nakanishi</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Novel spectro-electrochemical cell for <italic>in situ</italic>/operando observation of common composite electrode with liquid electrolyte by X-ray absorption spectroscopy in the tender X-ray region</article-title><source>Rev. Sci. Instrum.</source><year>2014</year><volume>85</volume><fpage>084103</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4891036</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25173283?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25173283</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Prabakar</surname><given-names>SJR</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Ikhe</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name><name><surname>Sohn</surname><given-names>K-S</given-names></name><name><surname>Pyo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Simultaneous Suppression of Metal Corrosion and Electrolyte Decomposition by Graphene Oxide Protective Coating in Magnesium-Ion Batteries: Toward a 4-V-Wide Potential Window</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2017</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>43767</fpage><lpage>43773</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b16103</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 29179534?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29179534</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>Y-s</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Boron-based electrolyte solutions with wide electrochemical windows for rechargeable magnesium batteries</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2012</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>9100</fpage><lpage>9106</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C2EE22509C</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Electrolyte Solutions for Rechargeable Magnesium Batteries Based on Organomagnesium Chloroaluminate Complexes</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2002</year><volume>149</volume><fpage>A115</fpage><lpage>A121</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.1429925</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jache</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Binder</surname><given-names>JO</given-names></name><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Adelhelm</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A comparative study on the impact of different glymes and their derivatives as electrolyte solvents for graphite co-intercalation electrodes in lithium-ion and sodium-ion batteries</article-title><source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source><year>2016</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>14299</fpage><lpage>14316</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6CP00651E</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 27165175?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27165175</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Das</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Roy</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name><name><surname>Hazra</surname><given-names>DK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Densities and viscosities of the binary aqueous mixtures of tetrahydrofuran and 1,2-dimethoxyethane at 298, 308 and 318&#x02009;K</article-title><source>Indian J. Chem. Technol.</source><year>1994</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>93</fpage><lpage>97</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"> Seguin, T. J., Hahn, N. T., Zavadil, K. R. &#x00026; Persson, K. A. Elucidating Non-aqueous Solvent Stability and Associated Decomposition Mechanisms for Mg Energy Storage Applications From First-Principles. Frontiers in Chemistry 7, 10.3389/fchem.2019.00175 (2019).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kitada</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Room Temperature Magnesium Electrodeposition from Glyme-Coordinated Ammonium Amide Electrolytes</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2015</year><volume>162</volume><fpage>D389</fpage><lpage>D396</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.0731508jes</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Esbenshade</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Improving Electrodeposition of Mg through an Open Circuit Potential Hold</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source><year>2015</year><volume>119</volume><fpage>23366</fpage><lpage>23372</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b07825</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gummow</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Morphology and Preferred Orientation of Pulse Electrodeposited Magnesium</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2010</year><volume>157</volume><fpage>E45</fpage><lpage>E49</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.3298883</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>IT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Characteristics of tetrahydrofuran-based electrolytes with magnesium alkoxide additives for rechargeable magnesium batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2016</year><volume>323</volume><fpage>51</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.05.045</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aurbach</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Turgeman</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Chusid</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name><surname>Gofer</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Spectroelectrochemical studies of magnesium deposition by <italic>in situ</italic> FTIR spectroscopy</article-title><source>Electrochem. Commun.</source><year>2001</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>252</fpage><lpage>261</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S1388-2481(01)00148-5</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fulmer</surname><given-names>GR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>NMR Chemical Shifts of Trace Impurities: Common Laboratory Solvents, Organics, and Gases in Deuterated Solvents Relevant to the Organometallic Chemist</article-title><source>Organometallics</source><year>2010</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>2176</fpage><lpage>2179</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/om100106e</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dewar</surname><given-names>MJS</given-names></name><name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>New heteroaromatic compounds. XXV. Studies of salt formation in boron oxyacids by boron-11 nuclear magnetic resonance</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>1967</year><volume>89</volume><fpage>2408</fpage><lpage>2410</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja00986a029</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>See</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y-M</given-names></name><name><surname>Ha</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Barile</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Gewirth</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of Concentration on the Electrochemistry and Speciation of the Magnesium Aluminum Chloride Complex Electrolyte Solution</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2017</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>35729</fpage><lpage>35739</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b08088</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28933814?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28933814</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Merrill</surname><given-names>LC</given-names></name><name><surname>Schaefer</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrochemical Properties and Speciation in Mg(HMDS)2-Based Electrolytes for Magnesium Batteries as a Function of Ethereal Solvent Type and Temperature</article-title><source>Langmuir</source><year>2017</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>9426</fpage><lpage>9433</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.7b01111</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28636822?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28636822</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kitada</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Fukami</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Murase</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrochemically active species in aluminum electrodeposition baths of AlCl<sub>3</sub>/glyme solutions</article-title><source>Electrochim. Acta</source><year>2016</year><volume>211</volume><fpage>561</fpage><lpage>567</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2016.05.063</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nakayama</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Complex Structures and Electrochemical Properties of Magnesium Electrolytes</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2008</year><volume>155</volume><fpage>A754</fpage><lpage>A759</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.2956022</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Benmayza</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Effect of Electrolytic Properties of a Magnesium Organohaloaluminate Electrolyte on Magnesium Deposition</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source><year>2013</year><volume>117</volume><fpage>26881</fpage><lpage>26888</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp4077068</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hattori</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Role of Coordination Structure of Magnesium Ions on Charge and Discharge Behavior of Magnesium Alloy Electrode</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source><year>2018</year><volume>122</volume><fpage>25204</fpage><lpage>25210</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.8b08558</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bieker</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The Power of Stoichiometry: Conditioning and Speciation of MgCl2/AlCl3 in Tetraethylene Glycol Dimethyl Ether-Based Electrolytes</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2019</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>24057</fpage><lpage>24066</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b05307</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 31199113?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31199113</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nakayama</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Sulfone-based electrolytes for aluminium rechargeable batteries</article-title><source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source><year>2015</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>5758</fpage><lpage>5766</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4CP02183E</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25627398?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25627398</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR53"><label>53.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stafford</surname><given-names>GR</given-names></name><name><surname>Tsuda</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Hussey</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The Structure of Electrodeposited Aluminum Alloys from Chloroaluminate Ionic Liquids: Let&#x02019;s Not Ignore the Temperature</article-title><source>ECS Transactions</source><year>2014</year><volume>64</volume><fpage>535</fpage><lpage>547</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/06404.0535ecst</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR54"><label>54.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sato, K., Mizuta, H. &#x00026; Okamoto, K. Positive Electrode Active Material For Magnesium Batteries. WO2020/027079A1 (2020).</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>