<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par138">All cognitive processes identified the role of experience in the decision-making process, particularly linked directly to cognition and cognitive framing (Hahn et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">2014</xref>), through threat interpretation (Haney, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">2017</xref>) and the scanning/ sensemaking process (Fontana, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2019</xref>). Through this research we may propose that a lack of experience in decision-making on climate change to date may be restricting further decision-making by limiting the cognitive process. The situation, however, is not so simple. Gond et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">2017</xref>) referred to the role of affective process and emotion in CSR evaluations. In our review we found that very few of the articles examining managerial level processes, other than Eberhardt-Toth and Wasieleski (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">2013</xref>) and Zhou et al., (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR96">2018a</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR97">2018b</xref>) who made significant reference to emotion. This lack of inclusion of emotion may indicate a second significant issue preventing meaningful corporate action against climate change. Zollo (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR99">2021</xref>) and Eberhardt-Toth and Wasieleski (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">2013</xref>) discussed the formation of cognition through directed and automatic components. Without an emotional connection, the implicit aspect may be limited leaving individuals to fall back on the purposeful, directed cognitive process. Considering past social responsibility issues such as child labour, which was once seen by some as acceptable, but is now widely rejected, evoking an automatic emotion of disgust we can understand the power of emotion in strong action. The question remains whether action on climate change would be accelerated if damaging activities elicited a stronger negative emotion.
</p>
