<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par140">Reviewing these three issue areas we propose below three potential tipping point situations linked to the issues above that may lead to overcoming managerial inaction on climate change each directed at a different level of intervention.
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par141">
    <bold>
     <italic>Requiring individual managerial level change:</italic>
    </bold>
    <italic> The conceptualisation of "leadership" is altered to the extent that maximising profit without action is personally catastrophic from a social and moral perspective.</italic>
    <disp-quote>
     <p id="Par142">Self-identity and the conceptualisation of what it is to be a leader may provide an avenue to trigger further decision-making. In our review we have seen a recent focus on leadership by Groschl et.al. (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">2019</xref>) and Waddock (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>). Outside academia we have also recently seen leadership called into question on ethical matters through the #BlackLivesMatter campaign. In line with increased links between company valuation and corporate social responsibility, sustainability actions and changes to expected gender and race representation in corporate leadership it is time to also reconsider what is good leadership. Waddock (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>) presented a view of a leader as a shaman. “
      <italic>Traditional shamans typically work on healing individuals or aspects of the community that have fallen sick or are perceived to be dis-eased—out of ease or unharmonious, where cultural mythologies are no longer working well (Dow 1986; Walsh 1989)</italic>.” As we seek to address climate change it seems we need more leaders bearing the traits outlined by Waddock (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2019</xref>).
     </p>
    </disp-quote>
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par143">
    <bold>
     <italic>Requiring organisational level change:</italic>
    </bold>
    <italic> The conceptualisation of what a successful business is altered to the extent that profit without action on climate change is highly socially unacceptable so much so that it is catastrophic from an investor (and therefore business) perspective.</italic>
    <disp-quote>
     <p id="Par144">Fontana (
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">2019</xref>) demonstrated the potential for managers to override financial considerations where social recognition benefits could be achieved. The situation described by Fontana is linked to the particular context of the Bangladesh garment industry, whereas the wider moves to alter the expectations of business require extensive industry and investor led change in expectations. The challenge remains as to how to trigger this change. How can we as a society establish an emotional connection with the natural environment rather than wealth?
     </p>
    </disp-quote>
    <disp-quote>
     <p id="Par145">The process of altering societal norms and institutional logics may be time consuming, however, recent experience with adjustments to the COVID-19 crisis has demonstrated the potential for widespread change on an accelerated basis. Additionally, as change is anticipated, but not yet enacted, sectorial stakeholder groups work to develop opinions on possible policy options (Buysse &amp; Verbeke, 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">2003</xref>; Clark &amp; Crawford, 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">2012</xref>; Martin &amp; Rice, 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">2010</xref>) potentially changing institutional logics in advance of policy enactment. The process of developing progressive policy, not just the policy itself, can have positive impacts on achieving cognitive reform.
     </p>
    </disp-quote>
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>3.</label>
   <p id="Par146">
    <bold>
     <italic>Requiring societal level change:</italic>
    </bold>
    <italic> The standard parameters which measure and lead to business success are altered to the extent that action is inevitable (e.g. through pricing carbon, divestment, or new technology).</italic>
    <disp-quote>
     <p id="Par147">Altering the standard parameters and increasing transparency on an organisations impact and activities will force action to be taken even by conservative organisations. Action shapes cognition with cognitive progress developed through experiential engagement in the management of climate change issues, including reporting and stakeholder engagement programs. With frame complexity linked to prior experience, successful solutions will likely be perceived as less risky to the managers involved with sustainability programs resulting in increased positivity regarding outcomes (Hahn et al., 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">2014</xref>). Engaging in these activities will naturally orient the cognitive process towards future action. The parameter adjustment may occur through government action to introduce a price on carbon or support clean-tech innovation. There is an established relationship between regulatory environmental reform and greater levels of environmental engagement (Dahlman &amp; Brammer, 
      <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">2011</xref>). It can also be supported by initiatives such as the Task Force on Climate-Related Financial Disclosures (TCFD).
     </p>
    </disp-quote>
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
