<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Several approaches have been proposed to overcome the volume expansion issue. One is to reduce the size of the Sn-based materials, i.e., construction of nanostructures. For instance, a 3D nanocomposite consisted of 3D structured Sn scaffold and a hollow Sn sphere was fabricated as the LIBs anode [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. The anode exhibited a capacity of 1700 mA h cm
 <sup>−3</sup> for over 200 cycles at 0.5 C. The high cycling stability could be attributed to the 3D nanostructured design that accommodated the volume expansion during charge/discharge [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Another effective approach is to construct Sn/carbon or Sn/metal composite, in which the carbon substrate or metal can act as the buffer to bear the volume change of Sn. Wang’s group designed a mesoporous carbon/Sn anode for Li-ion and Na-ion batteries, in which the mesoporous carbon was proposed to accommodate the volume change of Sn nanoparticles during ion insertion and extraction [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. A Sn/graphite anode presented improved capacity retention with only 0.7% loss per cycle [
 <xref rid="B13-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Nanocable-like Sn-core/carbon-sheath anode materials have been fabricated by chemical vapor deposition, delivering a specific capacity of 630 mA h g
 <sup>−1</sup> after 100 cycles at a current density of 100 mA g
 <sup>−1</sup> [
 <xref rid="B14-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. In addition, graphene-confined Sn nanosheets and 3D hierarchical SnO
 <sub>2</sub>/graphene frameworks were designed, showing enhanced lithium storage capability [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Liu et al. reported a 3D nanocomposite including both a 3D structured Sn scaffold and a hollow Sn sphere within each cavity where all the free Sn surfaces are coated with carbon, showing a high volumetric capacity of ∼1700 mA h cm
 <sup>−3</sup> over 200 cycles at 0.5 C, and a capacity greater than 1200 mA h cm
 <sup>−3</sup> at 10 C [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Combining Sn with metals could form intermetallic compounds and the metal could also act as the buffer to accommodate the volume expansion [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. A Ni
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>2</sub> microcage showed stable capacity of 534 mA h g
 <sup>−1</sup> after 1000 cycles at the current density of 1 C [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Single-crystalline FeSn
 <sub>2</sub> nanospheres with uniform small particle size have been synthesized, showing better electrochemical performances than other nano-spherical intermetallic compounds such as Cu
 <sub>6</sub>Sn
 <sub>5</sub>, CoSn
 <sub>3</sub> and Ni
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>4</sub>, due to its crystal structure [
 <xref rid="B18-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. In addition, Sn-Co alloy nanoparticles encapsulated in a porous 3D graphene network was also applied as the LIB anode [
 <xref rid="B19-materials-14-04348" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>].
</p>
