<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Climate change is likely to have severe impacts on the abundance, distribution, and seasonal timing of pests and their natural enemies, which will alter the degree of success of biological control programs [
 <xref rid="B69-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">69</xref>]. Phytophagous insect species are naturally controlled by top-down (natural enemies) and bottom-up (host plant availability and quality) mechanisms. These natural mechanisms interact to influence insect population dynamics, performance, and behaviour [
 <xref rid="B159-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">159</xref>]. In agricultural, forestry and other ecosystems, phytophagous insects can be considered as cornerstones of the tri-trophic host plant–insect pest–natural enemy relationship [
 <xref rid="B160-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">160</xref>]. The effects of climate change on interactions between insect pests and natural enemies, whether natural enemies are intentionally introduced to new regions or whether they are native and biological control is supported by conservation measures, are modulated by direct effects on the metabolism and physiology of the organisms involved, the responses of those organisms, and subsequent tri-trophic interactions. These interactions are affected by climate change in a variety of ways. Temperature changes can affect the biology of each component species of a system differently, destabilizing their population dynamics [
 <xref rid="B60-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] and causing temporal desynchronization. Natural enemies, which are the third trophic level, are expected to be significantly affected by climate change [
 <xref rid="B161-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">161</xref>]. If trophically connected species respond variously to climate change, the trophic interaction between them could be perturbed, resulting in decoupling of the synchronized dynamics between insect pests and their natural enemies and potentially negatively affecting the performance of biological control [
 <xref rid="B162-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">162</xref>].
</p>
