<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Therefore, the overall competence of a given species under elevated CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentrations is positively or negatively affected depending on its life history traits [
 <xref rid="B166-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">166</xref>]. Dyer et al. [
 <xref rid="B167-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">167</xref>] found that elevated temperature and CO
 <sub>2</sub> reduced the nutritional properties of alfalfa plants, (
 <italic>Medicago sativa</italic> L.), which are the host plants of the Beet armyworm (
 <italic>Spodoptera exigua</italic> Hubner). This type of reduced nutritional quality of the host plants resulted in a shortened development time of the larvae of 
 <italic>S. exigua</italic>. At the same time, larvae of its natural enemy, the parasitic wasp (
 <italic>Cotesia marginiventris</italic> Cresson) were unable to fully develop, leading to the extinction of the local population of 
 <italic>C. marginiventris</italic>. Few studies have addressed how increased CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration affects predator efficiency. The family of ladybirds (Coccinelidae) is the largest insect group of predatory natural enemies. Chen et al. [
 <xref rid="B166-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">166</xref>,
 <xref rid="B168-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">168</xref>] investigated the food preference of the Asian ladybird (
 <italic>Harmonia axyridis</italic> Pallas) in food choice experiments. They showed that 
 <italic>H. axyridis</italic> preferentially preyed on aphids under elevated CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration compared to ambient CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentration. Despite this preference, predation performance was not affected by high CO
 <sub>2</sub> concentrations. Eventually, the time required for larval development of 
 <italic>H. axydiris</italic> was significantly shorter or remained unchanged under altered CO
 <sub>2</sub> conditions [
 <xref rid="B166-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">166</xref>,
 <xref rid="B168-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">168</xref>].
</p>
