<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The precursor of carbon xerogel (CXG) was prepared by polycondensation of resorcinol (Sigma-Aldrich, Taufkirchen, Germany) with formaldehyde (Sigma-Aldrich, Taufkirchen, Germany). After pH adjustment to produce a mesoporous structure, gelation was completed after 3 days at 85 °C in a paraffin bath. The sample was then dried (4 days in an oven at a temperature of 60–120 °C, increasing temperature by 20 °C per day) and carbonisation was performed by heating the material to 150, 400, 600, and 800 °C. Each temperature was kept for 1–6 h to result in CXG. The detailed procedure is described in previous work [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-01805" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-nanomaterials-10-01805" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. Multi-walled CNTs (NANOCYL, NC3100 series, Nanocyl, Sambreville, Belgium) were pre-treated with hydrochloric acid (HCl) (Sigma-Aldrich, Taufkirchen, Germany) [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-01805" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. The Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C electrocatalyst (Sigma-Aldrich, Taufkirchen, Germany) was supported on CXG and CNTs following a modified incipient wetness impregnation method [
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-10-01805" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-01805" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Namely, an aqueous solution of ammonium molybdate (0.788 g in 6 mL, Sigma-Aldrich, Taufkirchen, Germany) was added dropwise to the carbon support (1 g), the slurry was homogenised in an ultrasonic bath (Model 3000514, JP Selecta, Barcelona, Spain) and dried at 110 °C overnight. Carburisation was performed in a tube furnace (Termolab, Águeda, Portugal) at a slow temperature rise to 800 °C and then holding it at 800 °C for 2 h under permanent nitrogen flow (Air Liquide, 99.99995 %, Algés, Portugal). The characterization of the prepared composite electrocatalysts, Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C/CNT and Mo
 <sub>2</sub>C/CXG, by X-ray diffraction analysis (XRD) (Philips 1050 Bruker D8 Advance, Bruker, Billerica, MA, USA), scanning electron microscopy (SEM) (JEOL JSM 7001F, JEOL, Tokyo, Japan), thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) (TA SDT 2960, TA instruments, New Castle, DE, USA), and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) (Kratos AXIS Ultra HSA with VISION software, Kratos Analytical Ltd., Manchester, UK) is presented in detail in a previous paper [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-01805" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>].
</p>
