<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The interpretation of wire-like Zn growth (
 <xref rid="R131" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>131</italic>
 </xref>) based on the Wulff shape of Zn in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5C</xref> appeases as less successful. Note that these Wulff shapes are built, assuming that the crystal is exposed to vacuum. In a solution, the interphase that adheres to certain facets (in the form of either a loose adsorbent layer or a solid by-product layer) can alter the energy landscape and thereby dominate the stable shape of crystal grown from that solution (
 <xref rid="R132" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>132</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R133" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>133</italic>
 </xref>). For example, when the deposit surface is cover by a thin (~5 nm) ZnO interphase, the Zn crystal grows preferentially along the [002] direction, forming 1D wire-like structures (
 <xref rid="R134" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>134</italic>
 </xref>). Analogous uniaxial growth along the [002] direction is also reported in vapor deposition of Zn under NH
 <sub>3</sub> gas, where a Zn
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>2</sub> interphase possibly formed by reaction with the NH
 <sub>3</sub> gas can produce a structure-directing effect (
 <xref rid="R135" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>135</italic>
 </xref>). This growth mode suggests that the six side facets are stabilized by the interphase and exhibit lower surface energy than the (002) basal plane. These observations are consistent with the argument made in previous section that the interphase formed on the surface of Zn will impose a strong effect on the deposition process, via the alterations of mass transport pathway and/or of crystal surface energy. In addition, of particular interest here is that the moss-like Zn morphology has been observed in vapor deposition (
 <xref rid="R136" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>136</italic>
 </xref>). This seemingly contradicts with our conclusion that the SEI formed in liquid electrolytes engenders moss-like growth because one may think that such interphase is absent on vapor-deposited Zn metals; the authors, however, interestingly report the existence of “a thin ZnO film on the Zn nanowire surface,” evidenced by the characteristic photoluminescence bands of ZnO. All these observations point toward the conclusion that these wire-like Zn deposition morphologies are fundamentally correlated to the interphasial chemistry.
</p>
