<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The use of microalgae to actively bio fix CO
 <sub>2</sub> is an activity strictly related with the growing factor of these microorganisms. In the past, a lot of research works were published where the focus was to produce enough biomass to economically sustain the production of biodiesel. This scope in the last years was slowly changed to production of food, cosmetic, and high value compounds. However, it is a fact that microalgae to successfully perform photosynthesis needs CO
 <sub>2</sub>, in fact it was reported that microalgae cells contain about 50% carbon, in which 1.8 kg of carbon dioxide are fixed by producing 1 kg of microalgae biomass [
 <xref rid="B31-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. Using photosynthesis process the CO
 <sub>2</sub> is fixed by microalgae cells to support their growth by using the carbon to produce carbohydrate and consequently, the carbohydrates are used to build proteins, nucleic acids, and lipids [
 <xref rid="B33-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]. Because of their simple cell structure and fast growth rate, microalgae are expected to have a 10 to 50 times higher CO
 <sub>2</sub> bio fixation efficiency than terrestrial plants [
 <xref rid="B34-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>,
 <xref rid="B35-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. This aspect related to the microalgae metabolism could be usefully considered for carbon capture mitigation when the microalgae were cultivated on a high efficiency system that is strongly integrated with an industrial plant. In this scenario, the CO
 <sub>2</sub> is provided by an existing industrial stream, as well as for the nutrient elements. There has been increasing interests on the use of microalgae growing technology for both bio fixation of carbon dioxide from flue gases [
 <xref rid="B36-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>,
 <xref rid="B37-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="B38-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>,
 <xref rid="B39-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B41-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>] and removal of nutrients from wastewater [
 <xref rid="B40-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B41-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>,
 <xref rid="B42-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>,
 <xref rid="B43-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>,
 <xref rid="B44-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. Another consideration that needs to be done is related with the kind of light energy provided to the microalgae growing system. If the light is coming from natural source, it has been proven that the theoretical maxima of solar energy conversion efficiencies in photosynthesis is around 10%–8% solar-to-biomass [
 <xref rid="B32-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. As confirmed by other experimental works the best-case scenario (lab and small scale green microalgal productivities) has achieved only about 40% (or less) of the theoretical maximum productivity. At the same time, the best case solar to biomass energy conversion efficiency obtained with green microalgae did not exceed the 3% value [
 <xref rid="B45-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>,
 <xref rid="B46-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]. Several studies reported by Melis (2009) [
 <xref rid="B32-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>], highlight solar to biomass energy conversion efficiencies for Spirulina and switchgrass that are lower than 1%. Obviously, biomass productivity is much lower for traditional C3 crop [
 <xref rid="B47-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>] and wild land plants, where the solar to biomass conversion efficiency values are below 0.1%.
</p>
