<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Ebi and colleagues have pointed out that this lack of funding stems not only from limited resources, but also from the belief that climate change is an “environmental” problem for which primary responsibility for research lies within non-health agencies and institutes, as well as a narrow framing of the health risks of climate change that does not consider systems-based approaches [
 <xref rid="B9-ijerph-18-07868" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Further, in the context of climate-related disasters, funding has traditionally focused on emergency preparedness or disaster response and recovery, with health impacts only considered secondarily. However, research tells us that a focus on health is a useful approach to help inform climate change policy and engage the public [
 <xref rid="B10-ijerph-18-07868" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-ijerph-18-07868" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-ijerph-18-07868" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. This is because climate change is inherently a health problem—a recent case study of climate-sensitive events in just eleven U.S. states in a single year estimated that the total health-related costs were USD 10 billion [
 <xref rid="B13-ijerph-18-07868" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Thus, considering climate change as a public health concern makes a compelling economic case, as well as a humanitarian one. The new Administration’s request for fiscal year 2022 discretionary funding—which includes a USD 100 million increase to NIH’s Climate Change and Human Health program, a USD 100 million increase to CDC’s Climate and Health program, and the establishment of a new Office of Climate Change and Health Equity within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)—recognizes the health implications of climate change and is a step in the right direction, although greater efforts are still needed, including in the area of metrics development to measure progress and facilitate accountability.
</p>
