<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par11">Elevated sulphur abundances were recorded throughout the 11 Maros-Pangkep rock art panels examined (Figs. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> and SI), except in areas of active water wash over the panels, something also observed in similarly ancient rock paintings in nearby East Kalimantan (Indonesian Borneo)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>. We identified salts typical of haloclasty on the underside of spall flakes; specifically, gypsum (calcium sulfate) (× 2) and halite (sodium chloride) at Leang Lompoa, Leang Balang Pakalu 5 and Leang Timpuseng (SI). These salts epitomize different aspects of the weathering processes: flaking and granular disintegration. With hydration, gypsum can increase in volume by 63%, creating accompanying swelling pressure, while the dehydration (phase transition to anhydrite) induces a 39% volume decrease
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> (p. 228); however, halite, a deliquescent salt found on the surfaces at Leang Timpuseng, has a smaller hygrometric morphology that tends to form a granular crust on damp substrates
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> (p. 227). Notably, Leang Timpuseng is one of two studied sites in closest proximity to the extensive wet rice fields (
 <italic>sawah</italic>) characteristic of Maros-Pangkep. The identification of halite at Leang Timpuseng is also important because the higher the concentration of sodium chloride in solutes, the lower the temperature required for hydration/dehydration transitions (shrink and swell) of calcium sulphide crystals that catalyse the flaking/spalling of rock surfaces
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> (p. 230). This indicates a far greater risk for accelerated degradation of Pleistocene rock art in proximity to 
 <italic>sawah</italic> and also 
 <italic>empang</italic>—the extensive networks of saline aquaculture ponds in the lower reaches of the Rammang-Rammang River, the watershed boundary at the heart of the Maros-Pangkep region.
</p>
