<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par13">Understanding the environmental context of early rock art is crucial for designing effective management strategies to help preserve these irreplaceable images from the human past
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>
 </sup>. Our study of the materiality of the Maros-Pangkep rock art panels shows that geological salts are ubiquitous, something borne out across the IMC by emerging physicochemical work on rock art in adjacent Indonesian islands
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">50</xref>
 </sup>. Loss of the painted limestone “canvas” from salt efflorescence enhanced by El Niño conditions is the most pressing threat to rock art preservation in this region – aside from the industrial-scale quarrying of limestone (with associated pollution yet to be quantified)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>
 </sup>. Long term physical and chemical monitoring has been ongoing in the Franco-Cantabrian rock art sites of Lascaux and Altamira since 1963 and 1997, respectively, with detailed climatic studies currently underway at Chauvet, Orgnac (Ardèche), Esparros (Hautes-Pyrénées), and Villars caves
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>
 </sup>. While a small-scale monitoring program has recently been initiated in Maros-Pangkep by the Makassar-based cultural heritage agency Balai Pelestarian Cagar Budaya, more support for this initiative is required, especially infrastructure investment. As some of the earliest known examples of artistic creativity on the planet, the Pleistocene rock art of Maros-Pangkep warrants monitoring and conservation efforts on par with those carried out over decades in Europe. The exceptionally old cave art of Indonesia is located within a dynamic tropical environment that renders it particularly vulnerable to the destructive impacts of climate change, adding unique urgency to this call for further research.
</p>
