<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">The island of Sulawesi lies at the centre of the Indonesian Maritime Continent (IMC), a region characterized by major ocean–atmosphere interactions
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. The lowland ‘tower’ karst of Maros-Pangkep sits at the southern end of the Tonasa Formation, an isolated platform sequence of Eocene to late Miocene marine-deposited limestones dominated by photic zone benthic foraminifera
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. The karst landscape covers an area of ~ 450 km
 <sup>2</sup> between 4°7′S and 5°1′S and is situated on an alluvial plain close to the western shoreline of Sulawesi’s southwestern peninsula, bounded to the east by the volcanic mountains of the Western Dividing Range. The isolated karst towers and plateau-like hill masses of Maros-Pangkep range from 150 to 300 m in height and 1 to 10 km in diameter, with networks of footcaves, overhangs, and high-level cave passages
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup> housing an extensive rock art assemblage first reported by archaeologists in the 1950s
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. More than 300 cave sites or rock shelters harbouring parietal imagery have been documented in these karsts, with new rock art sites found each year during ongoing field surveys (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>). At least two temporal phases of prehistoric imagery are evident based on direct-dating and studies of superimposition. The first phase, executed from at least 45.5 ka until ~ 20 ka based on Uranium-series dating of associated overlying coralloid speleothems
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>, is found exclusively on older case-hardened cave surfaces. Pleistocene rock art is characterised by red/mulberry hued pigments and typically comprises hand stencils and figurative paintings of large-bodied endemic land mammals (especially wild suids) shown in outline profile with irregular infill. The second, more recent rock art phase is found on fresher cave surfaces (or, more rarely, superimposed over the older cave surfaces and art styles) and is assumed to be only a few thousand years in age. This phase is attributed to the Neolithic farming communities colloquially known as ‘Austronesians’ who colonised Sulawesi ~ 4000–2000 years ago. This younger art phase is usually executed in black pigment (charcoal
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>) and is characterised by small images of anthropomorphic figures and domesticated fauna such as dogs, as well as an array of geometric motifs and abstract signs/symbols. We conducted direct Accelerator Mass Spectrometry (AMS) radiocarbon (
 <sup>14</sup>C) dating of a charcoal drawing of a human figure, typical of the Austronesian-style, located on the fresher surfaces of the ceiling panel at Leang Bulu Bettue. This yielded an age of 1583‒1428 calBP (SHCal 2020, Wk42768); to our knowledge this is only the second absolute age determination reported for such a motif
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).
</p>
