<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">In almost all sites containing early art, the hand stencils and figurative motifs are heavily affected by exfoliation of the limestone cave wall/ceiling surfaces that comprise the artists’ “canvas” (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> and Supplementary Information—SI). The deposition of solutes (chiefly irons, silicones, and calcium carbonates) from the bedrock and surrounding environment concentrate and oxidise at the limestone’s surface, blocking pores to form a mineralised rind—a process known as case-hardening
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. The case-hardened surfaces of the Maros-Pangkep caves, co-created by biofilms including plentiful microbial mats
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>), regulate water penetration on limestone surfaces, preventing rapid moisture uptake
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> (p. 217). While case-hardening makes the surface layer more resistant to weathering, the sub-surface zone immediately underneath is weakened by loss of cement matrices, the void spaces becoming susceptible to the accumulation of evaporites such as geological salts, especially where the outer crust has been breached
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>. From the earliest published descriptions of the Maros-Pangkep rock art over half a century ago, exfoliation of the older case-hardened surface of panels has been noted—termed “blistering” in early reports
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup> (p. 30). Also evident is the execution of the second phase of art production on more recent surfaces and/or overlying small areas of remnant case-hardening. In many instances, such as at Leang Bulu Bettue, Austronesian style rock art was created on long-exfoliated cave surfaces that preserve residual hand stencils of presumed Late Pleistocene age, suggesting that in some cases the early rock art was already in a state of advanced deterioration several thousand years ago. Similarly, at the cave art site of Leang Lambatorang Dutch graffiti signed with dates as early as AD 1769 is visible on “fresh” limestone surfaces exposed by exfoliation of early phase rock art (SI). A mounting body of quantitative and anecdotal evidence suggests that the rate of exfoliation is increasing (SI). Indonesian cultural heritage professionals, local academic archaeologists, and site custodians from nearby communities (some of whom have worked at the rock art sites long-term, even intergenerationally) report that the destruction of rock art through spalling has accelerated, with more panel loss from exfoliation over recent decades than at any other time in living memory
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
