<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par6">The tropics have always been integral to the global climate system, essentially acting as a “heat engine” driving millennial-to centennial-scale oscillations
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup>. The Australasian monsoon domain within which Sulawesi is located (from the equator to 10° S latitude and from 110° E–130° E longitude) is the most atmospherically dynamic region on Earth
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup>. Monsoon intensity has been the dominant feature of the Australasian paleoclimate
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (p. 110) with recent regional reconstructions beginning to disentangle the varied, localised responses to climate fluctuations across the IMC
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup> (p. 22). Generally speaking, a dry background climate state dominated the Australasian monsoon region during the Late Pleistocene (40–12 ka). At the time the earliest rock art in Maros-Pangkep was being created (at least 45–35 ka), climatic conditions were cooler and moister/more humid, resulting in lower evaporation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup> (pp. 26–27). This cool trend increased from ~ 32 ka throughout the glacial period when the tropics experienced generally stable dry conditions, peaking at the Last Glacial Maximum (LGM) 22–18 ka as a result of sea levels dropping to at least ~ 125 m lower than today, reducing Sea Surface Temperatures (SST) by 1–3 °C and constricting the Indo-Pacific Warm Pool (IPWP). Current evidence suggests the monsoon disappeared entirely over northern Australia at this time, but there were at least periodically wet conditions over the IMC
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup> (pp. 27–28). The monsoon appears to have undergone a process of reinvigoration (with some reversals) from 15 ka and was well-developed by 13–12 ka; oxygen isotope data throughout the tropics records relatively stable temperatures, even during the Arctic Cool Reversal (14.5 to 12.5 ka) and Younger Dryas (12.85–11.65 ka)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (p. 102), before a return to generally wetter, warmer conditions across the IMC with the inundation of the Sahul Shelf to the south 12–11 ka, and the Sunda Shelf to the west ~ 9.5–8.5 ka, warming SSTs and increasing evaporation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
