<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par7">Though less frequent or extreme than it is today, the El Niño Southern Oscillation’s (ENSO’s) El Niño phase became a dominant climate feature 7–5 ka
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup> (p. 30)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (p. 103). The IPWP reached thermal maximum 6.8–5.5 ka when coccolith records from the Banda Sea east of Sulawesi suggest a significant shift in the position of the monsoon (~ 6 ka) owing to low-latitude insolation forcing
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup>. Localised aridity from El Niño characterises much of Australasia from 5 ka
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup> (p. 29)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (pp. 103, 109), though more extreme and longer dry events are recorded 2.5–1.7 ka
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (p. 103). Modelling of ambient temperatures over the last millennium suggests peak pre-industrial warmth in Australasia 0.8–0.65 ka
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>
 </sup> (p. 5581). Terrestrial and marine records show dry El Niño dominated conditions on Sulawesi over the past 400–300 years
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>
 </sup> coincident with the advent of rice cultivation in the south of the island, dating to at least the fourteenth century
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>, though rice has been grown in West Sulawesi for more than 3 ka
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>
 </sup>. Minimum temperature anomalies are recorded at the time of the Northern Hemisphere’s so-named ‘Little Ice Age’ in the 16
 <sup>th</sup> and early nineteenth centuries
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>
 </sup> (p. 5381). These data complement stable isotope records from the Great Barrier Reef of Australia that document ENSO intensifying from the early 1600 s, with extended droughts in the mid-1760s to 1780s
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (concurrent with dated Dutch graffiti at Leang Lambatorang—SI). During these drier conditions, extensive deforestation of the fertile plains in Maros-Pangkep is likely to have occurred in step with the emergence of the earliest agrarian kingdoms (complex chiefdoms) in South Sulawesi in the late thirteenth century, and certainly from the fifteenth century onwards with the rise of the Makasar Goa-Talloq kingdom
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>. More extreme wet and dry years occur in the current era, which many scientists refer to as the ‘Anthropocene’ (&lt; 1965)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup> (p. 103)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">33</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>
 </sup>, precisely because of the prevalence of human induced environmental change. There is a clear trend toward more frequent ENSO activity in recent decades compared with past centuries or millennia
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup> (SI). These more intense and prolonged dry climate cycles, interspersed with moister recharge from monsoonal rainfall—combined with abundant evaporative water sources in the inundated rice fields at the base of the tower karsts and brackish aquaculture ponds toward the coastline—are providing highly favourable conditions for the deposit of the evaporite salts causing exfoliation of ancient cave/shelter surfaces.
</p>
