<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par8">The extensive shorelines of the IMC make the region sensitive to climate change
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup>, with Indonesia identified as a high-risk area in terms of drought-induced food security and extreme weather events such as tsunamis, flooding, and bush fires impacting densely populated coastal areas
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">4</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. The specific physiogeography of the Maros-Pangkep region makes it highly susceptible to ENSO. Located in the IPWP, Sulawesi’s hydroclimate is influenced by the changing position of the Intertropical Convergence Zone (ITCZ) and varying Indo-Pacific Walker circulation, with rainfall highest on the western coast compared with the rest of the island
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>
 </sup>. The highly seasonal precipitation in Maros-Pangkep is intensified by the central mountain range dividing the southwestern peninsula or ‘arm’ of Sulawesi, which preferences rainfall from southward monsoon migration—delivering ~ 80% annual precipitation December-March, while preventing astral winter rainfall from reaching the region as the ITCZ migrates north
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>
 </sup> (p. 11). Weather station data from Sulawesi shows 13 El Niño events between 1972 and 2012 with dry days (rainfall of &gt; 1 mm) increasing by more than two months in El Niño years compared with typical La Nina conditions
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>
 </sup>. Rainfall observations between 1967 and 2015 indicate that southwest Sulawesi is most highly affected by El Niño, experiencing longer dry spells, and, in the case of the Maros-Pangkep region, the most consecutive dry days
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup>. It is this combination of seasonal rainfall with alternating prolonged dry conditions under El Niño that provides ideal conditions for salt efflorescence and other forms of evaporite deposition.
</p>
