<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <list list-type="bullet" id="cssc202100364-list-0002">
  <list-item>
   <p>At smooth electrodes the adsorbate layer is formed during one cycle under the RRDE measurement conditions in this study, while the anodic peak associated with adsorbate layer oxidation is located around 0.3 V. Moreover, for 
    <italic>f</italic>
    <sub>R</sub>=13, after completion of the adsorbate layer, regeneration of the electrode by oxidative stripping of the adsorbate, starts at 0.3 V. For very rough electrodes, an anodic current can be observed starting from −0.5 V, which indicates easier oxidation of the incomplete adsorbate layer, as the layer is not finished during one cycle (indicated by diffusion‐limited peroxide formation during the ORR on rough electrodes).
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Oxidation of the adsorbate layer and of thicker peroxide layers occur at similar potentials.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>We had shown before, that oxidation of the superoxide CaO
    <sub>2</sub>
    <sup>+</sup> (at the ring electrode after formation at the disc) requires overpotentials of more than 0.5 V. This had been ascribed to the stabilization of the superoxide by forming a contact ion pair with Ca
    <sup>2+</sup>. This effect is much more drastic for peroxide oxidation, which requires overpotentials of 1.5 V at a smooth ring electrode. This is not really astonishing because the reversible thermodynamic potential of CaO
    <sub>2</sub>/O
    <sub>2</sub> is about 1.5 V more positive than that of the superoxide Ca(O
    <sub>2</sub>)
    <sub>2</sub>/O
    <sub>2</sub>.
    <xref rid="cssc202100364-bib-0029" ref-type="ref">
     <sup>[29]</sup>
    </xref> Since superoxide formation can occur only around −1 V (vs. Ag/Ag
    <sup>+</sup>), and since peroxide formation involves superoxide as an intermediate, it is the reduction to peroxide which requires a large (negative) overpotential, whereas its reoxidation occurs close to the thermodynamic potential. The question remains whether a catalyst or another solvent could be found for a possible calcium/oxygen battery allowing the direct 2‐electron reduction to peroxide at a more positive potential than to superoxide in Ca containing electrolytes.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
