<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par22">The selection of the moving window instead of single-pixel ensured a high probability of statistically significant regression results by including a larger number of pixels in the analysis and considering the neighbour environmental effect (Abel et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">2019</xref>). Furthermore, according to Abel et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">2019</xref>), when a step of time of a temporal-spatial moving window is 14 or 15 years, the optimal size of the moving window is 7 × 7 according to the significance of the regression slope and the quality of the regression fit. Additionally, we conducted a sensitivity test on the moving window size to determine a suitable size (Fig. S4). For example, we took the relationship between CS and precipitation and tested different sizes from 3 × 3 to 19 × 19. Subsequently, we generated nearly 1500 random points to extract the p-value of regression analysis, and the proportion of points with a p-value less than 0.05 was counted. When the size is 7, there is a high proportion of statistical significance. Furthermore, a size of 7 can capture better-detailed features compared to the larger size. Therefore, the size of the moving window was set to 7. The annual precipitation data comes from CHIRPS dataset. Temperature data is from the day temperature and night temperature of the MOD11A2 and MYD11A2 products (see Table 
 <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> for details). We used the average method to get the annual temperature product based on the above datasets. Further, we assumed that the effects of climate change on ecosystem services are linear, even though the relationship between environmental variables and ecosystem services are usually non-linear like logarithmic or exponential (Koch et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">2009</xref>; Schlenker et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR80">2009</xref>; Sutherland et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR93">2016</xref>; Peng et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">2017</xref>; Qiu et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR75">2019</xref>) in a larger observation interval. This is based on the consideration that our analysis was conducted to explore the impact of climate change on ecosystem services for single or neighbour pixels, and the degree of climate change of a single pixel is not so large. Therefore, we can approximate the non-linear relationship as a linear relationship.
</p>
