<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In general, the following factors may determine the distribution of insect pests: (I) natural biogeography; (II) crop distribution; (III) agricultural practices (monocultures, irrigation, fertilizers, pesticides); (IV) climate; (V) trade; and (VI) cultural patterns [
 <xref rid="B80-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">80</xref>]. Climate change will have a major impact on the geographic distribution of insect pests, and low temperatures are often more significant than high temperatures in determining their geographic distribution [
 <xref rid="B81-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">81</xref>]. Numerous pest species are shifting their range because of climate change, but also due to increased international trade, which allows individuals to disperse throughout the world. In the case of agricultural insect pests, this type of dispersal shift can greatly affect agricultural production [
 <xref rid="B82-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">82</xref>]. The geographic distribution and abundance of all organisms in nature is accentuated by species-specific climatic requirements that are crucial for their growth, development, reproduction, and survival. Modified temperature and precipitation patterns with the foreseeable changes in climate will determine the distribution, survival and reproduction of species in the future [
 <xref rid="B43-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. Due to the spread of insect pests to new areas, along with the shift in the growing areas of their host plants, farmers will face new and severe pest problems. In such cases, in addition to climatic conditions suitable for the particular crop, other factors such as soil properties and environmental structure are of great importance [
 <xref rid="B83-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">83</xref>]. For pest species in general, a poleward shift in distribution limits is predicted as a response to global warming [
 <xref rid="B84-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">84</xref>]. The ranges of insect pests are expected to shift to higher altitudes by 2055, with an increase in the number of generations in central Europe. In Europe, for example, the European corn borer (
 <italic>Ostrinia nubilalis</italic> Hubner) has shifted more than 1000 km northward [
 <xref rid="B85-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">85</xref>]. Nevertheless, a decrease in the number of generations was predicted for southern Europe due to global warming, which would negatively affect populations of this insect pest. This implies that climate change affects various species differently [
 <xref rid="B6-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Lopez-Vaamonde et al. [
 <xref rid="B86-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>] reported that 97 non-native Lepidoptera species in 20 families have become established in Europe, and 88 European Lepidoptera species in 25 families have expanded their range in Europe, with 74% of species becoming established in the last century. Parmesan et al. [
 <xref rid="B87-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">87</xref>] studied 35 species of non-migratory European butterflies and concluded that the geographic ranges of 63% had shifted 35 to 240 km northward and only 3% southward in the 20th century. Increased fluctuations of warm air masses towards higher latitudes have resulted in the establishment of the Diamondback moth (
 <italic>Plutella xylostella</italic> L.) in Arctic Ocean on the Norwegian islands of Svalbard, 800 km north of its former range limit in western Russia [
 <xref rid="B88-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">88</xref>]. The pink bollworm (
 <italic>Pectinophora gossypiella</italic> Saunders), a major cotton pest, is presumed to be expanding its current range from the frost-free zone in southern Arizona and California into the cotton growing areas of Central California [
 <xref rid="B89-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">89</xref>]. Gutierrez et al. [
 <xref rid="B90-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">90</xref>] suggest that the range of the Olive fly (
 <italic>Bactrocera oleae</italic> Rossi) in both Europe and North America will retreat southward and expand northward due to the effects of warmer summer temperatures and milder winters on adult flies. High summer temperatures currently limit the range of the 
 <italic>B. oleae</italic> in the desert regions of Arizona and southern and central California, while the cold limits its range in the far north. Climate warming is predicted to further limit its occurrence in many regions of California as high summer temperatures become increasingly unfavourable. Conversely, climatic conditions along the California coast are expected to be more favourable for them to thrive. In Italy, low winter temperatures limit olive and 
 <italic>B. oleae</italic> occurrence in the northern regions, but this is expected to change as formerly unfavourable regions become favourable due to global warming [
 <xref rid="B90-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">90</xref>]. On the other hand, changes in frost pattern, are one of the drivers of the spread of the frost-sensitive insect pests [
 <xref rid="B91-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">91</xref>]. The frequency of spring frosts decreases with increasing temperature, so longer warm periods extend the period and intensity of insect epizootics [
 <xref rid="B92-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">92</xref>]. Crop growers can in theory benefit from earlier seeding, but as a consequence these plants then become available to insect pests sooner, allowing them to begin feeding earlier and cause greater damage, as well as potentially producing additional insect generations during the typical growing season [
 <xref rid="B92-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">92</xref>]. In addition, rising temperatures may increase the overwintering survival of insects that were limited by low temperatures at higher elevations, leading to an expansion of their geographic range [
 <xref rid="B93-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">93</xref>,
 <xref rid="B94-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">94</xref>].
</p>
