<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Although there are still many unknowns related to climate change, it is widely accepted that it greatly affects the cultivation of agricultural plants as well as the insect pests associated with them. Some of the uncertainties regarding different aspects of climate change that are relevant to insect pests include small-scale climate variability such as temperature increase, increase in atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub>, changing precipitation patterns, relative humidity, and other factors. Given the enormous heterogeneity of insect species, their host plants and global climate variability, mixed responses of insect species to global warming are expected in different parts of the world. The effects of climate change on insects are complex, as climate change favours some insects and inhibits others, while impacting their distribution, diversity, abundance, development, growth and phenology. Additionally, it is generally expected that there will be an overall increase in the number of pest outbreaks involving a broader range of insect pests. Insects would likely expand their geographic distribution (especially northward). Due to increased overwintering survival rate and the ability to develop more generations, the abundance of some pests will increase. Invasive pest species will likely establish more readily in new areas and there will be more insect-transmitted plant diseases. Another negative consequence that could occur as a result of climate change is the reduced effectiveness of biological control agents—natural enemies—and this could be a major problem in future pest management programs. If climate change factors lead to favourable conditions for pest infestation and crop damage, then we face a high risk of significant economic losses and a challenge to human food security. A proactive and scientific approach will be required to deal with this problem. Therefore, there is a great need for planning and formulating adaptation and mitigation strategies in the form of modified IPM tactics, climate and pest monitoring, and the use of modelling tools.
</p>
