<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The magnesium ion battery is arguably the most explored multivalent battery system due to its lower price, high volumetric capacity, and abundance (i.e., the eighth most abundant element in the earth’s crust) [
 <xref rid="B52-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]. Despite the fact that its ionic radius is similar to lithium, magnesium ions have high charge density, which results in a strong polarization effect and sluggish diffusion process in cathode materials. On the other hand, aqueous zinc ion batteries are gaining a lot of attention due to the high abundance and capacity of Zn metal along with the excellent electrochemical stability in water [
 <xref rid="B53-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. Aluminium is also considered an attractive option for batteries due to its high abundance, high gravimetric density, lower reactivity, and easier handling [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. It can theoretically provide three times more charge per transferred ion as compared to lithium due to its trivalence. However, an insufficient cycle life and low capacity rate limit its usage [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. In general, the high charge density of the multivalent ions results in numerous interactions within the lattice of the host intercalation material and with the other species present in the electrolyte, making the diffusion of the high charge-density ion slow [
 <xref rid="B54-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>,
 <xref rid="B55-materials-14-04177" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. How much more this can be affected if one considers a large area electrode is a big question. In these systems, a major obstacle is the lack of suitable cathode materials. The scarcity of current potential cathode materials is probably due to the lack of knowledge, since for example Zn
 <sup>2+</sup> and Al
 <sup>3+</sup> have not been among the common cations studied in large-area energy storage systems (ESSs). If successful, multivalent systems can make a major advancement of our understanding of to how to store energy.
</p>
