<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">The severity and urgency of global warming has been stressed in a recent statement signed by an overwhelming number of scientists:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par24">Scientists have a moral obligation to clearly warn humanity of any catastrophic threat and to “tell it like it is.” … [W]e declare, with more than 11,000 scientist signatories from around the world, clearly and unequivocally that planet Earth is facing a climate emergency (Ripple et al., 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">2020</xref>).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>This strong pessimism regarding climate change as an unmitigated or poorly mitigated process (2a above) is also expressed by Lenton and colleagues (Lenton et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">2019</xref>). They argue for a highly increased risk of tipping points such as loss of the West Antarctic ice cap, elimination of the Amazon rainforest and thaw of permafrost in Arctic regions:
 <disp-quote>
  <p id="Par26">In our view, the evidence from tipping points alone suggests that we are in a state of planetary emergency: both the risk and the urgency of the situation are acute … We argue that the intervention time left to prevent tipping could already have shrunk towards zero, whereas the reaction time to achieve zero emissions is 30 years at the best. Hence we might already have lost the control of whether tipping happens. A saving grace is that the rate at which damage accumulates from tipping–and hence the risk posed–could still be under our control to some extent (Lenton et al., 
   <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">2019</xref>).
  </p>
 </disp-quote>However, Lenton and colleagues recognize that there are some scientists who believe that global tipping is “highly speculative” with “low probability” (Lenton et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">2019</xref>). This disagreement indicates some differences in degree of pessimism concerning climate change as an unmitigated or poorly mitigated process.
</p>
