<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par28">Another example of differences in degree of pessimism can be seen in the debate on one of the climate scenarios presented in the 2014 IPCC report, namely the RCP8.5 scenario. This scenario was one of four scenarios (Representative Concentration Pathways, RCPs) for what might happen with emissions and temperature rise by 2100. RCP8.5 (an RCP with an additional 8.5 W/m
 <sup>2</sup> radiative forcing) “projects” a 4–5 °C rise above preindustrial levels with disastrous climate impact (IPCC, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">2014</xref>, 57–66). The term ‘projection’ should not be confused with ‘prediction.’ While the latter term refers to what is likely to happen, the former only explores what may happen given certain assumptions regarding emissions levels, temperature and climate impact (King et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">2015</xref>, 29–30). In the 2014 IPCC report the RCP8.5 was never intended to predict the future; it was merely a projection. However, it has been used by many commentators as a prediction of what is likely to happen in absence of strong and effective mitigation policies, that is, as a result of “business-as-usual” (Hausfather &amp; Peters, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">2020</xref>). Hausfather and Peters argue that the business-as-usual interpretation is misleading. RCP8.5 is only a “highly unlikely” worst-case scenario requiring an increase in the use of coal that exceeds some estimates of the accessible coal reserves and an unlikely reversal of the current trend of declining costs of clean energies relative fossil fuels. According to many studies we are rather heading towards 3 °C above preindustrial levels by 2100, which is serious enough (Hausfather &amp; Peters, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">2020</xref>). To this has been responded that the RCP8.5 scenario could still be likely due to feedbacks and tipping points such as thaw of permafrost in the Arctic releasing vast amounts of methane (cf. Lenton et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">2019</xref> cited above). Moreover, among the four scenarios RCP8.5 agrees best with the historic cumulative CO2 emissions 2005–2020 and matches best the current and stated climate policies (Schwalm et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">2020</xref>).
</p>
