<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Throughout history, human population growth has been accompanied by many changes in everyday life, culture, technology, science, the economy, and agricultural production. Agricultural production has also undergone many major changes—agricultural revolutions—which have influenced by the development of civilization, technology, and general human advancement. However, the exceptional population growth in the last 100 years has had many undesirable consequences that (along with changes in environmental conditions) impact the security of the food supply. The growing world population has rising demands for crop production and accordingly, by 2050, global agricultural production will very likely need to be doubled to meet that kind of increasing demand [
 <xref rid="B1-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. For food security, numerous studies have recommended that enhancing crop yield, rather than clearing more land surface for crop production, is the most sustainable approach [
 <xref rid="B2-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Modern scientific research and agronomy are focused on climate change and related phenomena—rising global temperature and atmospheric carbon dioxide concentrations, heat waves, flooding, intense storms, droughts and other extreme weather events. Therefore, more attention to the aforementioned abiotic factors is given in agricultural science, as the tendency to reduce yield loss due to such conditions increases. Regarding crop production, changes in precipitation patterns may potentially have higher importance than temperature rise, especially in areas where dry seasons present a limiting factor for agricultural production [
 <xref rid="B3-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. One of the major biotic factors are pests, which are also impacted by climate change and weather disruptions. Temperature rise directly affects pest’s reproduction, survival, spread and population dynamics as well as the relationships between pests, the environment, and natural enemies [
 <xref rid="B4-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. As such, it is very important to monitor pest’s appearance and abundance as the conditions of their occurrence can change at a high pace. This paper will review the impact of some of the predicted climate changes, especially the rise of atmospheric carbon dioxide concentrations and temperatures along with changeable precipitation pattern effects on the biology and ecology of harmful insects, especially invasive pest species, which can be a major problem in crop production. Potential solutions for the current issues in plant production will be presented, mostly in the form of modified integrated pest management (IPM) strategies, which include IPM and the production of healthy food in an environmentally friendly way as well the monitoring techniques and modelling prediction tools.
</p>
