<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Aiming at addressing the aforementioned issues facing the layered Na‐Fe‐Mn‐O system, a variety of strategies have been attempted to achieve better electrochemical performance, such as metallic cations (Ti
 <sup>4+</sup>, Cu
 <sup>2+</sup>, Co
 <sup>3+</sup>, etc.) doping to stabilize the P2 structure,
 <sup>[</sup>
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0025" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>25</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0035" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>35</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0037" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>37</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0038" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>38</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0039" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>39</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0040" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>40</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0041" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>41</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0042" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>42</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>]</sup> surface engineering to retard the detrimental side reactions,
 <sup>[</sup>
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0043" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>43</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0044" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>44</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>]</sup> or nanosizing to shorten the ionic diffusion paths.
 <sup>[</sup>
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0045" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>45</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>]</sup> For example, Rojo's group successfully synthesized a Ti‐substituted P2‐Na
 <sub>2/3</sub>Mn
 <sub>0.8</sub>Fe
 <sub>0.1</sub>Ti
 <sub>0.1</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> material, which turned out to proceed with a solid solution reaction rather than the P2‐O2 phase transition during the charge/discharge process and showed a long cycling life of 87% capacity retention after 300 cycles.
 <sup>[</sup>
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0025" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>25</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>]</sup> Hu and co‐workers fabricated a free‐standing electrode of P2‐Na
 <sub>2/3</sub>Fe
 <sub>1/2</sub>Mn
 <sub>1/2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> with graphene flakes, in which the 2D graphene effectively improved the reaction activity of the oxide particles by forming a 3D conductive network, delivering a fascinating discharge capacity of 156 mA h g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 0.1 C with a capacity retention of 61% after 40 cycles.
 <sup>[</sup>
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0043" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>43</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>]</sup> Guo's team focused on the morphology design and the tailored P2‐Na
 <sub>2/3</sub>Fe
 <sub>1/2</sub>Mn
 <sub>1/2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> nanofibers enabled an optimized rate performance of 142 mA h g
 <sup>−1</sup> and 52 mA h g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 1 C and 15 C, respectively.
 <sup>[</sup>
 <xref rid="advs2021-bib-0045" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>45</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>]</sup> Despite inspiring progresses have been made, in terms of practical applications, it is still not competent to well combine good cyclic stability with superior rate capability in P2‐Na
 <sub>2/3</sub>Fe
 <sub>1/2</sub>Mn
 <sub>1/2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> only through a single modification route. Considering that cations doping can stabilize the crystal structure and nanoengineering can facilitate the reaction kinetics, the incorporation of the aforementioned two strategies may offer an opportunity to simultaneously boost the fast and stable sodium‐ion storage in a Fe/Mn‐based layered oxide cathode. However, to the best of our knowledge, such a dual‐strategy has scarcely been adopted which still remains a big challenge to date.
</p>
