<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To ensure that ring current used above corresponded only to H
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> oxidation, multi-segmented CV sweeps were obtained with 0.5 mM 
 <bold>1</bold>, 1.37 M TFEOH, and 0.5 mM BQ under Ar and O
 <sub>2</sub> saturation conditions (Fig. S62 and S63
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>). Beginning from the resting potential, the voltage was swept to a switching potential of +1.1 
 <italic>vs.</italic> Fc
 <sup>+</sup>/Fc, then to a switching potential at −0.87 V 
 <italic>vs.</italic> Fc
 <sup>+</sup>/Fc, followed by final switching potential of +1.05 V 
 <italic>vs.</italic> Fc
 <sup>+</sup>/Fc before completing the sweep at the resting potential. Data taken under Ar (Fig. S62,
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref> black) do not display the expected oxidation features associated with H
 <sub>2</sub>Q or quinhydrone oxidation in control experiments (Fig. S64 and S65
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>). When catalytic potentials are swept, the return sweep shows anodic current increases at ∼+0.4 V 
 <italic>vs.</italic> Fc
 <sup>+</sup>/Fc, before the expected oxidation response of H
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub>, suggestive of the re-oxidation of other reaction intermediates. To account for the background current unique to catalytic conditions, two sets of RRDE experiments were conducted with ring potentials of +0.85 V and +0.4 V 
 <italic>vs.</italic> Fc
 <sup>+</sup>/Fc for the systems which exhibited Levich behavior: BQ and TFEOH (Fig. S35 and S38
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>), 1 : 1 Mn to BQ with TFEOH (Fig. S42 and S45
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>), 1 : 2.5 Mn to BQ with TFEOH (Fig. S48 and S51
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>), and 1 : 5 Mn to BQ with TFEOH (Fig. S54 and S57
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>). The raw disk current responses for both ring potentials were averaged at identical rotation rates to produce the required values for the analysis described in the preceding paragraph. The difference between the ring currents at these two potentials under catalytic conditions was used for the H
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> efficiency analysis to remove the current response from other reaction intermediates in the determination of 
 <italic>I</italic>
 <sub>ring corrected</sub>. CV traces obtained under co-electrocatalytic conditions using the working electrode of the RRDE electrode confirmed that minimal reversibility was present at a 2.5 mM concentration of BQ (Fig. S66
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>) with a larger working electrode. Data were compared at a single rotation rate (400 rpm; 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">Fig. 4</xref>) from the RRDE experiments with different ratios of 
 <bold>1</bold> : BQ to minimize variability from the multiple equilibria involved in the overall reaction. To obtain an average and standard deviation at a rotation rate of 400 rpm, the current densities at 0.8 V, 0.85 V, and 0.9 V 
 <italic>vs.</italic> Fc
 <sup>+</sup>/Fc were each used to calculate the % H
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub>.
</p>
