<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Ionic conduction is considered the most important variable for solid electrolytes, and hence there have been many material developments for improved ionic conductivity [
 <xref rid="B9-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B36-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>,
 <xref rid="B37-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="B38-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. 
 <xref rid="molecules-26-03239-t001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref> describes some experimentally and computationally determined ionic conductivities. Some traditional ionic conductors that are considered “good” in performance with respect to this measure are included in 
 <xref rid="molecules-26-03239-t001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref> for comparison. Addition of adducts and other modifications to borohydrides have been demonstrated to be effective at improving ionic conduction [
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B39-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B41-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. As an example, pure lithium borohydride (LiBH
 <sub>4</sub>
 <sup>−</sup>) has a room temperature ionic conductivity of ~10
 <sup>−7</sup> S/cm [
 <xref rid="B40-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. Doping and adducts have been demonstrated to enhance ionic conductivities. These increases are realized for a variety of reasons, among which are stabilizing high ionic conductivity phases, expanding the lattice, and forming high conductivity sub-lattice pathways [
 <xref rid="B40-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B41-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. Work has been done in adding ligands, such as -NH
 <sub>2</sub>, to affect ionic conduction in borohydrides. For example, MgBH
 <sub>4</sub> having an ionic conductivity of 10
 <sup>−8</sup> S/cm realizes an increase in ionic conduction to 10
 <sup>−5</sup> S/cm with the addition of an -NH
 <sub>2</sub> adduct [
 <xref rid="B39-molecules-26-03239" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>].
</p>
