<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The main negative emissions technologies are reported in the following. The information reported was elaborated starting from the reports present in the scientific literature [
 <xref rid="B24-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B29-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,
 <xref rid="B30-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]:
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p>Forestation, afforestation and reforestation would involve planting forests on unused land;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Biochar, biochar involves the production of enriched carbon material by the slow pyrolysis process;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Soil Carbon Management, agricultural land management practices such as reduced tilling, cover crops and certain grazing practices increase organic carbon levels in soils;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Ocean Fertilization, involves adding nutrients to the ocean in order to stimulate the growth of planktonic algae and other microscopic plants that take up CO
    <sub>2</sub>;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Augmented Ocean Disposal (“ocean liming”), uses lime in oceans to trap CO
    <sub>2</sub> in a stable, dissolved inorganic form;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Enhanced Weathering and Mineral Carbonation, implies the application of finely ground silicate or carbonate minerals to seawater or soils;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Bio-energy with Carbon Capture and Storage (BECCS), is the combination of two mitigation options: biomass combustion to generate energy and Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS). The BECCS process achieve negative emissions by storing the carbon dioxide resulting from the combustion of plants, which have previously removed CO
    <sub>2</sub> from the air through photosynthesis;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Direct Air Capture, refers to industrial methods for removing carbon dioxide from the air by putting the air in contact with a chemical sorbent that are able to absorb the carbon dioxide. An example of this are the “Artificial Trees” technology: this is a technology that mimics the processes by plant life to withdraw CO
    <sub>2</sub> from the atmosphere;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Lime–Soda Process, this process is similar to artificial trees, but uses a chemical scrubbing method to enhance CO
    <sub>2</sub> capture;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Carbon Storage and CO
    <sub>2</sub> utilization, both BECCS and Direct Air Capture need carbon storage to achieve permanent removal of the carbon from the atmosphere. The most common method is geological storage in depleted oil and gas fields, coal beds, and saline aquifers; however total storage capacity is uncertain and requires further geological studies.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
