<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Concern is growing that as a civilisation we are exceeding the planetary boundaries that sustain life (Rockström et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">2009</xref>). In December 2015, the 21
 <sup>st</sup> Conference of Parties (COP 21) delivered a global agreement for countries to reduce emissions to keep temperature increases below 2
 <sup> °</sup>C, with an aspirational target of 1.5
 <sup> °</sup>C (United Nations, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR79">2015</xref>) with moral and legal cases raised to support this action. Despite this positive development in the movement against climate change there are no clearly developed paths for most countries to achieve the pledged reductions (United Nations, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR80">2018</xref>). Further within countries where emission trading schemes are in place many organisations are yet to make the transformational changes required to decarbonise their operations (Laing et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">2013</xref>; Okereke &amp; Kung, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">2013</xref>; Wade &amp; Rekker, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR84">2020</xref>). Wright and Nyberg (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR94">2015</xref>) have argued that organisations are actively locked into a process of creative self-destruction, exploiting the earth’s resources at their own risk and the risk of civil societies; however, practical alternative solutions are not forthcoming. With close to unanimous scientific consensus on the anthropogenic nature of climate change (Cook et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">2013</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">2016</xref>) achieving change to halt the further degradation of the earth’s atmosphere must be considered the salient wicked management challenge of the next decade. Given this overwhelming evidence on the need to act on climate change we ask why do decision makers remain complacent? Understanding the process of decision-making for or against action on climate change and sustainability is a vital step in overcoming long standing inertia in many organisations on the issue.
</p>
