<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par36">Sterol analysis followed standard protocols
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">66</xref>
 </sup>. Specifically, Androstanol (0.1 mg mL
 <sup>−1</sup>) was added as an internal standard to each sample of approximately 0.5 g of dried, homogenised sediment. Lipid compounds were extracted with solvents (DCM:MeOH, 3:1) using Microwave-Assisted Extraction, saponified and separated into neutral and acid fractions using aminopropyl SPE columns. The neutral fraction of each sample was then separated using silica gel column chromatography. The sterol fraction was trimethylsilylated using N,O-
 <italic>bis</italic>(trimethylsilyl)trifluoroacetamide (BSTFA)/trimethylchlorosilane (TMCS) (99:1 v/v) and heated at 70 °C overnight. Excess BSTFA-TMCS was removed by drying gently under nitrogen. Samples were dissolved in 50–100 µl of ethyl acetate prior to gas chromatography-flame ionisation detection (GC-FID) and gas chromatography–mass spectrometry (GC–MS) analysis. GC–MS analyses were performed on an Agilent 7890B GC injector (280 °C) linked to an Agilent 5977B MSD in full scan mode (50–600 amu s
 <sup>−1</sup>). Separation was performed on an Agilent fused silica capillary column (HP-5, 60 m, 0.25 mm ID, 0.25 um df) with Helium as a carrier gas. Sterol derivatives were analysed using the following temperature programme: 50 °C (held for 2 min) to 200 °C at 10 °C min
 <sup>−1</sup>, then to 300 °C at 4 °C min
 <sup>−1</sup> and held for 20 min. GC–MS peaks were identified through comparisons with known mass spectra (NIST08) and standards where possible. Analytes were quantified based on internal standards. For 13 of the samples, lipids were extracted from the dry sediment using a chloroform:methanol 2:1 mixture and then sonicated for 10 min, after which 0.75 mL of distilled water was added. Lipids were fractionated into neutral lipids (NLs; including sterols), glycolipids, and phospholipids (PLs) using a Bond Elut (0.5 mg) silica cartridge. First, the resin of the cartridges was conditioned using 5 mL of chloroform. Subsequently, the total lipids (1 mL) were applied to the resin, rinsed using chloroform, and then the NLs (including sterols) were collected under vacuum using 10 mL of chloroform. Sterols from the NL fraction were silylated with BSTFA, TMCS, and pyridine at 70 °C for 1 h. Trimethylsilyl (TMS) derivatives of sterols were analysed with GC–MS (Shimadzu) and GC-FID (Shimadzu) equipped with a Phenomenex (USA) ZB-5 Guardian column (30 m × 0.25 mm × 0.25 μm). Cholesterol and β-sitosterol were identified using characteristic ions of GC–MS runs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>
 </sup> and quantified with GC-FID using authentic standard solutions of plant sterol mixture from Larodan (including 53% β-sitosterol, 7% stigmasterol, 26% campesterol, 13% brassicasterol), and cholesterol from Sigma-Aldrich. The recovery percentage of the sterol samples was calculated using 5-α-cholestane (Sigma-Aldrich) as an internal standard.
</p>
