<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The species current estimated niche matched those of their current distributions, indicating that the climate variables available for use are capturing the environmental niche of these species (Baselga et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0003" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>). It is not unexpected that these 19 bioclimatic layers provide a reasonable niche estimate, given that amphibians are constrained by precipitation and temperature (Buckley &amp; Jetz, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0009" ref-type="bibr">2007</xref>). Most species in this group will not experience a decrease in suitable habitat, and in many cases, it expands. Most expand northward, with the exception of the most southern group (
 <italic toggle="yes">elongatus‐stormi‐asupak</italic>). This group seems to be at the highest risk for a contraction in their range and shifts toward the coast. This is similar to results from eastern 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon</italic> salamanders where southern species with small ranges displayed higher habitat loss, particularly those in drier ecoregions (Jacobsen et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0037" ref-type="bibr">2020</xref>; Milanovich et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0052" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>; Sutton et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0087" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). 
 <italic toggle="yes">Plethodon stormi</italic> in particular shows a pattern of expansion along the Cascade and Sierra Nevada Mountains indicating that this species may be especially restricted to the mountains and is the only species that might move southward. Following the mountain ranges in this geographic area is not an uncommon pattern (Matocq, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0048" ref-type="bibr">2002</xref>; Moritz et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0055" ref-type="bibr">1992</xref>), and given that several species in this group are mainly found in wet rocky talus slopes (Herrington &amp; Larsen, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0032" ref-type="bibr">1985</xref>; McIntyre et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0049" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>; Suzuki et al., 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0088" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>), it would not be surprising if salamanders in the PNW become more restricted to higher elevations. This might hinder their movement through valleys; however, there are many instances where many of these species have been found in what is not considered their preferred habitat (Corkran &amp; Thoms, 
 <xref rid="ece37735-bib-0019" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>).
</p>
