<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Concerning direct impacts, Global Warming is a progressive trend with variable intensity all over the world. Thus, heatwaves are strongly associated with mortality increases. Christidis et al. (2012) [
 <xref rid="B2-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>] pointed out that extreme heat events increased by fourfold in Europe between 1999 and 2008, causing in some countries about 15,000 deaths [
 <xref rid="B3-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Several scholars have stated that Global Warming is also responsible for an increase in cardiovascular, respiratory and kidney diseases, besides an increase in forest fires which are associated with an increase in smoke-related morbidity and mortality [
 <xref rid="B4-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. In terms of eye health, there is evidence of the effect of heat on the inflammatory response of the corneal cells [
 <xref rid="B6-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Furthermore, this has been related to the predisposition to infectious viral processes such as herpes and viral conjunctivitis, besides bacterial and fungal processes, in addition to allergies [
 <xref rid="B7-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Moreover, van der Leun et al. (2008) [
 <xref rid="B9-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] noted that an effective dose of ultraviolet radiation (UVR) could increase by 2% for every degree Celsius as the temperature rises. This phenomenon could also suppress cell immunity and increase sensibility to infections, facilitating the activation of latent viruses [
 <xref rid="B10-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Additionally, increasing UVR, in conjunction with summer thermal maximum, is related to the increase of ocular tumors and cataracts [
 <xref rid="B12-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], along with an increased risk of retinal detachment [
 <xref rid="B16-ijerph-18-07197" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>].
</p>
