<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A silver nanowire membrane was developed by filtering 2 mL of ethanolic dispersion of the silver nanowires through a quantitative filter paper (diameter = 25 mm, maximum aperture diameter: 10–15 µm). Next, the membrane was immersed in 1% (mass fraction) newly prepared sodium borohydride solution for 5 min and dried naturally to remove the PVP ligands [
 <xref rid="B34-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Then, the membrane was cut into 10 mm × 5 mm rectangles and used as working electrodes. An electrolytic cell with three electrodes was used for treating the membrane and recording the current–voltage curves. An Ag/AgCl electrode was used as the reference electrode; a 100 mL beaker filled with 100 mL of 0.1 mol·L
 <sup>−1</sup> hydrogen chloride solution was used as the electrolytic cell, and a titanium sheet covering the inner curved surface of the beaker was used as the auxiliary electrode. Then, the cut membrane was fixed on the platinum electrode holder to maintain good contact between the silver nanowires membrane and platinum sheet. Additionally, the area immersed in the electrolyte is 5 mm × 5 mm. During the experiment of treating the membrane in different scanning cycles at constant temperature, the experiment method was cyclic voltammetry; the potential scan rate was 0.025 V∙s
 <sup>−1</sup>; the potential scan range was from −0.1323 to 0.2677 V; the number of scans was set at 5, 10, 15, 20, and 25, respectively; the beaker was immersed in a water bath at 20 °C. During the experiment of treating the membrane in constant different scanning cycles at different constant temperature, the experiment method, the potential scan rate and the potential scan range were not changed; the number of scans was set at 15; the water bath was set at 16, 18, 20, 22, and 24 °C, respectively. Every time before starting the CV scan, the temperature of the beaker was ensured to reach the preset value and kept constant for 5 min. After the treatment, the treated substrates were washed with ultrapure water for 3 times and then dried naturally.
</p>
