<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A Zn-conducting water-in-trisalt gel electrolyte and halogen-incorporating cathode have been successfully developed and used in Zn-based electrochemical energy storage for the first time. The benefits of using confined halogen within the carbon structure as a cathode are (i) elimination of the irreversible binding of Zn
 <sup>2+</sup> to the host structure within the cathode chemistry, (ii) the provision of substantial extra charge through their conversion–intercalation/adsorption process, and (iii) obviating the need for ions to diffuse to the surface from bulk electrolyte as they are already inside the carbon structure. The most significant findings emerging from this study are that the identity of the Zn halide and carbon structure in the cathode composite produces electrochemical energy storage devices that are fundamentally different from each other (battery vs supercapacitor). The use of graphite in the composite electrode produced batterylike behavior, where the voltage plateau was related to the standard potential of the halogen species. 
 <italic>In situ</italic> Raman spectroelectrochemistry revealed that the identity of halides determines the mechanism of charge storage, intercalation vs electrosorption. In contrast, when activated carbon was used in the composite, the cell acted as a hybrid Zn-ion capacitor due to the fast reversible halogen species electrosorption/desorption in the carbon pores. In this case, the overall capacity is related to the number (binary or ternary) of Zn halides present; and the Zn|(activated carbon–ZnCl
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>2</sub>) cell exhibited a high specific capacity and energy density as well as good cycling stability. The combination of the Zn|(activated carbon–ZnCl
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>2</sub>) cell with the WiTS gel electrolyte is promising for the development of high-performing, low-cost, and environmentally friendly energy storage device based on Zn. Future work should focus on the microstructural design of carbon pores to match the size of halogens as well as investigating other carbon structures such as heteroatom-doped carbon or high surface area hard carbon materials.
</p>
