<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>PEMFCs (polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells) are a promising alternative energy source for transportation and stationary applications. The advantages of fuel cell technology include a high conversion rate, a natural operating temperature, environmental friendliness, and high stability [
 <xref rid="B1-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. According to the literature, PEMFCs can have the same potential power as batteries, power grids, and combustion engines [
 <xref rid="B2-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Despite the fact that PEMFCs are relatively cost-effective energy sources, their market availability for widespread use faces some obstacles that should be resolved. The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) on the cathode of the fuel cell, proceeds with a slower chemical kinetics, which is the most noticeable drawback of this technology [
 <xref rid="B3-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. A number of oxygen-containing species such as OH
 <sup>−</sup>, O
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>−</sup>, HO
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>−</sup> and H
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> are produced in aqueous media during the process which compete with oxygen reduction on electrode surface involving adsorption and desorption processes [
 <xref rid="B3-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Due to their immense importance in storage devices and electrochemical energy conversion systems, the oxygen reduction reaction on the cathode is extensively studied and still research in this field is in progress. Apart from its scientific significance, oxygen electrocatalysis is a requirement of industry where the renewable energy devices rely on oxygen electrochemistry (fuel cells, fuel synthesis, and metal-air batteries). As mentioned above the systems based on oxygen electrochemistry, the ORR has been documented as slow reaction kinetically as mostly platinum or platinum based electrode used are contaminated that affect the efficiency of oxygen reduction reaction. Pt is also an expensive metal with low availability around the globe. As a result, scientists have begun developing Pt-free nanoparticles as a dopant material for such electrodes, which has increased the catalytic activity and stability of cathode materials [
 <xref rid="B4-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-26-03440" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>].
</p>
