<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par30">Standard elevational metrics were related with ecological components and habitat zones of beaches to identify the vulnerability of sandy beach ecosystems to SLR. The current and future state of the ecologically critical, upper tidal zone of each beach, which ranged from bluff-backed, dune-backed, armored, and groomed, was measured and modeled using the total water level datum
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR108">108</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR109">109</xref>
 </sup> as a proxy for the dynamic landward extent of the upper intertidal zone, equivalent to the daily High Strand line (HTS)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>
 </sup>. Ecological research on area beaches
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR69">69</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR71">71</xref>
 </sup> combined with beach surveys and coastal processes studies enabled a predictive framework to be established between SLR and changes in the upper beach zones
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR84">84</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR110">110</xref>
 </sup>. The total water level projections from CoSMoS
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR95">95</xref>
 </sup> for 0.50, 1.00, 1.50, 2.00 and 5.00 m of SLR combined with background conditions (i.e. daily) and annual storm scenarios were used to establish the landward extent of the upper beach zone. The seaward limit of the upper beach zone was determined by the projected MHW elevation, as determined by shoreline modeling driven by a CoSMoS-generated twenty-first century water level time series
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR77">77</xref>
 </sup>. Upper beach zone landward migration and width was restricted by the presence of non-erodible structures, such as revetments, sea walls, roads or parking lots.
</p>
