<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Climate change has been identified as our greatest global health threat that will put the lives of people around the world at risk [
 <xref rid="B107-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">107</xref>,
 <xref rid="B108-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">108</xref>]. This review examined the factors that influence climate change-related mortality to describe the phenomenon in one country, the United States. Despite the importance of this issue to health of a nation, we found that capturing the full extent of climate change-related mortality has proved difficult. Relying on the published literature to identify the factors that influence climate change mortality may miss important findings that could be used to address policy and climate change adaptation programs. Depending on the state and the person completing the form, deaths certificates many only report the cause of death with a medical diagnosis, such as renal failure. The electronic health record (EMR) could be a valuable tool to search for climate change-related health indicators and mortality by linking ICD-10 codes. This would require some encouragement for providers to link climate, weather, and social indicators to the patient condition. There are classifications within the 2021 ICD-10 diagnosis codes for social issues (Z55-Z65), air pollution (Z77.110), flooding (X38.XXXA), heat (T67), and hypothermia (R68.0) but they are infrequently documented to record climate change-related mortality. Li and colleagues [
 <xref rid="B92-ijerph-18-08220" ref-type="bibr">92</xref>] used inpatient discharge data from ICD coding of the primary diagnosis, meteorological conditions, air pollution data, and ICD coded (by the investigators) death certificate to identify the impacts of extreme heat on climate change-related morbidity. Linking the ICD-10 codes that address climate change-related mortality to national weather and disaster information could further support accurate climate change mortality reporting. These data are important to provide the full impact of climate change to human health, for health care planning, to inform policy makers, and to promote climate adaptation and resilience plans for the U.S. population. An important next step would be to develop methods to quantify climate change-related mortality, instead of measuring impacts of single climate change events such as just wildfires or heatwaves. Quantifying climate change-related mortality as a whole can provide a comprehensive indicator of climate change impacts on the health of a population.
</p>
