<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Another important factor for ORR and OER activities is the geometrical effects of catalysts. For example, Kakizaki et al
 <italic>.</italic> demonstrated that in the case of β-phase manganese dioxide, the OER activity depends on the exposed crystal facet on the catalyst surfaces.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref>
 </sup> These facet dependencies were also reported for LaCoO
 <sub>3</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> and LiMn
 <sub>1.5</sub>Ni
 <sub>0.5</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>
 </sup> Furthermore, some studies have reported that ORR and OER activities can be improved by bending or distortion of polyhedra comprising active metal and O atoms.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref>
 </sup> Recently, the control of crystal phases was investigated to enhance ORR and OER activities. Long et al
 <italic>.</italic> compared the ORR activities of two distinct cobalt (Co)–manganese (Mn) spinel oxides bearing a cubic and a tetragonal phase, respectively.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref>
 </sup> Additionally, crystalline polymorphism affects ORR and OER activities on manganese oxide,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref38">38</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref>
 </sup> iron oxyhydroxide,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref40">40</xref>
 </sup> and palladium/copper alloy.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref>
 </sup> Besides such microscopic geometry, macroscopic morphologies are also keys to enhancing the ORR and OER activities. Several studies have attempted to construct catalyst nanostructures to enlarge surface areas and improve mass transports during the electrochemical ORR and OER processes. These catalyst nanostructures include enriched porous nanofibers and nanorods,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref>
 </sup> template-constructed porous structures,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref>
 </sup> and metal–organic framework structures.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref44">44</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
