<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>These reports suggested that geometrical effects play an important role in ORR and OER activities, while no study has investigated the influence of structural dimensionality on electrocatalytic ORR and OER activities. Such structural differences affect various characteristics, such as cathode performance for lithium-ion batteries
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref>
 </sup> and catalytic activity for aerobic oxidation;
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref46">46</xref>
 </sup> therefore, it may also affect the electrocatalytic activities for ORR and OER due to a change in electronic states. This paper presents the influence of structural differences on ORR and OER activities to obtain a novel guideline for designing promising oxygen electrocatalysts, among three types of Co–Mn bimetallic oxides (CMOs): tunnel-type (CMO_T), layer-type (CMO_L), and spinel-type (CMO_S) structures, as shown in 
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>. CMO_T exhibits a bundle 3 × 3 tunnel todorokite-type structure of a MnO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedral framework (OMS-1), where hydrated Co
 <sup>2+</sup> ions conduct in the one-dimensional tunnel. CMO_L exhibits a stacked layered structure of Mn oxides, with two-dimensionally intercalated Co
 <sup>2+</sup> ions. The interlayer distance can be changed by hydration conditions. CMO_S possesses a normal spinel structure, where the 8
 <italic>a</italic> site of Co
 <sup>2+</sup> ions can conduct through three-dimensional an 8
 <italic>a</italic>-16
 <italic>c</italic>(vacancy)-8
 <italic>a</italic> path in the Wyckoff position in the 
 <italic>Fd</italic>–3
 <italic>m</italic> space group. These materials show similarities in the host structures of a MnO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedral framework and guest Co
 <sup>2+</sup> ions, with distinct cation conduction paths. In addition, these materials are selectively prepared from the same procedure of an alcohol reduction process.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref46">46</xref>
 </sup> By controlling the reaction condition, such as the metal source, water content, and reaction temperature, a variety of Mn-based binary oxides can be obtained. Here, we examined ORR and OER activities of CMOs in alkaline media and discussed the important factors concerning the control of the catalytic performances.
</p>
