<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The swabbing extraction SERS detection of malachite green, fluoranthene [
 <xref rid="B35-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>], and potassium nitrate [
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-11-00672" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] were achieved by swabbing them on clean glass, polyethylene packaging bag, and aluminum sheet, respectively. The substrates were wet with methanol when swabbing fluoranthene and infiltrated with water while swabbing malachite green and potassium nitrate. The signals of malachite green were collected and used directly without normalization. Briefly, for the malachite green detection, 10 µL of 10
 <sup>−8</sup>–10
 <sup>−3</sup> M of malachite green aqueous solution were dropped on a clean glass and left to dry naturally. Then, the optimized substrate soak with water was used to gently swab the glass surface to collect the residue of the analytes. One gentle swabbing is sufficient. Substrates were decorated with propyl mercaptan by immersing them in a 10 mM ethanolic propyl mercaptan solution for 2 h before detecting fluoranthene and the SERS signals obtained were normalized by Raman peak at 1025 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> of propyl mercaptan. Briefly, 10 µL of 10
 <sup>−7</sup>–10
 <sup>−3</sup> M of fluoranthene ethanolic solution were dropped on a polyethylene packaging bag and left to dry naturally. Then, the optimized decorated substrate soak with ethanol was used to gently swab the bag surface to collect the residue of the analytes. One gentle swabbing is sufficient. Before detecting potassium nitrate, the substrate must be modified with DDTC by the infiltration in a 10 mM DDTC aqueous solution for 2 h. Then, the SERS signals obtained were normalized by Raman peak at 1271 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> of DDTC. Briefly, 10 µL of 10
 <sup>−8</sup>–10
 <sup>−3</sup> M of potassium nitrate aqueous solution were dropped on an aluminum sheet and left to dry naturally. Then, the optimized decorated substrate soak with water was used to gently swab the sheet surface to collect the residue of the analytes. One gentle swabbing is sufficient. During all the SERS detections, the excitation wavelength was 785 nm and the input laser source of the instrument was operated at 50 mW, and the integration time was 1 s.
</p>
