<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xml:lang="EN" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ao</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acsodf</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Omega</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2470-1343</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7807758</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsomega.0c04702</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Analysis of the Charging Current in Cyclic Voltammetry
and Supercapacitor&#x02019;s Galvanostatic Charging Profile Based on
a Constant-Phase Element</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Yun</surname><given-names>Changsuk</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath2"><name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>Seongpil</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1">Department of Advanced Materials
Chemistry, <institution>Korea University</institution>, Sejong 30019, <country>Korea</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>Email: <email>sphwang@korea.ac.kr</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>28</day><month>12</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>12</day><month>01</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>6</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>367</fpage><lpage>373</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>24</day><month>09</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>14</day><month>12</month><year>2020</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; 2020 American
Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2020</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><license-p>This is an open access article published under a Creative Commons Non-Commercial No Derivative Works (CC-BY-NC-ND) Attribution <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/page/policy/authorchoice_ccbyncnd_termsofuse.html">License</ext-link>, which permits copying and redistribution of the article, and creation of adaptations, all for non-commercial purposes.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_0007" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>We
investigated the charging current in cyclic voltammetry and
the galvanostatic charging/discharging behavior of a controversial
constant-phase element (CPE) to describe an electrical double layer
used only in electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. The linear potential
sweep in the time domain was transformed into the frequency domain
using a Fourier transform. The current phasor was estimated by Ohm&#x02019;s
law with the voltage phasor and a frequency-dependent CPE, followed by an inverse Fourier transform to
determine the current in the time domain. For galvanostatic charging/discharging,
the same procedure, apart from swapping the voltage signal with the
current signal, was applied. The obtained cyclic voltammetry (CV)
shows (1) a gradual increase in the charging current, (2) a higher
charging current at a low scan rate, and (3) a deviation from the
linear relationship between the charging current and the scan rate.
For galvanostatic charging/discharging, the results demonstrate (1)
curved charging/discharging behavior, (2) a higher voltage in the
early stage, and (3) a lower voltage during longer charging periods.
In contrast to a previous approach based on solving a differential
equation with a simple RC circuit, our Fourier transform-based approach
enables an analysis of electrochemical data with an arbitrary and
complex circuit model such as a Randles equivalent circuit. The CPE
model is more consistent with previous experimental results than a
simple ideal capacitor, indicating a ubiquitous CPE in electrochemistry
and a fair figure of merit for supercapacitors.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>ao0c04702</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>ao0c04702</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Cyclic
voltammetry (CV), a powerful technique used to investigate
electrochemical processes, has been attracting much attention in relation
to renewable energy.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> CV studies provide information
about (1) the formal potential and its close link to the standard
reduction potential of redox couples, (2) the charge-transfer kinetics
of electrodics, (3) the concentration of redox couples, (4) chemical
reaction mechanisms, and (5) the diffusion coefficient of redox couples,
among others.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref></sup> In spite of the popularity
of CV, there are several difficulties with this process, such as a
voltage drop by uncompensated solution resistance (iR drop) and background
signals. At a high electrolyte concentration and in conventional three-electrode
systems, the iR drop is negligible in most experiments. The latter
case, however, has been a practical issue in interpretations of CVs
because the precise estimation of the faradic current is essential
either for the determination of concentrations in analytical chemistry
or for the figure of merit of electrocatalysts or supercapacitors.
The dominant portion of the background current in CV originates from
the electrical double layer (EDL), which is modeled as a Gouy&#x02013;Chapman&#x02013;Stern
(GCS) double layer consisting of a serial connection between two capacitances
corresponding to the outer Helmholtz layer (OHP) and the capacitance,
which originates from the diffuse layer.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup> At a high electrolyte concentration, the capacitance of the diffuse
layer increases and the total capacitance therefore converges to the
capacitance of the OHP. Assuming that the capacitance is independent
of the applied potential, the background current in CV for the applied
potential (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>A) is explained by assessing the constant charging current with the
transient current at the vertex point of the potential sweep, as shown
in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>C. In reality,
this behavior of ideal polarized electrodes is rare, meaning that
this system has been verified based on the simple capacitance model.
Thus, CV in the absence of a redox couple is often used as a background,
which is not suitable for quantitative analysis and not practical
for several processes in electrochemistry such as a hydrogen evolution
reaction (HER).</p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>(A) Time versus the applied potential of CV with scan
rate = 100
mV/s and (B) corresponding power spectrum of the potential in the
frequency domain. CVs obtained by an inverse Fourier transform at
different scan rates with CPE of (C) <italic>n</italic> = 1.0 (pure
capacitor), (D) <italic>n</italic> = 0.9, (E) <italic>n</italic> =
0.8, and (F) <italic>n</italic> = 0.7. (G) Dependence of the charging
current upon <italic>n</italic> of CPE. Equivalent circuits are composed
of 100 &#x003a9; as a solution resistance and <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> = 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> F/s<sup><italic>n</italic>&#x02013;1</sup> as a CPE.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_0002" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig><p>Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy
(EIS) is another electrochemical
technique concomitant with CV.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref></sup> EIS is
based on a small-amplitude AC signal at a constant DC bias. EIS data
have been analyzed based on equivalent circuits composed of passive
elements such as resistance, capacitance, and Warburg impedance. A
physical meaning is assigned to each element, including the charge-transfer
resistance, double-layer capacitance, and diffusion impedance. Experimental
data have shown a systematic deviation from a simple model, especially
for double-layer capacitance as a nonfaradic process. While the GCS
model predicts the response of an ideal capacitor for a small AC signal
whose phase shift is &#x003c0;/2, the experimental current compared
to the applied AC voltage is shifted by <italic>n</italic> &#x000d7;
&#x003c0;/2, where <italic>n</italic> is a value between 0 and 1. This
new passive element, called a constant-phase element (CPE) in EIS,
has been widely used in equivalent circuits for EIS. The CPE can be
written as<disp-formula id="eq1"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_m001" position="anchor"/><label>1</label></disp-formula>where <italic>i</italic> is an imaginary unit
(<italic>i</italic><sup>2</sup> = &#x02212;1), &#x003c9; is an angular
frequency, and <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>n</italic> (0&#x02013;1) are the characteristic values corresponding to the
double layer.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref></sup> The <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> parameter represents ideal capacitor behavior when <italic>n</italic> = 1 or intermediate characteristics between a capacitor and a resistor
when <italic>n</italic> &#x0003c; 1.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup> Although
the origin of the CPE is still not clear,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref></sup> it remains a viable empirical element for use in
EIS techniques.</p><p>Galvanostatic charging/discharging has also
been used to characterize
supercapacitors and secondary batteries due to its relatively direct
physical relationship to the capacitive charge. For an ideal capacitor,
the triangular response upon a constant current with a small deviation
at the vertex caused by the solution resistance can be predicted.
However, the empirical results deviate severely from the theoretical
model, thus raising issues with regard to the validity of the simple
capacitor model for interpretation of results.</p><p>Questions remain
on how the charging current will flow in CV and
galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge for the CPE instead of the simple
capacitance. On the other hand, the ideal capacitor explains the charging
current, which is inconsistent with the empirical charging current
in both CV and galvanostatic charging/discharging. On the other hand,
the CPE instead of a capacitor has been successfully adopted to interpret
EIS data for small perturbations. This raises the question: why do
we not apply the CPE model to other electrochemical techniques to
predict the charging current for larger perturbations? The bottleneck
is that the CPE is described by a function of a complex variable depicted
in a phasor diagram due to the AC characteristic, while CV is expressed
as a function of a real variable. Specifically, the charging current
of CPE shown in <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref> upon
linear sweep voltage or galvanostatic charging/discharging is not
straightforward. <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> of the CPE is in units
of F/s<sup><italic>n</italic>&#x02013;1</sup> instead of F from the
real capacitance. Sadkowski published the first effort to address
this question based on a Laplace transform with a simple CPE.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> A similar approach was also applied to estimations of galvanostatic
charge&#x02013;discharge.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> Previous reports
investigated the electrochemical response of a simple equivalent circuit
consisting of a serial connection of the resistance and the CPE because
solving a general equation for a more general model, such as the Randles
equivalent circuit, is difficult. To circumvent the mathematics involved
in solving a differential equation for a complex model, our group
recently investigated the relationships between voltammetry, chronoamperometry,
and EIS using the Fourier transform (FT), in which the frequency domain
was used to predict the electrochemical response in the time domain.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> In the present paper, we applied the Fourier
transform to determine a bundle of harmonic waves for CV and the corresponding
current signal to observe the charging current of the CPE in CV. A
similar process was also applied to galvanostatic charging/discharging,
where our model returns the voltage signal corresponding to the harmonic
current signal at each frequency with the effective capacitance to
estimate the ability of a capacitor. The results show that the charging
behavior is more consistent with the experiments and with previous
reports on the CPE, demonstrating the validity of the CPE model for
use in various electrochemical techniques based on our FT-based approach.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2</label><title>Theory and Experiments</title><p>All results were obtained using
a house-built MATLAB code to perform
the discrete Fourier transform of triangular potential sweep and the
corresponding current signal. A simple equivalent circuit for an electrochemical
cell consisted of a serial connection of solution resistance (<italic>R</italic><sub>s</sub>) and CPE. The current signal at the frequency
domain was calculated based on simple Ohm&#x02019;s law<disp-formula id="eq2"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_m002" position="anchor"/><label>2</label></disp-formula>where <italic>V</italic> and <italic>I</italic> are complex numbers at a specific frequency, <italic>Z</italic> is
the total impedance, and other parameters are the same as in <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref>. For all calculations,
solution resistance and <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> were 100 &#x003a9;
and 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> F/s<sup>(1&#x02013;<italic>n</italic>)</sup>, respectively. Then, the data array of <italic>I</italic> (complex
number of current) at each frequency was transformed into the time
domain by the inverse Fourier transform to obtain the current signal
at the time domain.</p><p>Cyclic voltammetry was measured in a three-electrode
system cell
using a CHI 900B potentiostat (scan rate = 50 mV/s). A Au disk electrode
(BASi, 1.6 mm diameter), a mercury&#x02013;mercurous sulfate electrode
(MSE, sat. K<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>), and a Pt wire served as the
working electrode, reference electrode, and counter electrode, respectively.
A 0.105 M KClO<sub>4</sub> electrolyte was purged with argon gas for
15 min before the experiment. Both the voltage signal and the current
signal were transformed into the frequency domain based on a previously
reported method,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> followed by impedance
data. It should be mentioned that this impedance from large perturbations
is not the same as the conventional electrochemical impedance from
small perturbations. Then, the low-frequency region of impedance was
fitted with Randles equivalent circuits shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>A whose impedance is written
as follows<disp-formula id="eq3"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_m003" position="anchor"/><label>3</label></disp-formula>where <italic>Z</italic> is the total impedance, <italic>R</italic><sub>s</sub> is the solution resistance, <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> is the charge-transfer resistance, <italic>Q</italic><sub>1</sub> and <italic>n</italic>1 (0&#x02013;1) are the characteristic
values corresponding to CPE, <italic>Q</italic><sub>2</sub> and <italic>n</italic>2 (near 0.5) are the characteristic values corresponding
to Warburg impedance, and other parameters are the same as in <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref>. The house-built MATLAB
code was used to find optimized parameters for <xref rid="eq3" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq3" ref-type="disp-formula">3</xref></xref> based on nonlinear curve-fitting in least-squares
sense from split real parts and imaginary parts from experimental
CV.</p></sec><sec id="sec3"><label>3</label><title>Results and Discussion</title><p><xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref> illustrates
the method used to estimate the charging current in a cyclic voltammogram
(CV) with two different equivalent circuits. The first circuit, shown
in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>A, was composed
of the solution resistance and the conventional double-layer capacitance
(<italic>C</italic><sub>dl</sub>). Instead of <italic>C</italic><sub>dl</sub>, the empirical CPE was adopted. It is expressed here as <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref> (<xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>B). The total impedance in both cases was
the vector sum of <italic>R</italic><sub>s</sub> and the capacitive
element depicted in the corresponding phasor plot. Note that the phase
of the CPE differs from that of <italic>C</italic><sub>dl</sub>. Owing
to the nature of the capacitive element being dependent on the frequency,
expressed here as <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref>, the prediction of the current in the time domain is not straightforward.
To circumvent this problem, the frequency domain was adopted, as illustrated
in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>C. First,
the triangular waveform of the CV was transformed into the frequency
domain, resulting in complex numbers of the voltage phasor for each
frequency. The complex numbers for the current phasor were then calculated
simply with Ohm&#x02019;s law, i.e., by dividing the complex number
of the total impedance into the complex number of the voltage, as
described in <xref rid="eq2" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq2" ref-type="disp-formula">2</xref></xref>. Then,
the inverse Fourier transform was applied to determine the current
in the time domain. Finally, the CV was plotted as the voltage versus
the current in the time domain. To assess the galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge,
voltage as a stimulus for an electrochemical cell was swapped with
the current as a response, while other procedures were identical to
those used with the CV.</p><fig id="sch1" position="float"><label>Scheme 1</label><caption><title>Illustration of Estimation of the Charging
Current for Cyclic Voltammetry</title><p id="s1fn1">Equivalent circuits
composed
of solution resistance and either (A) conventional double-layer capacitance
or (B) constant-phase element (CPE) with corresponding phasor diagrams.
(C) Procedures for predicting cyclic voltammogram by the Fourier transform.
Details are described in the main article.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_0006" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig><p>CVs were studied using the equivalent circuits shown in either <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>A or <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>B with <italic>R</italic><sub>s</sub> = 100 &#x003a9; and <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> = 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> F/s<sup>(1&#x02013;<italic>n</italic>)</sup> and with
various <italic>n</italic> values. <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>A,B shows the representative linear potential
program at 100 mV/s in the time domain and the corresponding power
spectrum in the frequency domain after the Fourier transform operation,
respectively, demonstrating the contribution of the relatively low-frequency
harmonic wave during the conventional electrochemical measurement.
For an ideal capacitor with <italic>n</italic> = 1.0, the CV shown
in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>C is in
good agreement with the previous theoretical result. Specifically,
transient currents at both vertices dependent on the RC time with
the steady-state charging current are clearly observed, indicating
the validity of our procedure based on the Fourier transform. <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>D&#x02013;F shows
the CVs of CPE with <italic>n</italic> = 0.9, 0.8, and 0.7, respectively.
Compared to <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>C, showing the ideal capacitor, first, the CVs of the CPE demonstrate
a gradual increase in the current in the charging region, whereas
transient behavior is still shown at both vertices. The smaller <italic>n</italic> is, the more CV tilts apparently. Empirically, the charging
current in the majority of electrochemical cells follows the CVs of
the CPE, as shown in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>D,E as compared to an ideal CV for a capacitor. Therefore,
the CPE is a better model than a conventional capacitor to explain
the electrical double-layer in CVs. Second, the charging currents
for the CPE are much larger than that for a conventional capacitor
at a slow scan rate, while the charging currents of both systems converge
to similar values at a high scan rate. To clarify this point, the
current at 0 V was used as an estimator of the charging current and
was plotted depending on the scan rates, as shown in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>G. At a slow scan rate of 10
mV/s, a charging current of 43 &#x003bc;A for <italic>n</italic> = 0.7
is double that of 20 &#x003bc;A for <italic>n</italic> = 1.0. In contrast,
a charging current of 206.6 &#x003bc;A for <italic>n</italic> = 0.7
is nearly identical to that of 200.2 &#x003bc;A for <italic>n</italic> = 1.0 at a higher scan rate of 100 mV/s. The smaller the <italic>n</italic> is, the larger the charging current is when observed at
a slow scan rate. Third, the linear relationship between the charging
current and the scan rate is no longer valid for the CPE. The charging
current of the ideal capacitor (black dashed line in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>G) increases linearly depending
on the scan rate. For the CPE, however, there is a deviation from
the linear line indicated by the green dashed line for <italic>n</italic> = 0.7. This tendency has been widely observed in electrochemical
experiments and in previous reports,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> indicating the validity of our FT-based approach
for CV with the CPE model. In summary, the CPE model strongly affects
the charging behavior in CV compared with an ideal simple capacitor
model, coinciding with empirical experiments for CVs well.</p><p>The
CPE model is superior to the conventional capacitor model used
in the CV; hence, we assume that this model will also be useful in
characterization of supercapacitors. To investigate the effect of
the CPE model on a supercapacitor, the galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
was applied. Charging is the core operation in a supercapacitor. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>A shows a time versus
current curve applied to an electrochemical cell as a means of excitation.
Here, constant currents of 10 &#x003bc;A were applied to the equivalent
circuit shown in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref> as the charging current and discharging current. This current in
the time (<italic>i</italic>) domain was transformed into the frequency
domain (<italic>I</italic>), similar to that in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>C, after which the voltage phasor (<italic>V</italic>) was calculated by the multiplication of a complex number
to the current (<italic>I</italic>) and the total impedance (<italic>Z</italic>) at each frequency. The voltage in the time domain was
then generated by the inverse Fourier transform. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>B shows the galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
curves for both the ideal capacitor and the CPE. The triangular response
with the small iR drop was in good agreement with the predicted behavior
of the ideal capacitor with a constant current, demonstrating the
validity of our method in the galvanostatic mode. For the CPE, the
response is not linear but instead appears to be curved. As distortion
in CV depends on the <italic>n</italic> value of the CPE, the smaller
the <italic>n</italic> is, the larger the curvature becomes. The initial
region of CPEs shows a higher voltage than the ideal capacitor, demonstrating
that the apparent capacitance of the CPE in this region is smaller
than in the ideal case. In the extended charging region, however,
the magnitude of apparent capacitance is reversed from the low values
at the early stage, indicating lower efficiency as an energy storage
device. These results are in good agreement with a previous report
on the CPE based on the Laplace transform.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> Interestingly, the majority of papers on supercapacitors demonstrate
CPE-like behavior in experiments, but the characterization of supercapacitors
has been conducted based on an ideal capacitor model. Thus, both <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>n</italic> are more reliable indicators
than the traditional capacitance value when characterizing a supercapacitor.
These two values do not represent the capacitance, but one can estimate
the apparent capacitance, also referred to as the effective capacitance.
Several models have been used to estimate the effective capacitance
from the CPE in EIS corresponding to small perturbations.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> For large perturbations such as galvanostatic charging/discharging
and cyclic voltammetry, the electrochemical response is much more
complex. The following equation describes the effective capacitance
(<italic>C</italic><sub>eff</sub>) for a simple equivalent circuit
consisted of the solution resistance and the CPE<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup><disp-formula id="eq4"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_m004" position="anchor"/><label>4</label></disp-formula>where &#x00393; is the &#x003b3;
function and <italic>t</italic> is the time. One can estimate this
time-dependent <italic>C</italic><sub>eff</sub> after the estimation
of <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>n</italic>. For instance, <italic>C</italic><sub>eff</sub> is 2.23 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> F
in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>B with <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> = 1.0 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> F/s<sup>&#x02013;0.3</sup>, <italic>n</italic> = 0.7, and <italic>t</italic> = 20 s. The effective
capacitance of the CPE at a short time is lower than that of an ideal
capacitor (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c04702/suppl_file/ao0c04702_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link>) such
that the larger potential in the initial region of the CPE in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>B is reasonable.
It is also important to note that similar behaviors for the charging&#x02013;discharging
of hybrid supercapacitors have been reported.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup> Unfortunately, we do not have any ideal method to identify the two
different processes of either a hybrid supercapacitor or the CPE.
Nonetheless, the suggested CPE model with our FT-based approach is
a very promising model applicable to estimations and for explaining
the behaviors of supercapacitors.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>(A) Time versus the applied current in
galvanostatic charging&#x02013;discharging.
(B) Galvanostatic charge and discharge profiles of the equivalent
circuit consisted of CPE with various <italic>n</italic> values.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_0003" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig><p>Both CV and galvanostatic charging/discharging
show the unique
features from the CPE model compared to the behaviors of a conventional
capacitor. Although the origin of the CPE has not yet been clearly
revealed, the CPE model represents the empirical experimental results
from electrochemistry well. To understand the physical meaning of
the CPE in an electrochemical system, Bode plots of equivalent circuits
were devised, as shown in <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>. Respectively, <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>A,B shows the amplitude and phase of equivalent circuits
depending on the frequency, respectively. At a high frequency, the
amplitude and phase of the total impedance approach the solution resistance,
as expected. The phase, however, still shows a difference between
the simple capacitor and the CPE. The phase of the simple capacitor
passed the inflection point approaching 0 of the resistor, while that
of the CPE with <italic>n</italic> = 0.7 does not reach the inflection
point. This implies that the CPE with a smaller <italic>n</italic> possesses capacitive characteristics even at a high frequency. The
effect of the CPE is more dramatic in the low-frequency region. Both
the amplitude and phase of the total impedance are smaller than those
of the simple capacitor. For the CV, larger charging current levels
were observed, as shown in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>, an outcome consistent with the smaller amplitude
of the total impedance because the lower frequency contributes more
to the slower potential scan. In addition, the remaining resistive
characteristics of the CPE at a low frequency from the phase cause
a gradual increase in the charging current. For galvanostatic charging/discharging,
the phase of the total impedance from the CPE shows more capacitive
behavior at a high frequency and more resistive behavior at a low
frequency. Therefore, the initial response of the galvanostatic measurement
depending on the high frequency tends to increase the potential, while
the longer charging causes the dissipation of the energy due to the
nature of the resistor.</p><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Bode plot of equivalent circuits in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>B for the amplitude
(A) and the phase (B).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_0004" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig><p>Our FT-based approach
can be applied not only to a simple serial
RC circuit model but also to a general equivalent circuit model, which
cannot easily be solved by the Laplace transform. The CV was obtained
from a Au working electrode, as indicated by the black solid line
in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>C, to get the practical charging current. Its impedance
was analyzed by our FT-based approach, as shown in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>C. The black dots in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>B represent the impedance
data for this large-amplitude perturbation, which is symmetric most
likely due to the symmetry of the current in the CV. Half of the experimental
data for the low-frequency region appear to consist of a hemisphere
and a linear line with ca. 45&#x000b0;, similar to the Randles equivalent
circuit shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>A in spite of the considerable difference in the amplitude of the
perturbation. It should be noted that both charge-transfer resistance
(<italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub>) and the Warburg impedance are not
expected for an ideal polarized electrode in an electrolyte without
redox species, whereas they were observed experimentally.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> The simple RC circuit models previously reported
do not represent the practical CV; thus, we assumed a Randles equivalent
circuit based on the trend shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>B. Although the physical meaning and the
origin of <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> and the Warburg impedance
are not obvious, we speculate that the heterogeneity of the electrode/electrolyte
interface,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup> liquid bulk phenomena,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> or the variance in the capacitance depending
on the electrode potential<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref></sup> may evoke
these components. In contrast to solving a complex differential equation,
we applied the lsqcurvefit function for nonlinear fitting in MATLAB
based on the Randles equivalent circuit. The red dots in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>B show the fitting
result from the FT-based approach. Even this equivalent circuit shows
some deviation from the experimental data in both the impedance and
CV because the Au/electrolyte interface is not a perfectly ideal polarized
electrode. Although the charging current for the electric double layer
is dominant, experimental background current can come from various
sources, though this is out of the scope of this manuscript. Note
that the experimental impedance can be fitted with any equivalent
circuit by our method. Then, the inverse Fourier transform results
in the CV are expressed by the red line in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>C. These results demonstrate that the experimental
electrochemical data in the time domain, such as the CV and galvanostatic
charging/discharging data, can be modeled with an arbitrary circuit
model to find the physical phenomena.</p><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(A) Schematic model of the Randles equivalent
circuit. (B) Nyquist
plots of impedance data from cyclic voltammetry (black dot) and from
fitting with the Randles circuit (red dot). (C) Cyclic voltammogram
of the bare Au disk electrode in 0.105 M KClO<sub>4</sub> with a scan
rate of 50 mV/s (black solid line) and the fitted voltammogram from
the equivalent circuit after the inverse Fourier transform to the
time domain (red solid line).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_0005" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec id="sec4"><label>4</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>We investigated the charging current in
the CV and galvanostatic
charging/discharging behavior of the CPE, which has been used in only
electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. To circumvent the frequency-dependent
reactance of the CPE, the response for specific excitation is analyzed
based on the harmonic wave at each frequency using the Fourier transform
combined with Ohm&#x02019;s law. The response in the time domain is
acquired by the inverse Fourier transform. Compared with CV based
on a conventional simple capacitor model, the equivalent circuit with
CPE shows (1) a gradual increase in the charging current, (2) a higher
charging current at a low scan rate, and (3) a deviation from the
linear relationship between the charging current and the scan rate.
For galvanostatic charging/discharging, the results demonstrate (1)
the curved charging/discharging behavior, (2) the larger voltage in
the early stage, and (3) the lower voltage in longer charging. From
empirical experimental results, CPE seems to model the real system
better than the simple capacitor, indicating the ubiquitous CPE in
electrochemistry. The CPE model may also apply to the characterization
of various electrochemical systems with an arbitrary circuit model,
especially the effective capacitance of supercapacitors with <italic>Q</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>n</italic>.</p></sec></body><back><notes id="notes-1" notes-type="si"><title>Supporting Information Available</title><p>The Supporting Information
is available free of charge at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsomega.0c04702?goto=supporting-info">https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsomega.0c04702</ext-link>.<list id="silist" list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Plot of time versus the
effective capacitance of CPE
(Figure S1) and the galvanostatic charging profile calculated by the
FT method and a previous mathematical model (Figure S2) (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c04702/suppl_file/ao0c04702_si_001.pdf">PDF</ext-link>)</p></list-item></list></p></notes><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="sifile1"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c04702_si_001.pdf"><caption><p>ao0c04702_si_001.pdf</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d7e1019-autogenerated"><p>The authors declare
no
competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>S.H. acknowledges the support from the Basic Science Research
Program through the National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) grant
funded by the Korea Government (MSIP) (No. NRF-2019R1A2C1089951).</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="book" id="cit1"><person-group person-group-type="allauthors"><name><surname>Allen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bard</surname><given-names>L.
R. F.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Electrochemical Methods:
Fundamentals and Applications</source>, <edition>2</edition>nd ed.; <publisher-name>John Wiely &#x00026; Sons</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>2001</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Elgrishi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rountree</surname><given-names>K. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>McCarthy</surname><given-names>B. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rountree</surname><given-names>E. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Eisenhart</surname><given-names>T. T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dempsey</surname><given-names>J. L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A Practical Beginner&#x02019;s
Guide to Cyclic Voltammetry</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Educ.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>95</volume>, <fpage>197</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>206</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jchemed.7b00361</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Stern</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The theory
of the electrolytic double layer</article-title>. <source>Z. Elektrochem.
Angew. Phys. Chem.</source>
<year>1924</year>, <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>508</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>516</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>H.-C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>W.-S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Modeling
and Applications of Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy (EIS) for
Lithium-ion Batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Sci.
Technol.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.33961/jecst.2019.00528</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Zoltowski</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>On the electrical
capacitance of interfaces exhibiting constant phase element behaviour</article-title>. <source>J. Electroanal. Chem.</source>
<year>1998</year>, <volume>443</volume>, <fpage>149</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>154</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0022-0728(97)00490-7</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>B.-Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Conversion
of a Constant Phase Element to an Equivalent Capacitor</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Sci. Technol.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>318</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>321</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.33961/jecst.2020.00815</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Hirschorn</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Orazem</surname><given-names>M. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tribollet</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Vivier</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Frateur</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Musiani</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Determination of effective
capacitance and film thickness
from constant-phase-element parameters</article-title>. <source>Electrochim.
Acta</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>55</volume>, <fpage>6218</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6227</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2009.10.065</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Kerner</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pajkossy</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>On the origin of capacitance
dispersion of rough electrodes</article-title>. <source>Electrochim.
Acta</source>
<year>2000</year>, <volume>46</volume>, <fpage>207</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>211</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0013-4686(00)00574-0</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>M. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lasia</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Influence of experimental
factors on the constant phase element behavior
of Pt electrodes</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>56</volume>, <fpage>8058</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8068</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2011.02.068</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Alexander</surname><given-names>C. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tribollet</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Orazem</surname><given-names>M. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Contribution of Surface Distributions
to Constant-Phase-Element (CPE) Behavior: 1. Influence of Roughness</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>173</volume>, <fpage>416</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>424</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2015.05.010</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>C&#x000f3;rdoba-Torres</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mesquita</surname><given-names>T. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nogueira</surname><given-names>R. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Relationship between the Origin of
Constant-Phase Element Behavior in Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy
and Electrode Surface Structure</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem.
C</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>119</volume>, <fpage>4136</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4147</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp512063f</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>C&#x000f3;rdoba-Torres</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mesquita</surname><given-names>T. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nogueira</surname><given-names>R. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Toward a better characterization
of constant-phase element behavior on disk electrodes from direct
impedance analysis: Methodological considerations and mass transport
effects</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>92</volume>, <fpage>323</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>334</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2013.01.036</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Sadkowski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Time domain
responses of constant phase electrodes</article-title>. <source>Electrochim.
Acta</source>
<year>1993</year>, <volume>38</volume>, <fpage>2051</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2054</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0013-4686(93)80339-2</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Sadkowski</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>On the ideal
polarisability of electrodes displaying cpe-type capacitance dispersion</article-title>. <source>J. Electroanal. Chem.</source>
<year>2000</year>, <volume>481</volume>, <fpage>222</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>226</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0022-0728(99)00480-5</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Gharbi</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tran</surname><given-names>M. T. T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tribollet</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Turmine</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Vivier</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Revisiting
cyclic voltammetry and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy analysis
for capacitance measurements</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>343</volume>, <elocation-id>136109</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2020.136109</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Allagui</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Freeborn</surname><given-names>T. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Elwakil</surname><given-names>A. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Maundy</surname><given-names>B. J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Reevaluation of
Performance of Electric Double-layer Capacitors from Constant-current
Charge/Discharge and Cyclic Voltammetry</article-title>. <source>Sci.
Rep.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <elocation-id>38568</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/srep38568</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27934904</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>B.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Correlation between Tafel Analysis
and Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy by Prediction of Amperometric
Response from EIS</article-title>. <source>ACS Omega</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>19307</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>19313</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsomega.9b02672</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31763554</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Orazem</surname><given-names>M. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Frateur</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tribollet</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Vivier</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Marcelin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>P&#x000e9;b&#x000e8;re</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bunge</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>White</surname><given-names>E. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Riemer</surname><given-names>D. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Musiani</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Dielectric
Properties of Materials Showing Constant-Phase-Element
(CPE) Impedance Response</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>160</volume>, <fpage>C215</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>C225</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.033306jes</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Supercapacitors Performance Evaluation</article-title>. <source>Adv.
Energy Mater.</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <elocation-id>1401401</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201401401</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Khademi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Barz</surname><given-names>D. P. J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Structure of
the Electrical Double Layer Revisited:
Electrode Capacitance in Aqueous Solutions</article-title>. <source>Langmuir</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>36</volume>, <fpage>4250</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4260</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c00024</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32227968</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Grahame</surname><given-names>D. C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The Electrical
Double Layer and the Theory of Electrocapillarity</article-title>. <source>Chem. Rev.</source>
<year>1947</year>, <volume>41</volume>, <fpage>441</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>501</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr60130a002</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18895519</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>