<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par14">This analysis is centered on the “sensitivity” and “exposure” of ecosystem services to climate change. These concepts reflect the response of a system to stress (Turner et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR97">2003</xref>). “Sensitivity” is defined as the degree to which a system is modified or affected by perturbations, and “exposure” is the nature and degrees to which a system experiences environmental or social stress (Adger 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">2006</xref>). According to the characteristics of the research object, the meaning of “sensitivity” and “exposure” has been also constantly enriched (Adger 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">2006</xref>; Smit et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR88">2006</xref>; Smith et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR89">2014</xref>; Seddon et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2016</xref>; Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">2018a</xref>). Adger (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">2006</xref>) thought vulnerability is a function of climate variation to which a system is exposed, its sensitivity, and its adaptive capacity. Smit et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR88">2006</xref>) highlighted the importance of quantifying sensitivity and exposure in risk management and adaptation to climate change. Remote sensing technology has being increasingly applied and it uses vegetation indices (e.g., NDVI) as a proxy to quantify the ecosystem sensitivity to climate change (Smith et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR89">2014</xref>; Seddon et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR83">2016</xref>; Li et al. 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">2018a</xref>). In our analysis, we directly used the ecosystem services instead of vegetation indices, and evaluated the effect of climate change on the services. Therefore, following Li et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">2018a</xref>), sensitivity is thus understood as the degree of disturbance of climate change on ecosystem services or the ecosystem services’ resistance to climate change. Exposure is to be interpreted as the gains or losses of ecosystem services driven by future climate.
</p>
