<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Herein, we describe a new class of composite cathode materials that contain Zn halides (ZnCl
 <sub>2</sub>, ZnBr
 <sub>2</sub>, and ZnI
 <sub>2</sub>) and carbons (graphite or activated carbon), where the halide ions act both as charge carriers and as redox centers. It should be noted that our approach differs from the conventional Zn–bromine flow battery, where bromide is oxidized to bromine and stored in an external tank.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> The approach we pursue in the current study uses Zn halide immobilized on carbon hosts as the cathode, where the redox activity of the halides is exploited to store more charge. In other words, the halides undergo a “conversion–intercalation/adsorption” reaction inside the carbon structure when the cell is charged using a Zn
 <sup>2+</sup> conducting water-in-trisalt (WiTS) gel electrolyte. Our approach also removes the halogen cross-over seen in Zn–bromine cells as the halogen is confined (intercalated or adsorbed) within the carbon structure upon oxidation. The variety of the halogen species means that the cell voltage can be fine-tuned and increased. The standard reduction potentials of I
 <sup>–</sup>/I
 <sub>2</sub>, Br
 <sup>–</sup>/Br
 <sub>2</sub>, Cl
 <sup>–</sup>/Cl
 <sub>2</sub>, and F
 <sup>–</sup>/F
 <sub>2</sub> redox couples are 0.54, 1.09, 1.36, and 2.8 V vs standard hydrogen electrode (SHE), respectively.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> The combination of the zinc-halide–carbon cathode with a Zn anode can therefore generate an open-circuit voltage that ranges between 1.3 and 3.5 V depending on the halide type. The flexible and non-flammable semisolid WiTS gel electrolyte, which is compatible with the halogen cathode, exhibited fast electrode kinetics for Zn oxidation and reduction without the formation of Zn dendrites. We will show that both the identity of the Zn halide and carbon structure in the cathode produces electrochemical energy storage devices that fundamentally differ from one another. The resultant composite electrodes can deliver a capacity of 480 mAh g
 <sup>–1</sup> at 0.05 A g
 <sup>–1</sup> with a corresponding energy density of 140 Wh kg
 <sup>–1</sup>. The conversion–intercalation/adsorption mechanism of the individual ZnX
 <sub>2</sub>–carbon composite in the WiTS gel electrolyte is characterized by electrochemical, 
 <italic>in situ</italic> Raman spectroscopy and 
 <italic>ex situ</italic> X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) techniques and analyzed in detail.
</p>
