<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Agricultural commodities face substantial risk from climate change because of their sensitivity to and dependence on weather variables
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>. One such commodity is coffee, a crop and beverage of importance in international trade. The two species of coffee with economic importance are the Robusta coffee (
 <italic>Coffea canephora</italic> Pierre) and Arabica coffee (
 <italic>Coffea arabica</italic> Linnaeus). Arabica coffee has relatively higher demand (over 70% of the world coffee market) due to its higher beverage quality
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>. Worldwide, there are five key agroecological zones suitable for producing Arabica coffee, classified on the basis of temperature and rainfall characteristics. These areas are between latitude 20° N and 25° S at altitudes ranging between 700 and 2000 m.a.s.l
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup>. Arabica coffee is more sensitive to climatic factors than robusta coffee and thus is expected to be affected more by climate change
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. This is because Arabica coffee is grown in specific climatic and biophysical envelopes coupled with a narrow genetic diversity
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>. As such, there is evidence that climate change is reducing area suitable for coffee
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, limiting yield
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>, and increasing the risks of pests and disease
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. These biophysical impacts eventually impinge on the livelihoods of 25 to 30 million smallholder coffee farmers who produce the majority of the world’s coffee
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
