<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">In addition to the general requirements for Arabica coffee production, and perhaps most importantly, coffee quality profiles are strongly influenced by local climatic (rainfall, temperature, humidity and radiation), topological (elevation, slope angle and aspect), and edaphic (soil depth, acidity/alkalinity and fertility) factors
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. These give the coffee distinctive characteristics specific to production areas. The combination of these factors is unique to each region and thus difficult to replicate, and slight modifications will affect the eventual profile of the coffee, but impact studies on this important aspect are missing. The effect is such that even when the same coffee variety is planted in different areas, the profiles will be different
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. This 
 <italic>terroir</italic> influence in coffee is so strong that it can be detected by chemical traces
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. As such, grading and classification of coffee on the global market are based on the roast appearance and cup quality (flavour, flagrance, acidity and body), bean physiognomies (size, shape and colour), the density of beans and number of defects
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. All of these characteristics are heavily influenced by the geographic characteristics (climate, altitude and soils) of the area of cultivation, the botanical variety and to some extent the preparation (washed or unwashed)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. In addition, the use of geographical indicators of origin as proxies of product and process quality have grown immensely in the single-origin coffee markets
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup>. The demand for specialty coffee is increasing across world markets, especially as they are used also in blending with lower quality coffees to create instant coffees. This creates opportunities for coffee growing countries and smallholder communities to receive a premium price of about + 20 to + 50% compared to regular coffee beans
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
