<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In recent years, a large volume of electrocatalysis research has focused on replacing noble metals with non-precious metals such as transition metal oxides, chalcogenides, phosphides, carbides, and nitrides. In particular, abundantly available iron and iron carbide (Fe/Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C) have received significant attention in this respect due to their strong, inherent, and durable catalytic activity for the OER and ORR. In the early 2000s, Lefevre et al. [
 <xref rid="B76-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">76</xref>] first reported an iron-based non-precious metal catalyst (Fe-NPMC) for polymer electrolyte fuel cells synthesized by twice ball milling a mixture of ferrous acetate and phenanthroline carbon support and then subjecting it to pyrolysis at 800 °C. They found that the current density of the iron-based cathode was almost equivalent to that of a Pt-based cathode at a cell potential of ≥0.9 V. Lee et al. [
 <xref rid="B77-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">77</xref>] subsequently fabricated Fe/Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C on melamine foam, which exhibited excellent ORR behavior in an alkaline solution. In addition, a similar type of C-C supported Fe/Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C cathode demonstrated outstanding ORR behavior in neutral media [
 <xref rid="B78-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">78</xref>]. Hu et al. investigated the ORR activity of Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C NPs embedded in graphitic layers in both alkaline and neutral media and confirmed their high catalytic activity and stability in both media [
 <xref rid="B79-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">79</xref>]. A similar type of cathode, N-incorporated Fe/Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C/CNTs derived from an MOF, was reported by Li et al. [
 <xref rid="B80-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">80</xref>], acting as a bifunctional catalyst for both the OER and ORR processes. As displayed in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f006">Figure 6</xref>a–f, the prepared hybrid catalyst exhibited enhanced ORR activity equivalent to that of Pt/C and high OER activity superior to that of Pt/C, making it a potential candidate for use in renewable energy technologies. Yang et al. [
 <xref rid="B81-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">81</xref>] later synthesized N-doped graphitic layers with an Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C/Fe catalyst to improve the ORR activity and explored it as a potential alternative for Pt-C in Zn-air batteries and fuel cells. Recently, an MOF-derived Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C@N-CNT catalyst also showed promising ORR activity in alkaline media [
 <xref rid="B82-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">82</xref>].
</p>
