<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Based on the observations above, few reports on Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C/Fe-based cathodes have focused on LOBs. Lai et al. [
 <xref rid="B83-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">83</xref>] prepared N-doped graphene@Fe/Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C (Fe-PNG) electrodes using a one-step carbonization process with an MIL-100 (Fe) MOF as an iron precursor. The prepared Fe-PNG cathode exhibited a porous 3D network morphology in which Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C/Fe NPs were evenly distributed on the outer layer of the graphene. This porous 3D nanostructure contained meso- and macro-pores that create space to accommodate the Li
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> produced during discharge, thus being beneficial for the migration of Li
 <sup>+</sup> and O
 <sub>2</sub>. The ORR and OER activity of the Fe-PNG electrode was monitored using linear sweep voltammetry analysis at 5 mVs
 <sup>−1</sup> (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f006">Figure 6</xref>g,h). As can be seen in the voltammogram, the Fe-PNG cathode showed excellent OER and ORR stability compared to the pristine Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C/Fe cathode. Their corresponding charge–discharge behaviors are demonstrated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f006">Figure 6</xref>i–l. The experiment was conducted in a potential window of 2.0 to 4.4 V (vs. Li/Li
 <sup>+</sup>), producing a charge and discharge capacity of 6850 and 7150 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup>
 <sub>carbon+catalyst</sub>, respectively (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f006">Figure 6</xref>j). The voltage profile of an LOB using Fe-PNG offered an outstanding capacity retention of 800 mAhg
 <sup>−1</sup>
 <sub>carbon+catalyst</sub> at 0.1 mAcm
 <sup>−2</sup> (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f006">Figure 6</xref>k) and the cycling stability was maintained for over 30 cycles at different current densities (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f006">Figure 6</xref>l). The same research group analyzed a similar type of electrode, Fe/Fe
 <sub>3</sub>C@graphatic carbon embedded with CNTs (Fe@NG-NCNT) derived from Prussian blue, and studied its potential application as a potential cathode in LOBs [
 <xref rid="B84-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">84</xref>]. The as-prepared Fe@NG-NCNT-based LOB delivered a maximum discharge capacity of 6966 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 0.1 mA cm
 <sup>−2</sup>. 
</p>
