<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par29">Besides the importance of biotic interactions affecting species’ persistence and distribution under climate change, we also show that their dispersal ability and available genetic variance (i.e., capacity to respond to selective pressures swiftly) influence their responses. When local conditions change and temperatures increase, species become increasingly maladapted at their initial locations and pre-adapted to temperatures at higher latitudes, driving a northward movement. Dispersal is therefore suggested as a mechanism that provides spatial insurance to species
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>
 </sup>, mitigating the negative impacts of climate change. However, a northward movement of initially warm-adapted species comes at the expense of the species located in the coldest regions which cannot disperse further
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>
 </sup>, a consequence of dispersal that has been shown in the previous studies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>. One might think that combining good dispersal ability with large genetic variance should temper this problem by allowing the northernmost species to adapt locally, and thus alleviate the negative impacts of increased temperatures better than each of these processes on their own. This expectation is also consistent with recent projections based on empirical data
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>
 </sup>. However, the projected extinctions, considering both dispersal and species’ ability to adapt, have been obtained without explicitly considering species interactions
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>
 </sup>. We show that large genetic variance combined with good dispersal ability result in a global biodiversity loss similar to when both dispersal ability and evolutionary rate are low. The reason, again, has to do with species interactions: the ability of individual species to disperse and adapt to new local conditions is of no use if they are prevented by other species from reaching the new locations. Similarly, cold-adapted species may be able to sustain in their current location with large genetic variance, but get outcompeted by the arrival of better adapted migrating species. The negative interaction between high dispersal and fast adaptation under climate change has also been demonstrated by Thompson and Fronhofer
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. However, in our case, we show that temperature-dependent competition reduces some of the negative impacts by allowing more local coexistence, albeit at the cost of reduced local growth rates.
</p>
