<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>While porous carbonaceous materials are highly useful for enhancing ORR activity, their OER activity remains low, leading to a high charging potential of over 4.5 V and the decomposition of the electrolyte, thus weakening the performance of LOBs. For this reason, noble metal catalysts such as Pt, Au, and RuO
 <sub>2</sub> have been employed in LOBs, but their high cost and poor specific capacity have restricted their use in commercial applications. Recently, 2D metal carbides have gained attention because of their advantageous properties, including the presence of several valence states, low resistivity, stronger electrochemical properties, and low cost. Due to the presence of reactive functional groups such as conductive metallic carbides and terminal transition metal atoms (Ti) on their surface, Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXenes are considered a promising candidate for various energy storage devices, including LIBs, sodium ion batteries, Li-S batteries, supercapacitors, and LOBs. They also have a specific surface morphology with ultra-high conductivity and malleable interlayer spaces. For these reasons, the lithium diffusion barrier of Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXenes (0.07 eV) is lower than that of commercial graphite electrodes (0.3 eV) due to the higher number of active sites, which in turn favors the rapid migration of lithium ions and enhanced charge–discharge characteristics. Recently, due to its high conductivity and hydrophilicity, Xue et al. [
 <xref rid="B118-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>] reported excellent ORR behavior with outstanding electrochemical activity for an Mn
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>-Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub> catalyst, while Zou et al. [
 <xref rid="B119-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">119</xref>] fabricated an MOF-derived Ni-Co mixed sulfide on a Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub> matrix and used it as an active catalyst for OER reactions in zinc–air batteries. Based on their exceptional ORR/OER catalytic properties, Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXenes with different active components such as TiO
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B120-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>], MoS
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B121-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>], SnS [
 <xref rid="B122-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>], Fe
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub> [
 <xref rid="B123-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">123</xref>], g-C
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub> [
 <xref rid="B124-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>], ZnO [
 <xref rid="B125-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>], and MnO
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B126-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">126</xref>] have been widely employed as cathodes in LIBs, SCs, and SIBs. However, Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXenes have rarely been reported as a cathode material for LOBs. Hence, this is an emerging topic that requires further attention. Some interesting composite cathodes based on Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXenes for LOBs are discussed below. 
</p>
