<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Over the past decade, Ni-based oxide materials have been increasingly incorporated into renewable storage devices due to their high catalytic activity and general abundance and availability. However, their poor intrinsic electrical conductivity and tendency to agglomerate have limited their commercial viability. To overcome these shortcomings, 2D layered materials such as graphene and reduced graphene oxides have been employed. Recently, NiO-Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXene catalysts were proposed as a low-cost electrocatalyst for LOBs by Li et al. [
 <xref rid="B128-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">128</xref>]. Different combinations of ultrasonically processed NiO-Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXene electrodes displayed excellent electrochemical behavior, with a superior initial discharge capacity of 13,350 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> @ 100 mA g
 <sup>−1</sup> (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f009">Figure 9</xref>a). However, as shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f009">Figure 9</xref>b, the capacity drastically fell to 5790 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> @ 500 mA g
 <sup>−1</sup>. Furthermore, it can be seen in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f009">Figure 9</xref>c–e that the capacity of the electrodes depended on the NiO loading mass, rising initially before subsequently declining. The NiO-Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>-2 electrode exhibited a minimum charge and discharge overpotential of 0.64 and 0.21 V, respectively. The same electrode offered an excellent capacity retention of over 90 cycles with the highest round-trip efficiency of 76.4%. This electrocatalytic activity was further supported by CV and EIS analyses (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f009">Figure 9</xref>f,g), confirming the rapid transport of lithium ions in LOBs (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f009">Figure 9</xref>h). In a similar manner, CoO-incorporated Ti
 <sub>3</sub>C
 <sub>2</sub>T
 <sub>x</sub> MXene nanosheets were recently synthesized using a hydrothermal process, producing excellent lithium oxygen storage performance with the highest initial cycle capacity at 16,220 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> and an extended life, of over 160 cycles [
 <xref rid="B129-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">129</xref>].
</p>
