<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A variety of materials have been investigated as alternative non-Pt catalysts for ORR, including oxides [
 <xref rid="B10-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], nitrides [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], sulfides [
 <xref rid="B14-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], carbides [
 <xref rid="B13-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>] of transition metals, metal–nitrogen–carbon catalysts (MNC) [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>], and metal-free catalysts [
 <xref rid="B20-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Various transition metal sulfides (TMS) of Mo, Fe, Co, Ni, and V have been explored as ORR catalysts due to their earth-abundance, low cost, and considerable activity [
 <xref rid="B14-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Nanostructured TMS have also been considered to further improve the ORR activity, due to increased number of active sites compared to their bulk counterparts. Another way to improve ORR activity is to combine TMS with carbon supports including carbon nanotube (CNT), graphene (GR), and amorphous carbon [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Carbon supports can provide high electrical conductivity and large surface area to disperse TMS, enhancing ORR activity [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="B23-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. They can also act as a growth mediator, reducing TMS particle aggregation. Heteroatom (N and S) doping into the carbon supports further increases active sites and hence ORR activity by modulating their electronic structure [
 <xref rid="B24-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B26-materials-14-02146" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Therefore, fabricating nanostructured TMS on heteroatom-doped carbon supports could offer a good approach to improve the ORR activity of TMS.
</p>
