<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The adaptation measures promote the adaptative capacity and reduce vulnerability to climate change effects, at the same time benefit from positive opportunities resulting from climate change. If the proper management of negative impacts was well designed and implemented the climate change may provide competitive advantages to early-adopting growers [
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B71-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">71</xref>]. According to [
 <xref rid="B55-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>], many studies have emphasized the potential for adaptation to reduce costs or increase gains associated with climate change. To create adaptation measures the future socio-economic scenarios and socio-economic scenarios must be considered, to provide a framework for adaptation decision-making for practitioners [
 <xref rid="B23-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. With these facts in mind, the efficiency of each measure is ruled by the local specificities and regional-to-local climate change signals, so it may be implemented on a large scale, at a European level, or on a small scale, as a cultivation company [
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. A decisive factor is the cost of operations that can determine the socio-economic viability and future stability of a designated crop and framework [
 <xref rid="B20-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Crop responses to hostile circumstances are powerfully tied to the implemented adaptation measures, such as a change in agricultural practices and crop management (changing in varieties, training systems, sowing dates, fertilizer, pesticide use, irrigation schedule, pruning, phytosanitary treatments, and harvesting) [
 <xref rid="B20-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. Therefore, the potential of the different adaptation strategies may prevent more dramatic changes in the suitability of a given region to grow crops. Adaptation strategies are divided into two main parameters, short-term and long-term, these measures depend mainly on the application time.
</p>
