<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p content-type="flushleft">Current efforts to curb global warming have been largely ineffective and future climate scenarios predict that global temperatures will rise from +2.6 to + 4.8 °C (and as much as +8 °C in the Arctic) by the end of the century (
 <xref rid="fig01" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1</xref>) (
 <xref rid="r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 <xref rid="r2" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). The scope of the ecological transformations that could occur beyond 2100 CE under prevailing emission rates is truly alarming (
 <xref rid="r4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). Planning a sustainable response to climate change requires us to identify the critical climate thresholds capable of disrupting social, economic, or political systems and culturally appropriate strategies for countering such disruptions. Natural climate archives (e.g., pollen data, sediment records, ice cores) and the paleontological and archaeological records offer unique opportunities for observing, measuring, and understanding how humans have responded to a wide range of climate events in the past, forming a sound basis for predicting how climate change could transform our lives in the future and offering a range of possible solutions (e.g., ref. 
 <xref rid="r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). The archaeological record is a valuable source of information that has been largely overlooked in climate research until comparatively recently, however (
 <xref rid="r6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>
 <xref rid="r7" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r8" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r9" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r10" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r11" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="bib134" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). As a result, the sensitivity of human systems to the full range of conditions predicted under different future climate scenarios remains largely untested. We contend that a multidisciplinary science of the past—an “archaeology of climate change”—provides a solid foundation for assessing the implications of climate change across cultures and helps design sustainable development strategies.
</p>
