<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0025">Several electrochemistry and electrochemical-engineering textbooks have been published over the past decades. Selecting the appropriate text(s) for a course depends as much on the educational history of the students as it does on the course content. Each textbook has valuable examples and homework problems at a range of difficulties spanning fundamental concepts and applications. These problems are useful independent of what book or books are used in a given electrochemistry course. The comprehensive electroanalytical approach taken by Bard and Faulkner prepares students to interpret many types of electroanalytical data and derive expressions for the polarization response of different electrodes, but can be challenging for beginning electrochemists because of its mathematical and analytical rigor (
 <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">Bard and Faulkner, 2000</xref>). Other texts offer an approach rooted in physical chemistry that is suited for scientists seeking to understand electrode kinetics and surface properties (
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">Eliaz and Gileadi, 2019</xref>; 
 <xref rid="bib38" ref-type="bibr">Schmickler and Santos, 2010</xref>; 
 <xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">Bockris and Reddy, 1973</xref>) or focusing on understanding voltammetry in detail (
 <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">Compton and Banks, 2018</xref>). Electrochemical engineering texts are available, which introduce fundamental electrochemistry concepts while covering a broad range of electrochemical devices such as batteries and fuel cells, and applications in corrosion and electrodeposition (
 <xref rid="bib17" ref-type="bibr">Fuller and Harb, 2018</xref>; 
 <xref rid="bib32" ref-type="bibr">Newman and Balsara, 2021</xref>). Fuller and Harb provides multiple chapters on the design of scaled up battery packs and fuel cell stacks, essential content for students entering the electrochemical industry. The recently updated text from Newman and Balsara includes a mathematically rigorous treatment of the physics required to build comprehensive models of electrochemical devices as well as new and expanded content on electrochemical impedance spectroscopy and Li-ion batteries.
</p>
