<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xml:lang="EN" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ao</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acsodf</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Omega</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2470-1343</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">8319934</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c01751</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Sodium/Lithium-Ion Transfer Reaction at the Interface
between Low-Crystallized Carbon Nanosphere Electrodes and Organic
Electrolytes</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath1"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="true">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-1103-3329</contrib-id><name><surname>Kondo</surname><given-names>Yasuyuki</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath2"><name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>Tomokazu</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath3"><name><surname>Yokoyama</surname><given-names>Yuko</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">&#x000a7;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath4"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="true">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4662-0996</contrib-id><name><surname>Miyahara</surname><given-names>Yuto</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath5"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="true">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5177-3570</contrib-id><name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>Kohei</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">&#x02225;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath6"><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>Takeshi</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">&#x02225;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>&#x02020;</label>Graduate
School of Engineering, <institution>Kyoto University</institution>, Nishikyo-ku, 615-8510 Kyoto, <country>Japan</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#x02021;</label>Graduate
School of Engineering, <institution>Nagoya University</institution>, Furo-cho, Chikusa-ku, 464-8603 Nagoya, <country>Japan</country></aff><aff id="aff3"><label>&#x000a7;</label>Office
of Society-Academia Collaboration for Innovation, <institution>Kyoto University</institution>, Nishikyo-ku, 615-8510 Kyoto, <country>Japan</country></aff><aff id="aff4"><label>&#x02225;</label>Element
Strategy Initiative for Catalysts &#x00026; Batteries, <institution>Kyoto University</institution>, Nishikyo-ku, 615-8246 Kyoto, <country>Japan</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>Email: <email>yasuyuki.kondo@elech.kuic.kyoto-u.ac.jp</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>13</day><month>07</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>27</day><month>07</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>6</volume><issue>29</issue><fpage>18737</fpage><lpage>18744</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>01</day><month>04</month><year>2021</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>05</day><month>07</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; 2021 The Authors. Published
by American
Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><copyright-holder>The Authors</copyright-holder><license><license-p>Permits non-commercial access and re-use, provided that author attribution and integrity are maintained; but does not permit creation of adaptations or other derivative works (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0013" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>Carbon nanosphere
(CNS) electrodes are the candidate of sodium-ion
battery (SIB) negative electrodes with small internal resistances
due to their small particle sizes. Electrochemical properties of low-crystallized
CNS electrodes in dilute and concentrated sodium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)
amide/ethylene carbonate + dimethyl carbonate (NaTFSA/EC + DMC) were
first investigated. From the cyclic voltammograms, both lithium ion
and sodium ion can reversibly insert into/from CNSs in all of the
electrolytes used here. The cycling stability of CNSs in concentrated
electrolytes was better than that in dilute electrolytes for the SIB
system. The interfacial charge-transfer resistances at the interface
between CNSs and organic electrolytes were evaluated using electrochemical
impedance spectroscopy. In the Nyquist plots, the semicircles at the
middle-frequency region were assigned to the parallel circuits of
charge-transfer resistances and capacitances. The interfacial sodium-ion
transfer resistances in concentrated organic electrolytes were much
smaller than those in dilute electrolytes, and the rate capability
of CNS electrodes in sodium salt-concentrated electrolytes might be
better than in dilute electrolytes, suggesting that CNSs with concentrated
electrolytes are the candidate of SIB negative electrode materials
with high rate capability. The calculated activation energies of interfacial
sodium-ion transfer were dependent on electrolyte compositions and
similar to those of interfacial lithium-ion transfer.</p></abstract><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Element Starategy Initiative for Catalysts &#x00026; Batteries, Kyoto University</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="doi">NA</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>NA</award-id></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>ao1c01751</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>ao1c01751</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Global energy consumption has continued to increase with the economic
growth of emerging countries, and the emission of greenhouse gases
has increased. To suppress greenhouse gas emissions without impeding
the economic growth of emerging countries, it is essential to shift
from the thermal power generation to the renewable energy generation.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref></sup> Because the power generation by renewable energies
usually fluctuates drastically, the large-scale power energy storage
is necessary. In addition, electric vehicles (EVs) are also paid much
attention owing to decreased emission of carbon dioxide. Currently,
the lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) are used for the electric motors
of EVs,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> and the next-generation LIBs with
high energy densities are developed.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref></sup> At the same
time, the increase of cost and the shortage of lithium sources are
predicted after LIBs are widely applied to these large-scale applications.
Then, sodium-ion batteries (SIBs) are attracting attention as substitutes
for LIBs because of abundant sodium resources.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref></sup> The configuration of SIBs is originated from the concept that the
lithium ion in the LIBs is replaced with the sodium ion. Sodium ion
shuttles between positive electrodes and negative electrodes in SIBs
in the same manner as in LIBs. The candidates of negative electrode
materials of SIBs are carbonaceous materials, titanium-based materials,
phosphorus, or tin.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref></sup> Among these materials,
carbonaceous materials are the most attractive as they are commercialized
for LIBs. The most famous candidate for carbon negative electrode
material in SIBs is amorphous carbon because the reactivity of sodium
ion and graphitic materials is anomalously small and sodium ion cannot
insert into graphite but inserts deeply into amorphous carbon.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup></p><p>As for the batteries of EVs, high rate
capability is also desired.
Carbon nanosphere (CNS) is expected as the candidate for carbon negative
electrode materials with high rate capability and good cycling stability
because CNS has small particle sizes, short diffusion distances, and
the basal planes covering the surface.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref></sup> To enhance
the rate capability of electrode materials, the resistance of electron
transfer in composite electrodes, the resistance of ion diffusion
in composite electrodes, the resistance of ion diffusion inside the
electrode material, and the resistance of interfacial ion transfer
should be considered.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref></sup> To analyze each
resistance inside batteries, electrochemical alternating current impedance
spectroscopy is the specific tool because processes with different
relaxation times can be divided by impedance spectroscopy.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref></sup> In LIBs, the interfacial lithium-ion transfer
reaction at the interface between electrodes and electrolytes has
been studied using electrochemical impedance spectroscopy.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> Based on these results, the interfacial lithium-ion transfer is
especially the significant rate-determining step. The interfacial
sodium-ion transfer at the interface between electrodes and electrolytes
is also expected to be the significant step. However, the kinetic
properties of interfacial sodium-ion transfer at the interface between
the CNS electrode and electrolyte are still not fully understood.</p><p>The kinetics of lithium-ion transfer at the interface between graphite
negative electrodes and electrolyte solutions seemed to be influenced
by the interaction between lithium ions and solvents, counteranions,
or solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) in common organic electrolyte
solutions, organic electrolyte solutions with SEI-forming additives
like vinylene carbonate or fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC), and ionic
liquid-based electrolyte solutions, respectively.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup> As for ordinal
ethylene carbonate (EC)-based electrolyte solutions, the rate-determining
process in the interfacial lithium-ion transfer seemed to be the desolvation
process of lithium ions.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> On the other
hand, the kinetics of sodium-ion transfer at the interface between
CNS electrodes and electrolyte solutions is complicated. In the previous
study, the interaction between sodium ions and organic solvents was
expected to be weaker than the interaction between lithium ions and
solvents.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> On the contrary, the activation
energies of the interfacial sodium-ion transfer at the interface between
graphitized CNS electrodes and electrolyte solutions were as large
as those of interfacial lithium-ion transfer.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> In addition, the activation energies were dependent on the composition
of electrolyte solutions.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> However, the
interfacial sodium-ion transfer resistances of CNS electrodes measured
in the previous study were much larger than the interfacial lithium-ion
transfer resistances even if amorphous CNS electrodes, which seemed
to have many reactive sites, were used with FEC-based electrolytes.
Therefore, discovering the proper electrolytes to decrease the sodium-ion
transfer resistances of amorphous CNS electrodes is still necessary.</p><p>In this study, the interfacial sodium-ion transfer resistances
and the activation energies of sodium-ion transfer reaction at the
interface between amorphous CNS electrodes and EC-based organic electrolyte
solutions were measured by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy.
The EC-based electrolyte with ordinal concentration was first used
because it is the most common organic electrolyte. The EC-based electrolyte
with high salt concentration was also used to make SEI more stable
and prevent degradation, as reported in previous studies.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> As a comparison, the interfacial lithium-ion transfer reaction at
the interface between amorphous CNS electrodes and organic electrolyte
solutions was also investigated.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2</label><title>Results
and Discussion</title><sec id="sec2.1"><label>2.1</label><title>Structural Characterization
of CNS-1100</title><p>First, the structure of CNS-1100 (CNS treated
at 1100 &#x000b0;C)
was investigated. <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref> shows the X-ray diffraction (XRD) pattern of CNS-1100. The
XRD pattern of CNS-1100 did not show the (002) line derived from the
graphitic structure.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup><xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref> shows the Raman spectrum of
CNS-1100 electrodes. The Raman spectrum showed a large D-band<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref></sup> at around 1350 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> and a G-band<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref></sup> at around 1585 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. These
results indicated that CNS-1100 had an amorphous and low graphitized
structure in both bulk and surface regions, as previously reported.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup><xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref> shows the
scanning electron microscopy (SEM) image of CNS-1100 composite electrodes.
CNS-1100 had a spherical shape indicating the coverage by bent basal
planes derived from low graphitization degree, and the lithium ion
or sodium ion intercalates into CNS-1100 from the surface of CNS.
The solution structures of organic electrolytes were also investigated
using Raman spectroscopy. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref> shows the Raman spectra of 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> lithium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl) amide/ethylene carbonate +
dimethyl carbonate (LiTFSA/EC + DMC) and 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> sodium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl) amide/EC + DMC (NaTFSA/EC +
DMC). The peaks derived from C=O bending modes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> of EC and CF<sub>3</sub> bending modes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref></sup> of the TFSA anion appeared at around 720 and 745 cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, respectively. These peaks shifted at a higher Raman
shift in concentrated electrolytes by the interaction with lithium
or sodium ion, indicating that most of the lithium or sodium ions
were coordinated with solvents in dilute electrolytes or anions in
concentrated electrolytes.</p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>XRD pattern of the CNS-1100 electrode.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0002" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Raman spectrum of the CNS-1100 electrode.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0003" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>SEM image of the CNS-1100 electrode.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0004" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Raman
spectra of (a) 0.9 and (b) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC
+ DMC and (c) 0.9 and (d) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC +
DMC.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0005" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><label>2.2</label><title>Lithium-Ion
Transfer Reaction at the Interface
between CNS Composite Electrodes/Organic Electrolyte Solutions</title><p>Electrochemical properties of CNS-1100 composite electrodes in electrolytes
containing lithium ions were investigated. <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref> shows the CVs of 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> CNS-1100 composite electrodes in LiTFSA/EC + DMC. The irreversible
currents were observed only in the 1st cycle, suggesting the formation
of SEI on CNS electrodes in all of the electrolytes. The redox peaks
also appeared in all of the electrolytes and were assigned to the
reversible lithium-ion insertion into/from CNS-1100.</p><fig id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Cyclic voltammograms
of the CNS-1100 composite electrode in (a)
0.9 and (b) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol)
at a scan rate of 0.1 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0006" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref> shows the
Nyquist plots of the CNS-1100 composite electrode in 0.9 and 4 mol
kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol). Two semicircles
appeared at the high-frequency and the middle-frequency regions in
0.9 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol). The semicircles
at the high-frequency region or at the middle-frequency region were
assigned to the parallel circuits of capacitances and SEI resistances
or charge-transfer resistances, respectively, because only the semicircle
at the high frequency was observed at open-circuit potential (OCV)
after cyclic voltammetry (CV). Only one semicircle was observed at
the middle-frequency region in 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC
+ DMC (1:1 by vol). As for the concentrated electrolytes, this semicircle
was assigned to the charge-transfer resistance. The SEI resistance
seemed to be negligibly small in the concentrated electrolyte because
the SEI on CNS electrodes in this concentrated electrolyte might have
good passivation ability than in 0.9 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC
+ DMC (1:1 by vol), and the SEI formation reaction might finish earlier
and the thickness of SEI in the concentrated electrolyte might be
thinner than in the dilute electrolyte, as previously reported for
concentrated carbonate-based electrolytes.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Nyquist
plots of CNS-1100 composite electrodes in (a) 0.9 and (b)
4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol) and equivalent
circuits used for fitting for CNS-1100 electrodes in (c) 0.9 and (d)
4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0007" id="gr6" position="float"/></fig><p>The activation energies of the interfacial lithium-ion transfer
at the interface between CNS and electrolyte solutions were measured.
The logarithmic reciprocal of charge-transfer resistances was plotted
against the reciprocal of temperature. <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref> shows the temperature dependence of charge-transfer
reactions of CNS-1100 composite electrodes in 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol). The activation energy
was calculated using the following Arrhenius equation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref></sup><disp-formula id="eq1"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_m001" position="anchor"/><label>1</label></disp-formula>where <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> is the
charge-transfer resistance, <italic>A</italic> is the prefrequency
factor, <italic>E</italic><sub>a</sub> is the activation energy, <italic>R</italic> is the gas constant, and <italic>T</italic> is the absolute
temperature. The charge-transfer resistances were estimated basically
by fitting with the equivalent circuit shown in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>c (<italic>R</italic><sub>Sol</sub> is the
resistance of electrolyte conductivity and <italic>R</italic><sub>SEI</sub> is SEI resistance). When the SEI resistance was negligible,
the charge-transfer resistances were estimated using the equivalent
circuit shown in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>d. As a result, the activation energy in 0.9 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol) was 56 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>,
which was near to the reported values for highly oriented pyrolytic
graphite (HOPG) and glassy carbon electrodes.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref></sup> In the previous reports regarding the lithium-ion transfer resistances
of carbon negative electrodes, the differences in activation energies
of charge-transfer resistances measured in different electrolytes
corresponded to the differences of interaction between lithium ions
and solvents by calculating the heats of solvating reaction, and the
rate-determining step was considered to be the final desolvation process.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref></sup> Based on the previous reports,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref></sup> solvents seem to be difficult to cointercalate into the
bulk of low-crystallized carbons and desolvation process should be
necessary for lithium-ion insertion into CNS-1100. Hence, the rate-determining
step in the lithium-ion transfer reaction between the CNS electrode
and the dilute electrolyte seemed to be the final desolvation process
of EC. The activation energy in 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC
+ DMC (1:1 by vol) was 75 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> and very large.
We speculated that the kinetics of the interfacial lithium-ion transfer
reaction in concentrated electrolytes is controlled by the interaction
between the lithium ion and anion, which might be stronger than the
interaction between lithium ions and neutral solvents. These results
were consistent with the previous reports of graphitized CNS.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Temperature dependence of charge-transfer resistances
of CNS-1100
composite electrodes in (a) 0.9 and (b) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0008" id="gr7" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><label>2.3</label><title>Sodium-Ion Transfer Reaction at the Interface
between CNS Composite Electrodes/Organic Electrolyte Solutions</title><p><xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref> shows the
CVs of CNS-1100 composite electrodes in 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol). The irreversible currents were observed
in all of the electrolytes, and most of the irreversible currents
disappeared from the 2nd cycle, indicating the formation of SEI on
CNS electrodes in the same manner of the lithium-ion system. The redox
peaks also appeared in all of the electrolytes and were assigned to
the reversible sodium-ion insertion into/from CNS-1100. However, redox
peaks in the dilute EC-based electrolyte decreased during cycling.
This seemed to be because the SEI in the SIB system is easier to dissolve
into electrolytes than that in the LIB system.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref></sup> CNS has a large surface area owing to the small particle
size, and the dissolution of SEI and degradation due to continuous
electrolyte decomposition might be much severe. On the other hand,
the redox peaks in concentrated electrolytes did not decrease during
cycling, suggesting that the stability of SEI in concentrated electrolytes
is the best. These results might be because the dissolution of SEI
and the continuous electrolyte decomposition were the most minimized
by the saturation of the high-salt-concentration electrolyte.</p><fig id="fig8" position="float"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>Cyclic voltammograms
of CNS-1100 composite electrodes in (a) 0.9
and (b) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol)
at a scan rate of 0.1 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0009" id="gr8" position="float"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig9" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig9" ref-type="fig">9</xref></xref> shows the
Nyquist plots of the CNS-1100 composite electrode in 0.9 and 4 mol
kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol). At least one
semicircle was observed at the middle-frequency region in all of the
electrolytes. This semicircle at the middle-frequency region was assigned
to the parallel circuits of charge-transfer resistances and capacitances
like the cases of previous literatures.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> The SEI resistance
seemed to be negligible in the concentrated electrolytes because the
amounts of SEI formation might also be minimized due to the best stability
of SEI. In addition, only the interfacial sodium-ion transfer resistances
in concentrated electrolytes were as small as the interfacial lithium-ion
transfer resistances. The origin of the small interfacial resistance
in the concentrated electrolyte might be derived from the high stability
of SEI to prevent degradation of electrodes and large activity of
sodium ion in concentrated electrolytes, which leads to large prefrequency
factors. These results indicated that CNS-1100 negative electrodes
in concentrated electrolytes can be the candidate of negative electrodes
with high rate capability in SIBs.</p><fig id="fig9" position="float"><label>Figure 9</label><caption><p>Nyquist plots of CNS-1100 composite electrodes
in (a) 0.9 and (b)
4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0010" id="gr9" position="float"/></fig><p>The activation energies of the interfacial sodium-ion transfer
at the interface between amorphous CNS and electrolyte solutions were
evaluated in the same manner as that of the lithium system. <xref rid="fig10" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig10" ref-type="fig">10</xref></xref> shows the temperature
dependence of charge-transfer reactions of CNS-1100 composite electrodes
in 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol).
The activation energy in 0.9 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC
+ DMC (1:1 by vol) was 56&#x02013;64 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. On
the other hand, the activation energy in 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol) was 68&#x02013;69 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> and very large. These values of activation energies were close to
those of graphitized CNS electrodes.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> Hence,
the electrolyte dependency of activation energies of interfacial sodium-ion
transfer seemed to be universal for carbonaceous electrodes independent
of the graphitization degree. The activation energies of the interfacial
sodium-ion transfer might be dependent on the interaction between
sodium ions and solvents or anions. However, the rate-determining
step of the interfacial sodium-ion transfer might not be the simple
desolvation process but the multiple process because these values
of activation energies of interfacial sodium-ion transfer were much
larger than the expected values of activation energies decided by
the simple desolvation process based on the weak Lewis acidity of
sodium ion. Considering the large activation energies of sodium-ion
transfer resistances in concentrated electrolytes, decreasing the
activation energies is desired in the future to decrease the interfacial
resistances due to changing the salt anions and so forth.</p><fig id="fig10" position="float"><label>Figure 10</label><caption><p>Temperature
dependence of charge-transfer resistances of CNS-1100
composite electrodes in (a) 0.9 and (b) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0011" id="gr10" position="float"/></fig><p>Finally, <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">11</xref></xref> shows the charge&#x02013;discharge curves of CNS-1100 and acetylene
black (AB) composite electrodes in 0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1 by vol). At the first cycle, the irreversible
capacity of the CNS electrode in the dilute electrolyte was larger
than that in the concentrated electrolyte, indicating that the passivation
ability of SEI in the concentrated electrolyte was better than in
the dilute electrolyte like the case of the cyclic voltammograms.
The maximum reversible capacity of CNS-1100 electrodes was around
145 mAh g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. To evaluate the rate capability of
CNS-1100 electrodes in both electrolytes, the reversible capacities
were plotted against the cycling number, as shown in <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">11</xref></xref>c. Based on the result in <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">11</xref></xref>c, the rate capability
of CNS-1100 electrodes in the concentrated electrolyte under medium
current densities was better than in the dilute electrolyte. These
results also indicated that internal resistances of CNS-1100 electrodes
in the concentrated electrolyte can be smaller than in the dilute
electrolyte. Under the largest current densities, capacity loss in
the concentrated electrolyte was almost the same as in the dilute
electrolyte. This seemed to be because IR drops in the concentrated
electrolyte were larger than in the dilute electrolyte due to the
smaller electrolyte conductivity and so on. Hence, decreasing the
activation energies of charge-transfer resistances and increasing
electrolyte conductivities in concentrated electrolyte systems are
desired to fabricate the high-rate sodium-ion battery in the future.</p><fig id="fig11" position="float"><label>Figure 11</label><caption><p>Charge&#x02013;discharge
curves of CNS-1100 and AB composite electrodes
in (a) 0.9 and (b) 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC (1:1
by vol), and (c) reversible capacities plotted against the cycle number
in both electrolytes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao1c01751_0012" id="gr11" position="float"/></fig></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><label>3</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>The interfacial sodium-ion transfer reaction at the interface between
the CNS-1100 electrode and electrolyte solutions was investigated
with comparison to the lithium-ion transfer reaction. From the cyclic
voltammograms, both lithium ion and sodium ion can reversibly insert
into/from CNS-1100 in all of the electrolytes. In the Nyquist plots,
the semicircles at the high-frequency region and the middle-frequency
region were assigned to the SEI resistance and the charge-transfer
resistance, respectively. The activation energies of both interfacial
lithium-ion and sodium-ion transfer resistances were also measured.
The values of activation energies of both interfacial lithium-ion
and sodium-ion transfer resistances were dependent on the composition
of electrolytes. In addition, these values of the activation energies
for amorphous CNS electrodes were close to those for graphitized CNS
electrodes, suggesting that the activation energies of the interfacial
sodium-ion transfer might be independent of the graphitization degree.
The charge&#x02013;discharge curves indicated the better rate capability
of CNS-1100 and AB electrodes in sodium salt-concentrated electrolytes
than in dilute electrolytes. To fabricate the SIBs with high rate
capability, applying nanocarbonaceous negative electrodes with concentrated
organic electrolyte solutions is one of effective approaches.</p></sec><sec id="sec4"><label>4</label><title>Experimental Section</title><p>Electrochemical measurements were
carried out using a three-electrode
cell. A CNS-1100 composite electrode (CNS-1100 (700&#x02013;800 nm,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> Tokai Carbon Co., Ltd.)/poly(vinylidene difluoride) (PVdF) = 80:20
wt %) was used as a working electrode. CNS-1100 electrodes used in
cyclic voltammetry and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy did
not contain conductive carbons to exclude the interfacial reaction
of conductive carbons. For charge&#x02013;discharge measurements, the
CNS-1100 and AB composite electrodes (CNS-1100/AB (Denka)/PVdF = 78:2:20
wt %) were used. The Ag/Ag<sup>+</sup> electrode (silver wire immersed
into EC + DMC (1:1 by vol) (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) mixture containing
0.2 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> of NaTFSA (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.)
and 0.04 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> of silver trifluoromethanesulfonate
(Sigma-Aldrich)) was used as a reference electrode, and a natural
graphite composite electrode (natural graphite/PVdF = 90:10 wt %)
was used as a counter electrode. Electrolyte solutions were EC + DMC
(1:1 by vol) (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) mixture containing 0.9 and
4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> LiTFSA (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) or
NaTFSA. In this study, TFSA salts with high solubility were used to
avoid the evolution of HF. The potential of the silver reference electrode
was calibrated by measuring the redox potential of ferrocene in each
electrolyte containing 3 mmol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> of ferrocene
(Alfa Aesar). Hereafter, all potentials are referred to as Fc/Fc<sup>+</sup>; &#x02212;2.77 and &#x02212;2.74 V vs Fc/Fc<sup>+</sup> in
0.9 and 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC, respectively,
were near to 0.2 V vs Na/Na<sup>+</sup>. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) was
conducted between open-circuit potential (OCV) and various potentials,
and the scan rate was set at 0.1 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. Electrochemical
impedance spectroscopy was carried out with an ac amplitude of 10
mV in a frequency range of 100 kHz to 10 mHz at temperatures ranging
from 30 to 10 &#x000b0;C. Charge&#x02013;discharge measurements were conducted
between OCV and &#x02212;2.98 or &#x02212;2.925 V vs Fc/Fc<sup>+</sup> in 0.9 or 4 mol kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC, respectively,
and the current densities were set between 25 and 200 mA g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. The cells were assembled in an Ar-filled glovebox. All electrochemical
measurements were carried out using HSV-100 (HOKUTO-DENKO) and Solartron1470E+1400A
(Solartron Analytical). SEM, XRD measurements, and Raman spectroscopy
were used for structural characterization of CNS-1100 electrodes and
electrolyte solutions using S-3000H (Hitachi High-Tech Fielding Corp.),
RINT2200 (RIGAKU), and LabRAM HR (HORIBA).</p></sec></body><back><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d7e746-autogenerated"><p>The authors declare
no
competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>This work was partially supported by the Element Strategy
Initiative for Catalysts &#x00026; Batteries (ESICB), Kyoto University.</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Doughty</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>P. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Skhil</surname><given-names>A. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Clark</surname><given-names>N. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Boyes</surname><given-names>J. D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Batteries
for large-scale stationary electrical energy storage</article-title>. <source>Electrochem. Soc. Interface</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>49</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>53</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.F05103if</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hua</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ouyand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A review on the key
issues for lithium-ion battery management in electric vehicles</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>226</volume>, <fpage>272</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>282</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2012.10.060</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fei</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ci</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Green, scalable, and
controllable fabrication of nanoporous silicon
from commercial alloy precursors for high-energy lithium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Nano</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>12</volume>, <fpage>4993</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5002</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsnano.8b02219</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29683640</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>An</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Nonflammable fluorinated carbonate
electrolyte with high salt-to-solvent ratios enables stable silicon-based
anode for next-generation lithium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>23229</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>23235</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b05570</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31252474</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kubota</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dahbi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Komaba</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Research development
on sodium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>Chem. Rev.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>114</volume>, <fpage>11636</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11682</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr500192f</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25390643</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Dahbi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kubota</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tokiwa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Komaba</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Negative electrodes
for Na-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>16</volume>, <fpage>15007</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>15028</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c4cp00826j</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24894102</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Komaba</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ishikawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yabuuchi</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ozeki</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nakayama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogata</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gotoh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fujiwara</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrochemical
Na insertion and solid electrolyte interphase for hard-carbon electrodes
and application to Na-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>Adv. Funct.
Mater.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>3859</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3867</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.201100854</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Yoshizawa</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tanaike</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hatori</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yoshikawa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kondo</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>TEM and electron tomography
studies
of carbon nanospheres for lithium secondary batteries</article-title>. <source>Carbon</source>
<year>2006</year>, <volume>44</volume>, <fpage>2558</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2564</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2006.05.041</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Maruyama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yoshizawa</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium-ion intercalation and deintercalation behavior of graphitized
carbon nanospheres</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>1128</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1137</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7TA07902H</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Ogihara</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kawauchi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Okuda</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Itou</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Takeuchi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ukyo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Theoretical and experimental analysis of porous electrodes for lithium-ion
batteries by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy using a symmetric
cell</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>159</volume>, <fpage>A1034</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>A1039</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.057207jes</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Amemiya</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fujishima</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. Variety of
transfer function analysis</article-title>. <source>Denki Kagaku</source>
<year>1993</year>, <volume>61</volume>, <fpage>290</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>294</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5796/electrochemistry.61.290</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sagane</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Toda</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sugie</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Ion-solvent
interaction
for lithium-ion transfer at the interface between carbonaceous thin-film
electrode and electrolyte</article-title>. <source>TANSO</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>2010</volume>, <fpage>188</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>191</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7209/tanso.2010.188</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Ishihara</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium-ion transfer
at the interface between high potential negative electrodes and ionic
liquids</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>161</volume>, <fpage>A1939</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>A1942</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.1111412jes</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Iriyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Kinetics of
lithium
ion transfer at the interface between graphite and liquid electrolytes:
effects of solvent and surface film</article-title>. <source>Langmuir</source>
<year>2009</year>, <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>12766</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>12770</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/la901829v</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19856995</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sagane</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ohtsuka</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Iriyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium-ion
transfer at the interface between lithium-ion conductive ceramic electrolyte
and liquid electrolyte-a key to enhancing the rate capability of lithium-ion
batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>152</volume>, <fpage>A2151</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>A2154</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.2042907</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Sagane</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Sodium-ion transfer at the interface between ceramic
and organic electrolytes</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>195</volume>, <fpage>7466</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7470</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2010.04.054</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Kondo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yokoyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyahara</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Kinetic properties
of sodium-ion transfer at the interface between
graphitic materials and organic electrolyte solutions</article-title>. <source>J. Appl. Electrochem.</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>51</volume>, <fpage>629</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>638</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10800-020-01523-z</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Takada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sodeyama</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tateyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hirata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kawase</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Unusual passivation
ability of superconcentrated electrolytes toward hard carbon negative
electrodes in sodium-ion batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl.
Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>9</volume>, <fpage>33802</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>33809</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b08414</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28766928</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Kondo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyahara</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Sodium-ion
intercalation behavior of graphitized carbon nanospheres covered with
basal plane</article-title>. <source>Chem. Lett.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>48</volume>, <fpage>799</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>801</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1246/cl.190111</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>H.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fukutsuka</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>In situ Raman investigation
of electrolyte solutions in the vicinity of graphite negative electrodes</article-title>. <source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>18</volume>, <fpage>27486</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>27492</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6CP05489G</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27711581</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Castriota</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Caruso</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Agostino</surname><given-names>R. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cazzanelli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Henderson</surname><given-names>W. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Passerini</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Raman investigation of the ionic
liquid N-methyl-N-propylpyrrolidinium bis(trifluoromethanesulfonyl)imide
and its mixture with LiN(SO<sub>2</sub>CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub></article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. A</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>109</volume>, <fpage>92</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>96</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp046030w</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16839092</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit22"><name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Inaba</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Iriyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Interfacial
reactions between graphite electrodes and propylene carbonate-based
solutions: Electrolyte-concentration dependence of electrochemical
lithium intercalation reaction</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2008</year>, <volume>175</volume>, <fpage>540</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>546</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2007.08.065</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fukuda</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Iriyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Solvated Li-ion transfer
at interface between graphite and electrolyte</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2004</year>, <volume>151</volume>, <fpage>A1120</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>A1123</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.1763141</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Doi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Iriyama</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ogumi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium-ion transfer
at an electrolyte/heat-treated nongraphitizable carbon electrode interface</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>152</volume>, <fpage>A1521</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>A1525</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.1943668</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>Inagaki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tanaike</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Determining factors
for the intercalation into carbon
materials from organic solutions</article-title>. <source>Carbon</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>39</volume>, <fpage>1083</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1090</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0008-6223(00)00233-5</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Mogensen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Brandell</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Younesi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Solubility
of the solid electrolyte
interphase (SEI) in sodium ion batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS
Energy Lett.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>1173</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1178</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.6b00491</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Hasegawa</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kanamori</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kannari</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ozaki</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nakanishi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Studies on electrochemical
sodium storage into hard carbons with
binder-free monolithic electrodes</article-title>. <source>J. Power
Sources</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>318</volume>, <fpage>41</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>48</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.04.013</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>