<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Worldwide, the chestnut tree (
 <italic>Castanea</italic> spp., Fagaceae family) is an ecologically, economically, and culturally important resource [
 <xref rid="B1-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. Chestnut trees are reproduced using seedlings or vegetative propagation, namely rooted cuttings [
 <xref rid="B2-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. These trees can be found in natural and semi-natural forest stands, or managed stands, including traditional orchards and modern plantations [
 <xref rid="B3-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. They are cultivated for the importance of their fruit and wood. The fruit is used in the preparations of many recipes due to its high nutritional value and can be eaten in two different ways: consumption of fresh fruits or processed products [
 <xref rid="B5-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. In fresh conditions, these fruits are characterized by a restricted shelf-life, owed to their high-water activity and starch content [
 <xref rid="B6-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. These fruits reveal different types, flavors, or sweetness depending on the variety. For example, the fruits from 
 <italic>Castanea sativa</italic> Portuguese cultivar ‘Judia’ have around 50–80 fruits kg
 <sup>−1</sup> [
 <xref rid="B7-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Wood is also a chestnut by-product, it is strong but relatively light, having a high density, widely used in the construction of buildings and furniture [
 <xref rid="B5-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Chestnut woods are rich in water-soluble extract. These conditions are negatively influenced when woods are exposed to air pollutants, promoting wood discoloration [
 <xref rid="B11-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. In addition, over the past few decades, the production of edible mushrooms grown underneath chestnut trees was promoted [
 <xref rid="B12-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>].
</p>
