<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Chestnut ecosystems are currently threatened by different stress factors (natural or anthropogenic) such as climate change, abandonment of traditional orchards, wildfire, and an increased incidence of pests and diseases [
 <xref rid="B5-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Climate is considered one of the main drivers of biodiversity and ecosystem change. With climate change, modifications in crop microclimate conditions are projected to occur, with implications in the suitability of a given region to grow a specific crop [
 <xref rid="B3-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Climate change may modify the physiological and reproductive cycles of species, like anticipating or delaying phenological timings, with implications on yields and fruit quality characteristics. As an illustration, leaf expansion and seed enlargement phases during histogenesis are strongly forced by thermal accumulation. The patterns of pests and diseases associated with chestnuts may also shift with climate change [
 <xref rid="B1-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Moreover, the quality parameters and chemical composition of chestnuts are largely influenced by climate conditions [
 <xref rid="B21-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. According to [
 <xref rid="B22-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>], tree growth is primarily regulated by temperature and precipitation and, secondarily, by soil moisture, solar radiation, and air humidity. Growth is closely linked to climate parameters, thus hinting at its high sensitivity to climate conditions and vulnerability under changing climates. Some climate change facts suggest warmer temperatures and longer growing seasons in the future, accompanied by more frequent and intense extreme weather conditions, such as severe rainfall events, droughts, or heatwaves [
 <xref rid="B9-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B23-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. The aforementioned future conditions cause damages to crop in the upcoming decades [
 <xref rid="B25-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. For the chestnut ecosystems in the Iberian Peninsula, climate change may represent a major threat, leading to significant losses of goods and ecosystem services [
 <xref rid="B3-plants-10-01463" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>].
</p>
