<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Electrochemical measurements were carried out using a three-electrode cell. A CNS-1100 composite electrode (CNS-1100 (700–800 nm,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> Tokai Carbon Co., Ltd.)/poly(vinylidene difluoride) (PVdF) = 80:20 wt %) was used as a working electrode. CNS-1100 electrodes used in cyclic voltammetry and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy did not contain conductive carbons to exclude the interfacial reaction of conductive carbons. For charge–discharge measurements, the CNS-1100 and AB composite electrodes (CNS-1100/AB (Denka)/PVdF = 78:2:20 wt %) were used. The Ag/Ag
 <sup>+</sup> electrode (silver wire immersed into EC + DMC (1:1 by vol) (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) mixture containing 0.2 mol kg
 <sup>–1</sup> of NaTFSA (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) and 0.04 mol kg
 <sup>–1</sup> of silver trifluoromethanesulfonate (Sigma-Aldrich)) was used as a reference electrode, and a natural graphite composite electrode (natural graphite/PVdF = 90:10 wt %) was used as a counter electrode. Electrolyte solutions were EC + DMC (1:1 by vol) (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) mixture containing 0.9 and 4 mol kg
 <sup>–1</sup> LiTFSA (Kishida Chemical Co., Ltd.) or NaTFSA. In this study, TFSA salts with high solubility were used to avoid the evolution of HF. The potential of the silver reference electrode was calibrated by measuring the redox potential of ferrocene in each electrolyte containing 3 mmol kg
 <sup>–1</sup> of ferrocene (Alfa Aesar). Hereafter, all potentials are referred to as Fc/Fc
 <sup>+</sup>; −2.77 and −2.74 V vs Fc/Fc
 <sup>+</sup> in 0.9 and 4 mol kg
 <sup>–1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC, respectively, were near to 0.2 V vs Na/Na
 <sup>+</sup>. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) was conducted between open-circuit potential (OCV) and various potentials, and the scan rate was set at 0.1 mV s
 <sup>–1</sup>. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy was carried out with an ac amplitude of 10 mV in a frequency range of 100 kHz to 10 mHz at temperatures ranging from 30 to 10 °C. Charge–discharge measurements were conducted between OCV and −2.98 or −2.925 V vs Fc/Fc
 <sup>+</sup> in 0.9 or 4 mol kg
 <sup>–1</sup> NaTFSA/EC + DMC, respectively, and the current densities were set between 25 and 200 mA g
 <sup>–1</sup>. The cells were assembled in an Ar-filled glovebox. All electrochemical measurements were carried out using HSV-100 (HOKUTO-DENKO) and Solartron1470E+1400A (Solartron Analytical). SEM, XRD measurements, and Raman spectroscopy were used for structural characterization of CNS-1100 electrodes and electrolyte solutions using S-3000H (Hitachi High-Tech Fielding Corp.), RINT2200 (RIGAKU), and LabRAM HR (HORIBA).
</p>
