<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par29">Unlike conventional syntheses of single-metal-atom-doped carbon, which require high annealing temperatures for complete carbonization, plasma engineering allows direct carbonization in a precursor solution in an organic solvent (e.g., benzene) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>] or in a solution containing nitrogen and carbon (e.g., pyridine, phenylamine) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>] at ambient temperature and pressure. Specifically, the generation of NC can be achieved via rapid C–N and/or C–C integration during plasma discharge and the related chemical reactions [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. For instance, B–N double-site-doped carbon was prepared by supplementing the precursors with boric acid and/or phenylboronic acid [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. The mechanisms of the in situ syntheses of heteroatom-doped carbons via plasma engineering have been thoroughly reviewed by Li et al. [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]. More importantly, Morishita et al. reported that the rate of carbon production from benzene derivatives (e.g., benzene and aniline) via plasma synthesis (1–10 mg min
 <sup>−1</sup>) substantially exceeds that of pyrolytic methods [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]. Thus, it was hypothesized that plasma engineering can be used to effectively prepare single-atom-doped catalysts from aniline and metal phthalocyanines. During plasma engineering, direct carbonization proceeds by the combination of CN and C
 <sub>2</sub> radicals with the solution precursor at the gas/liquid interface. Since the metal phthalocyanine has high chemical stability and is only present in small amount in the solution phase, the molecular structure is expected to maintain its planar metal-N
 <sub>4</sub> coordination during the fast formation of carbon materials. Also, the solubility of metal phthalocyanines is very low in pure aniline, which might result in easy agglomeration. An ultrasonic homogenizer uses the dispersion effect of ultrasonic waves in the liquid to cause cavitation of the liquid, which is useful in mixing, emulsifying, dispersing, and deagglomeration [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study to combine plasma engineering with ultrasonication-assisted homogenization to prevent agglomeration during the synthesis and to successfully dope molecular M-N
 <sub>4</sub> atomically within the NC matrix with a high production rate of ~ 10 mg min
 <sup>−1</sup>.
</p>
