<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Accelerating natural selection in response to current and future environmental stressors may be particularly important for the survival of species that have suffered severe range reductions, a common occurrence amongst Australian endemics. Whilst reintroduction programs are becoming common, few take into account future adaptability or, indeed, adaptive capacity of source populations [
 <xref rid="B140-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">140</xref>,
 <xref rid="B158-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">158</xref>,
 <xref rid="B159-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">159</xref>]. Conservation practitioners now need to think seriously about the long-term viability of the populations they are managing under climate change projections. Actions could include maximising evolutionary potential by working towards increased population size, genetic variation, and gene flow in managed populations [
 <xref rid="B86-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>,
 <xref rid="B153-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">153</xref>] or targeted provenancing strategies involving the selection of source individuals for translocations and reintroductions with an adaptive bias towards predicted climate change conditions [
 <xref rid="B160-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">160</xref>]. Climate resilience may even be encouraged by exposing individuals to climate stressors, as per Kelly and Phillips (2019) [
 <xref rid="B100-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">100</xref>]. The greater stick-nest rat (
 <italic>Leporillus conditor</italic>), for example, is a murid rodent that became extinct on the Australian mainland in the early 1900s, surviving only on a single offshore island [
 <xref rid="B161-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">161</xref>]. The species became the focus of a number of translocation efforts beginning in the 1980s, including a reintroduction to Arid Recovery Reserve, a 12,300 hectare predator-free enclosure in South Australia’s arid zone [
 <xref rid="B162-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">162</xref>,
 <xref rid="B163-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">163</xref>]. Although the translocation was initially considered a success, having retained a viable population for two decades, it was observed that the stick-nest rats demonstrated spikes in mortality during extreme summer heat events [
 <xref rid="B164-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">164</xref>], a selection pressure that may lead to natural selection for animals with improved physiological adaptations to heat. Comprehensive genomic analyses of the stick-nest rat population at Arid Recovery by White et al. [
 <xref rid="B14-life-11-00653" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>] twenty years after the species’ reintroduction identified six loci under putative selection in the genome when compared with founding populations, but further research is required to determine whether these genomic regions are associated with heat stress. This differentiation may be an adaptive response to heat stress experienced during the hot summer months at Arid Recovery, implying that the translocation of greater stick-nest rats has led to the establishment of a population that is better adapted to withstand hotter, drier conditions.
</p>
