<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In recent years, there has been a continuous energy consumption increase due to various activities. Reducing and decarbonizing energy consumption, especially with actions aimed at the most energy sectors (industry, buildings, and mobility) is, therefore, a way to go in order to reach “eco-sustainable” community [
 <xref rid="B3-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Since 1870, more than 70% of anthropogenic greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions have resulted from the combustion of fossil fuels [
 <xref rid="B4-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Constructing projections of future fossil fuel emissions for studies of future climate change is a challenging task. Workers in 19th-century mines could have scarcely imagined the technologies used by today’s coal industry. The same context is faced today when pondering an outlook for coal in the global energy system of the 21st-century [
 <xref rid="B5-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Chakrabarty and Wang [
 <xref rid="B6-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>] highlighted that multinational enterprises must adapt their strategies to changes in the external business environment to perform environmentally, economically, and socially. This is because, on the one hand, their globalized activities across the world will have an important impact on the climate or on society [
 <xref rid="B7-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. Multinational enterprises can accelerate or slow sustainable development process both locally and globally by acting as one of the main actors in the international globalized economy [
 <xref rid="B8-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Considering that cities are responsible for a large part of energy consumption (from which about 80% of carbon emissions derive) greening urban areas can also make a difference. In this case, it is necessary to intervene both in the reduction in emissions for energy consumption (due, for example, to domestic heating) and on emissions due to transport [
 <xref rid="B11-ijerph-18-06767" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>].
</p>
