<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>GDD is a measure of heat accumulation calculated annually by accumulating the daily total sum of degrees between a minimum and maximum temperature threshold (Dmin and Dmax). GDD has long been used to predict plant and insect phenology in agriculture [
 <xref rid="B122-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>]. Future temperature increases will affect univoltine and multivoltine temperate species in different ways and to different extents. For multivoltine insects, such as aphids and some lepidopteran species, such as the large cabbage white butterfly (
 <italic>Pieris brassicae</italic> L.), higher temperatures, all other parameters being equal, should allow for faster development times that predictably allow for additional generations within a year [
 <xref rid="B49-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>,
 <xref rid="B123-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">123</xref>]. Species with annual life cycles generally develop more rapidly than those with longer life cycles [
 <xref rid="B49-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. Using several models, it has been extrapolated that a 2 °C increase in temperature could result in one to five additional life cycles per year [
 <xref rid="B121-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>]. The most significant examples in this regard are aphids, which can be expected to produce four to five additional generations per year due to their low developmental threshold and short generation time. Aphids may, therefore, be particularly sensitive indicators of temperature changes [
 <xref rid="B120-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>]. Higher temperatures during their development have the beneficial effect of shortening the time in the larval and nymphal stages (when they are highly threatened by predators) [
 <xref rid="B124-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>], and allowing species to become adults earlier [
 <xref rid="B120-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>].
</p>
