<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Expected responses of insects to a rise in temperature include an advance in the timing of adult emergence and an increase in flight duration [
 <xref rid="B120-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>]. One explanation for the changes in voltinism is the earlier onset of the flight period, which could allow for the production of an additional generation [
 <xref rid="B125-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>]. Since the insects fly earlier in the growing season, the individuals of the first generation could reproduce earlier. In addition, due to higher temperatures, faster larval development and growth occurs, so more individuals of the subsequent generation could develop when photoperiod and temperature conditions are still favourable, allowing them to develop directly in the same season rather than diapausing as larvae [
 <xref rid="B125-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>]. The timing of adult emergence can be documented with pheromone-, suction-, or light- traps. Long-term data analyses on insect phenology show that the timing of emergence of insect pests changes under climate change [
 <xref rid="B75-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">75</xref>]. Analysis of suction trap data showed that the spring flight of the Potato aphid (
 <italic>Myzus persicae</italic> Sulzer) began two weeks earlier for every 1 °C increase in mean temperature in January and February [
 <xref rid="B6-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Depending on the temperatures during winter and the duration of exposure, the relative abundance of populations after winter ranges from very low (cold winter) to very high (mild winter) [
 <xref rid="B126-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">126</xref>]. A 50-year report of the timing of the first migrating individuals of 
 <italic>M. persicae</italic> caught in a suction trap each year (from a study by Rothamsted Research, Harpenden, UK) showed a strong correlation with winter mean temperatures in January and February [
 <xref rid="B96-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>]. Members of the order Lepidoptera are another good example of phenological changes. Such changes in butterflies have been reported in the UK, where 26 of 35 observed species have advanced their first appearance [
 <xref rid="B120-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>,
 <xref rid="B127-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">127</xref>]. In Spain, the first appearance of 17 species has shifted by 1–7 weeks in only 15 years [
 <xref rid="B120-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>,
 <xref rid="B128-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">128</xref>]. Early emergence increased voltinism in the European grapevine moth (
 <italic>Lobesia botrana</italic> Denis and Schiff.) in Spain. This pest is usually trivoltine in Mediterranean latitudes, but with a tendency to emerge early in spring, it sometimes has a fourth additional flight, possibly due to global warming [
 <xref rid="B129-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">129</xref>]. Since the 1980s, the number of generations per year has increased in many central European Lepidoptera species, with some univoltine or bivoltine species transitioning to bivoltine or multivoltine life cycles [
 <xref rid="B125-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>]. Partially bivoltine or multivoltine species are expected to experience an increase in abundance of second or subsequent generations [
 <xref rid="B125-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>,
 <xref rid="B130-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">130</xref>].
</p>
