<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par7">Under the alkaline condition, the discharge/charge (ORR/OER) reactions at the air cathode of ZABs are: O
 <sub>2</sub> + 2H
 <sub>2</sub>O + 4e
 <sup>−</sup> 
 <inline-formula id="IEq1">
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$$\leftrightharpoons $$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M2">
    <mo>⇋</mo>
   </math>
   <inline-graphic xlink:href="40820_2021_650_Article_IEq1.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </inline-formula>4OH
 <sup>−</sup>. The ideal bifunctional catalysts can mediate this reversible oxygen reactions from equilibrium status to OH
 <sup>−</sup> or O
 <sub>2</sub> to a great extent [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. Among various electrocatalysts ever reported, the material composites encompassing transition metal-based compounds (such as oxides, sulfides, carbides, and nitrides) supported on heteroatom-doped carbon (especially N-doped carbon) were explored as a class of compelling catalysts toward both ORR and OER [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. The carbon support with unique porous structure is essentially important for the high performance of the composite catalysts, which can not only facilitate the charge transfer and mass transport, but also provide large surface area to ensure abundant exposed active sites. Recently, the supported bimetal alloy (e.g., CoFe, NiCo, and FeNi) composites have received growing interest owing to their binary active metal sites in a single nanoparticle, which may provide more selectivity for different catalytic reactions. In addition, the interaction between different metals can effectively modify the electronic structures, resulting in stabilized surface energy and moderate oxygen binding affinity [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>].
</p>
