<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par10">In this work, a novel Co-based coordination framework with uniform nanoflower structure was explored as precursor to prepare heterostructured Co/CoFe nanoparticles embedded in N-doped graphitic carbon. The preparation strategy is facile and versatile, which allows hydrothermal coordination reaction for morphology construction and subsequent cation exchange for composition regulation. The pyrolytic Co/CoFe@NC material delivers multiple advantages in terms of oxygen electrocatalysis for its unique morphology, heterostructure and bimetallic composition. It maintains the nanoflower morphology of the precursor, which can expose abundant catalytic active sites and enlarge catalyst/electrolyte contact area. The supportive and protective NC thin layer not only ensures a high electrical conductivity, but also prevents nanoparticles from agglomeration and dissolution during catalysis. The density functional theory (DFT) calculations suggest that the incorporation of Fe atoms can moderate the adsorption free energies of oxygen-containing intermediates in ORR and OER, which effectively boost the intrinsic activity of Co/CoFe@NC. The theoretical analysis also reveals the charge transfer from the metal layer to the NC layer, which can cause an electron-rich state on the latter and induce extra surface catalysis from carbon matrix. As a result, the optimized catalyst displays extraordinary bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis with a small ∆
 <italic>E</italic> (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>j</italic>=10 
 </sub>− 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>1/2</sub>) value of 0.70 V, which is among the best in literature reports. The rechargeable ZABs, including liquid batteries and flexible quasi-solid-sate batteries with a home-made sodium polyacrylate hydrogel (PANa) as electrolyte were assembled, demonstrating very impressive performance with high open-circuit voltage, small discharge/charge voltage gap and excellent long-term cyclability, and mechanistic flexibility.
</p>
