<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par31">Long-term full water column temperature data are scarce in the Laurentian Great Lakes. The longest continuous moored record has been collected by the Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory, which has had a site occupied in southern Lake Michigan since 1991. Another site in western Lake Superior has been occupied since 2005 (ref. 
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref>
 </sup>). Neither of these have sufficient data to explore climate-related changes in stratification phenology. However, there are several sites at which surface water temperature has been measured by meteorology buoys in recent decades. Surface water temperature from these buoys can be a useful proxy for stratification phenology
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>. Specifically, when the surface water temperature reaches the temperature of maximum density (3.98 °C at the surface of fresh water lakes), stability considerations require that deep water temperatures must be between the temperature of maximum density for a given depth (this temperature decreases by 0.2 °C for every 100 m depth) and the surface temperature of maximum density. Therefore, the heat content of the water column is known to a high level of confidence, so that the date of this occurrence is a useful phenological indicator. Reaching 3.98 °C at the surface in the spring thus coincides with the onset of positive stratification
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>
 </sup>. In this study, we investigate stratification phenology in three of the Laurentian Great Lakes—Superior, Michigan, and Huron with sub-daily surface temperature data from surface meteorology buoys, which have been deployed by the National Data Buoy Center (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.ndbc.noaa.gov" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://www.ndbc.noaa.gov</ext-link>) in the open (offshore) waters of the lakes since 1980 (although not all years had suitable data). Ontario is excluded from the study since data are only available as far back as 2002; Erie is excluded because its surface temperature is typically already above the temperature of maximum density when the buoys are deployed in the spring. At all sites, the buoys are typically recovered before the lake cools through the temperature of maximum density, so there is not sufficient data to examine the break-up of stratification. In these lakes, we determine stratification onset as the first day of year on which the minimum lake surface temperature exceeds 3.98 °C.
</p>
