<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Generated [NiSalen]
 <sup>+•</sup> species are known to undergo radical coupling to yield a redox active metallopolymer, in which phenolate moieties of adjacent monomer units are joined together by carbon–carbon single bonds (this concept has been shared by many researchers [
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>] but alternative descriptions of the metal–
 <italic>salen</italic> polymer structure also exist [
 <xref rid="B46-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]). Previous studies of one-electron oxidation of the sterically hindered [NiAmben] analogue have shown that the SOMO of generated radicals is more developed on the nitrogens and less on the benzene rings, but the spin density at the phenyl 
 <italic>para</italic> positions is non-negligible [
 <xref rid="B21-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. In the absence of 
 <italic>para</italic>-protecting substituents, the electrochemically generated Ni
 <sup>II</sup>–anilinyl radical cations should be prone to undergo the 4,4′-phenyl–phenyl coupling reaction, yielding an electrochemically active polymer network on the electrode surface. A general representation of the proposed mechanism for [NiAmben] polymerization is shown in 
 <xref ref-type="scheme" rid="molecules-26-02646-sch001">Scheme 1</xref>. The process likely involves the formation of σ-dimers as intermediate reaction products. Dimeric structures undergo further oxidation, deprotonation, and reactions with other radical cations in the system to yield a robust polymer film. The proposed mechanism of poly-[NiAmben] formation appears to be quite similar to that of poly(diphenylamine) films [
 <xref rid="B47-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>,
 <xref rid="B48-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>] and is indirectly confirmed by the presence of a shoulder at ca. 330 nm in the spectrum of the undoped film (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f009">Figure 9</xref>a). This shoulder is not observed in the spectrum of the monomer and may result from intraligand π–π* transitions in the σ-bonded amidobenzilideneimino moieties of adjacent [NiAmben] units [
 <xref rid="B39-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. 
</p>
