<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Spectral changes accompanying the electrooxidation of poly-[NiAmben] are more complex. One-electron oxidation of its repeat units is a two-step process. Potential-induced changes in the spectra of poly-[NiAmben] between −0.6 and 0 V are consistent with formation of anilinyl radical cations that seem to be delocalized through metal centers, as in similar monomeric complexes [
 <xref rid="B21-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Pronounced decrease in the absorption intensity of the MLCT band with increasing electrode potential supports this assumption. As higher anodic charge is injected into the polymer between 0 and 0.4 V, the system gradually shifts to a more stable electronic structure via charge rearrangement between ligand nitrogens and nickel ions. The charged species progressively acquire spectroscopic signatures of benzidine radical cations B
 <sup>•+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B39-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B49-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>,
 <xref rid="B50-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>], while involvement of metal orbitals in the oxidation becomes negligible. Potential-induced spectral changes accompanying the transfer of the second electron per a repeat unit of poly-[NiAmben] (above 0.4 V) are overall indicative of the conversion of benzidine radical cations B
 <sup>•+</sup> to dications B
 <sup>2+</sup>) [
 <xref rid="B39-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B49-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>,
 <xref rid="B50-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]. Spectral changes observed at electrode potentials above 1.0 V are minor, which indicates that poly-[NiAmben]-modified electrodes exhibit capacitive charging rather than faradaic currents in this potential range [
 <xref rid="B51-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]. 
</p>
