<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Different types of charged species in the 
 <italic>p</italic>-doped polymers are responsible for the observed differences in their electrochemical behavior. The generation of anilinyl radical cations delocalized through metal centers in the first step of poly-[NiAmben] oxidation as opposed to the apparent absence of similar charged species in the 
 <italic>p</italic>-doped poly-[NiSalen] film explains significant cathodic shift of the onset potential of the polymer oxidation in the N
 <sub>4</sub> system vs. its N
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> analogue (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f011">Figure 11</xref>b). Both polymers feature distinct pairs of redox peaks in the cyclic voltammograms associated with the conversion of the neutral repeat units to singly charged ones (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f006">Figure 6</xref>b and 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f011">Figure 11</xref>b) and maxima in their conductance profiles at a 1:1 ratio of the neutral/radical cation mixed valence system (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f008">Figure 8</xref> and 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f012">Figure 12</xref>b). In addition to that, poly-[NiAmben] shows the second oxidation peak in the CV curve ascribed to the conversion of singly to doubly oxidized fragments and the second conductivity maximum, which is associated with the second redox wave and could therefore be assigned to charge transport through the polymer film involving radical cation/dication mixed valence state. Poly-[NiSalen] undergoes more than one-electron transfer per repeat unit when charged to 1.3 V (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-26-02646-f011">Figure 11</xref>b), which is not, however, manifested as individual peaks in voltammetric or conductance curves. Instead, this polymer appears to possess negligible conductivity at redox states of n &gt; 1, which indicates suppressed charge mobility between singly and doubly oxidized fragments of the polymer. Previous studies have identified poor intrachain nickel ion-mediated conduction as the main cause of charge trapping in heavily 
 <italic>p</italic>-doped nickel–
 <italic>salen</italic> polymers [
 <xref rid="B12-molecules-26-02646" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. In our tests, poly-[NiSalen] showed decent coulombic efficiencies only at high charge/discharge rates (
 <xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-molecules-26-02646">Figure S8</xref> and 
 <xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-molecules-26-02646">Table S3</xref>) and quickly degraded during repeated potential cycling when charged to 1.3 V. Enhanced intrachain displacement of charge in the heavily 
 <italic>p</italic>-doped poly-[NiAmben] film prevents the formation of localized immobile charges at high anodic potentials and significantly reduces risks of polymer network overoxidation in multiple charge/discharge cycles. 
</p>
