<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Metal-ion batteries (MIBs) are rechargeable batteries that use metal ions as a charge carrier being capable of reversible intercalation and deintercalation into the host material [
 <xref rid="B1-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. In recent years, on account of their low self-discharge, less memory effect and high efficiency, the implementation of MIBs for energy storage has become very popular [
 <xref rid="B6-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. Of different types of MIBs, lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) are widely used for various applications due to their high energy density and long cycle life [
 <xref rid="B8-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. However, some important factors such as high cost and safety issues tarnish the large-scale application of LIBs [
 <xref rid="B10-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Besides LIBs, various monovalent (Na
 <sup>+</sup>, K
 <sup>+</sup>) and multivalent (Mg
 <sup>2+</sup>, Zn
 <sup>2+</sup>, Al
 <sup>3+</sup>) ions have been considered as charge carriers in MIBs. In view of this, ZIBs have attracted the interest of researchers [
 <xref rid="B12-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. It is noted that zinc (Zn) has a low redox potential of −0.763 V vs. a standard hydrogen electrode (SHE), which is favorable for near neutral or slightly acidic aqueous electrolytes [
 <xref rid="B16-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. In addition, Zn has a higher specific volumetric capacity compared to that of lithium viz. 5855 and 2066 mAh cm
 <sup>−3</sup>, respectively [
 <xref rid="B17-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. As compared to lithium, Zn is lower in cost and highly abundant [
 <xref rid="B18-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-ijms-21-04689" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>].
</p>
