<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In brief, MXenes have the chemical formula M
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub>X
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>T
 <italic>
  <sub>x</sub>
 </italic>, in which M stands for a transition metal element (Ti, V, Mo, Nb, Cr, etc.) and X denotes the carbide or nitride. As illustrated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f008">Figure 8</xref>a, they are atomically thin sheets of metal carbides, metal nitrides, or metal carbonitrides [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B107-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">107</xref>,
 <xref rid="B108-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">108</xref>,
 <xref rid="B109-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">109</xref>,
 <xref rid="B110-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">110</xref>,
 <xref rid="B111-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">111</xref>,
 <xref rid="B112-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">112</xref>,
 <xref rid="B113-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">113</xref>] with a surface functional group (T) of O
 <sup>2−</sup>, OH
 <sup>−</sup>, or F
 <sup>−</sup> [
 <xref rid="B114-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">114</xref>]. The first 2D MXene materials were developed by Gogotski’s research group at Drexel University in 2011. They derived 2D MXene from the MAX phase by removing the A group using etching [
 <xref rid="B115-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">115</xref>], which is unlikely to block the transport of mobile ions [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. These MAX phases consist of layers of TMCs or TMNs (M
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub>X
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>) that are infused with layers of A-element atoms (i.e., Group 13 and 14 elements in the periodic table) [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. After etching the surface of the MXene, it terminated with OH
 <sup>−</sup> and F
 <sup>−</sup> groups, which play a dominant role in deciding the characteristics of MXene compounds. These MX phases, which consist of several stacked layers of flakes or sheets with weak interlayer interactions, are subjected to delamination using solvents such as DMSO, DMF, and ethanol/water through ultra-sonication. Due to the presence of the surface-reacting X group, MXenes offer greater thermodynamic stability compared to their pure counterparts. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f008">Figure 8</xref>b presents a schematic representation of the process of producing an MXene from a MAX phase [
 <xref rid="B116-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">116</xref>,
 <xref rid="B117-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">117</xref>]. To date, over 70 MAX phases and over 20 MXenes have been identified. The ultra-sonication time and the choice of surfactant intercalation agent strongly affect the morphology of MXene compounds, which can include wrinkled sheets, spheres, nanoplates, and scrolls. An example of MXene sheet morphology is shown in the SEM micrographs in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-10-02106-f008">Figure 8</xref>c–g [
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B116-nanomaterials-10-02106" ref-type="bibr">116</xref>]. In contrast to graphene materials, MXenes offer a variety of chemical compositions due to the atomic layer thickness of the TMCs and TMNs. 
</p>
