<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Global climate changes have significant impacts on agriculture and also on agricultural insect pests. Agricultural crops and their corresponding pests are directly and indirectly affected by climate change. Direct impacts are on pests’ reproduction, development, survival and dispersal, whereas indirectly the climate change affects the relationships between pests, their environment and other insect species such as natural enemies, competitors, vectors and mutualists [
 <xref rid="B4-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Insects are poikilothermic organisms; the temperature of their body depends on the temperature of the environment. Thus, temperature is probably the most important environmental factor affecting insect behaviour, distribution, development and reproduction [
 <xref rid="B42-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>]. Therefore, it is very likely that the main drivers of climate change (increased atmospheric CO
 <sub>2</sub>, increased temperature and decreased soil moisture) could significantly affect the population dynamics of insect pests and thus the percentage of crop losses [
 <xref rid="B43-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. Climate change creates new ecological niches that provide opportunities for insect pests to establish and spread in new geographic regions and shift from one region to another [
 <xref rid="B44-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. The complexity of physiological effects exerted by rising temperatures and CO
 <sub>2</sub> can profoundly affect interactions between agricultural crops and insect pests [
 <xref rid="B45-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>,
 <xref rid="B46-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>,
 <xref rid="B47-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. Therefore, farmers can expect to face new and intense pest problems in the coming years due to the changing climate. The spread of crop pests across physical and political boundaries threatens food security and is a global problem common to all countries and all regions [
 <xref rid="B44-insects-12-00440" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>].
</p>
