<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There are several methods for synthesizing PBAs. The coprecipitation method is one of the most widely used methods for synthesizing PBA powder because it allows mass production at low cost [
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Additives such as citrate and polyvinylpyrrolidone have been introduced into precursors to improve the specific capacity and cyclic performance [
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Methods based on the use of a single-salt solution have been employed to obtain Prussian blue with low vacancy and water amount, which enhances the specific capacity and cyclic performances [
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Besides bulk synthesis, several other methods have been reported for depositing PBA films. Electrodeposition methods have been studied to deposit a Prussian blue thin film on electrodes, which were then utilized as electrochemical sensors and electrochromic devices [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Metal hexacyanoferrate films have been deposited by applying cyclic potential [
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. However, the PBA films are only deposited on conductive electrodes subjected to electric potential. To overcome this limitation, a method of growing PBA films by repeatedly immersing the substrate into two precursors has been demonstrated [
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-11-01860" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Unlike the electrodeposition methods, this immersion method can deposit PBA films on any surface regardless of the surface electrical conductivity; however, when the number of immersion repetitions is increased, the PBA films grow as particle-like structures rather than a conformal film. Well-developed PBA coating methods can expand the utilization of PBAs with superior physical and electrochemical properties to various applications, from batteries to microscale devices integrated with PBA thin films.
</p>
