<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0085">The core program at Oregon consists of six quarter-long courses. The first course is a lecture course that focuses on the fundamental theories of electrochemistry, with coupled use of hands-on laboratory activities and numerical simulations. The course generally follows Bard and Faulkner’s text, with some additions. After providing an overview of electrochemistry theory and applications, a review of electrostatics, and introduction to basic three-electrode measurements under mass-transfer control in the first week, the focus shifts to foundational concepts. First, thermodynamics are covered, starting from basic physical-chemistry equations and derivations of the relationship between free energy and the cell potential, then proceeding to discussions of the electrochemical potential and its use in describing equilibrium and interface effects. Students learn how to construct Pourbaix diagrams from thermodynamic data and use them to predict reactions. Electrochemical kinetics is discussed using transition-state and Marcus theory leading to the current-overpotential, Butler-Volmer, and Tafel equations. Double-layer theory is discussed in the context of showing how the resulting electric potential drop affects electron- and ion-transfer kinetics and the free-energy surface for the reaction. Transport by diffusion and migration is introduced in the context of the electrochemical-potential gradient and students are introduced to the transference number for ionic transport. Next, electroanalytical potential step, linear sweep voltammetry, and cyclic voltammetry experiments are discussed. The current-time and current-voltage expressions are not derived in class as they include the use of relatively tedious methods in solving differential equations. Instead, the emphasis is placed on defining and understanding boundary and initial conditions, as well as the meaning and difference between steady-state and transient responses. A brief discussion of multistep electrochemical mechanisms and interpreting voltammetry follows. Students use simple commercial software to simulate the effects of transport, electrochemical kinetics, and mechanism on the resulting shape of voltammograms (such as that provided as part of the Bio-Logic software package, EC-Lab). The course ends with a discussion of alternating current (AC) circuits and impedance analysis. Students typically struggle to use complex numbers to manipulate and represent AC responses and often need to review basic circuits. The students learn to derive basic expressions for Randles equivalent circuits and to fit experimental data to identify charge transfer and diffusional impedances as well as the ohmic resistance and double-layer capacitance.</p>
