<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In recent decades, green or renewable energy system development has garnered great interest worldwide due to high energy demand and the desire to save the atmosphere from air pollution. Secondary batteries are often considered the best renewable energy resources and alternative energy systems for gasoline fuels to fulfill the energy demand with high energy density [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Among them, Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> batteries have attracted much attention as the next-generation energy storage system with a high specific energy density that is integrated with low-cost and environmentally friendly air cathode catalysts. Their practical energy density is comparable to gasoline fuel and 10 times higher than commercially available Li-ion batteries [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Molecular oxygen (O
 <sub>2</sub>) spread throughout the atmosphere is mainly used as a renewable oxidant source for Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> batteries. However, the practical viability of Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> batteries is still challenging due to the poor rate of oxygen reaction kinetics (O
 <sub>2</sub> reduction/evolution; ORR/OER), electrolyte instability and poor long-term stability [
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. On the other hand, noble metal catalysts such as Pt, Ru and Ir have been used as potential air electrodes in Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> batteries. This is owing to their high catalytic activity toward ORR/OER; however, they are very expensive, low-abundance materials, and they deliver poor cyclability due to their poor bifunctional activity, which is also a further reason to limit the commercialization of Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> batteries [
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Therefore, non-precious metals/oxides and carbon-based material catalysts or their composites should be considered in the development of a new air electrode for Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> battery application [
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>].
</p>
