<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Perovskite oxides (ABO
 <sub>3</sub>) are the most frequently considered air catalysts in recently studied metal–air battery systems [
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Because of their high electronic and ionic conducting properties, they have demonstrated excellent bifunctional catalytic activity towards ORR/OER reactions when the A sites and B sites are substituted with other elements [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. Interestingly, lanthanum manganite (LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub>) perovskite is a well-known catalyst for ORR in the perovskite family due to its defective cation-deficient lattice and the presence of multiple oxidation states, such as Mn
 <sup>3+</sup> and Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. Conversely, it has a poorer OER activity than LaCoO
 <sub>3</sub> and LaNiO
 <sub>3</sub> due to the Mn-O bond’s lower binding energy on the LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub> surface. However, the bifunctional ORR and OER properties of LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub> can be tuned by the partial substitution of La and Mn sites with alkaline earth or rare-earth and transition-metal cations, respectively. Therefore, metal-ion-doped LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub> perovskites have received enormous attention in Li-air or Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> battery applications as cathode materials to replace the conventional Pt or Pt/C catalysts [
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. The discharge and recharge overpotentials of these LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub>-based cathodes are significantly reduced as compared to commercial carbon and Pt/C catalysts [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. However, most of the LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub>-based perovskites are prepared by a sol–gel method, which produces non-porous microparticles with a low surface area, resulting in low storage capacity and poor cycle stability. Hence, the development of LaMnO
 <sub>3</sub> perovskites with more porosity and a high surface area is still required to increase the oxygen and Li
 <sup>+</sup> ion diffusion pathways for the high storage capacity and cyclability of Li-O
 <sub>2</sub> batteries [
 <xref rid="B25-nanomaterials-11-01025" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>].
</p>
