<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par36">For all lakes that were considered suitable to estimate stratification phenology from surface temperature observations, notably those that passed the criteria described above, we calculated the lake mean surface temperature time series from the satellite data
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>, which were then used to identify the first and last day of year in which surface temperature cross the 3.98 °C threshold. Only observations from 2007 to 2019, the time period in which most satellite retrievals were available in ESA CCI Lakes v1.0, were used in this study, as the low temporal resolution of retrievals prior to 2007 could bias the calculated stratification phenology. Furthermore, the satellite data were only used to identify the onset and break-up of thermal stratification if the temporal resolution of observations were considered adequate for each year. Specifically, we only used the satellite observations to estimate stratification onset if measurements were available at a temporal frequency of &lt;5 days for at least 75% of the ice-free period, defined using the lake ice cover data from ESA CCI Lakes. Linear interpolation was then used to generate a gap-free time series when each of the previous criteria were met. The onset and break-up of thermal stratification averaged across all years per lake were then compared to the cold- and warm-season climatic data (air temperature and wind speed), respectively. For this comparison, we used climate data from ERA5, extracted from the same lake centre pixels as the lake temperatures described above. ERA5 data were used, as opposed to the ISIMIP2b historic climate projections, because the latter finish in 2005, and the satellite data used do not start until 2007. This also forms an additional validation of the relationships shown between climate and lake stratification, as both independent data sets produced similar results. One additional limitation for this criterion for defining stratification break-up is in shallower dimictic or monomictic lakes, which often mix at significantly higher temperatures than 3.98 °C due to the build-up of heat within the hypolimnion during summer.
</p>
