<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Nanostructured SVOs with different morphologies (such as nanorods, nanowires, nanorings, etc.) have synthesized and showed varying properties and electrochemical performance [
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. In particular, significant efforts have been devoted to developing β-AgVO
 <sub>3</sub> nanomaterials due to their stable layered structure, high Ag/V ratio, and superior ionic properties [
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Chen et al. used a facile and straightforward low-temperature hydrothermal method to synthesize different one-dimensional β-AgVO
 <sub>3</sub> nano/microstructures. The capacity for the as-synthesized β-AgVO
 <sub>3</sub> electrode was 272.7 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> at 0.01 mA in primary lithium batteries [
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Liang et al. successfully prepared β-AgVO
 <sub>3</sub> nanorods by a soft chemistry route, followed by a calcination process. The nanorods fabricated at 400 °C delivered an initial specific discharge capacity of 186 mAh g
 <sup>−1</sup> at a current density of 100 mA g
 <sup>−1</sup> as a cathode in primary lithium batteries [
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Furthermore, β-AgVO
 <sub>3</sub> has also been developed as the electrode for rechargeable LIBs. For example, Li et al. successfully synthesized multiscale silver vanadates particles by using a simple sol-gel method with organic acids as reductants and annealing at temperatures higher than 450 °C [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-11-00569" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. The β-AgVO
 <sub>3</sub> particles as the cathode for rechargeable LIBs exhibited a high initial capacity of 243 mAh g
 <sup>−1,</sup> and 41% of the initial capacity was retained after 100 cycles.
</p>
