<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xml:lang="EN" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ao</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acsodf</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Omega</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2470-1343</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7482300</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsomega.0c02778</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Synergy between Interconnected Porous Carbon-Sulfur
Cathode and Metallic MgB<sub>2</sub> Interlayer as a Lithium Polysulfide
Immobilizer for High-Performance Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Garapati</surname><given-names>Meenakshi
Seshadhri</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath2"><name><surname>Sundara</surname><given-names>Ramaprabhu</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1">Alternative Energy and Nanotechnology
Laboratory (AENL), Nano Functional Materials Technology Center (NFMTC),
Department of Physics, <institution>Indian Institute
of Technology Madras</institution>, Chennai 600036, <country>India</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>Email: <email>ramp@iitm.ac.in</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>08</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>08</day><month>09</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><volume>5</volume><issue>35</issue><fpage>22379</fpage><lpage>22388</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>12</day><month>06</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>13</day><month>08</month><year>2020</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2020</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><license-p>This is an open access article published under an ACS AuthorChoice <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/page/policy/authorchoice_termsofuse.html">License</ext-link>, which permits copying and redistribution of the article or any adaptations for non-commercial purposes.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0011" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>Lithium-sulfur
(Li-S) batteries are the potential candidates for
developing high-energy-density electric vehicles. However, poor electrical
conductivity of sulfur/discharged products, low active material utilization,
shuttle mechanism, and poor cycle life remain the major challenges
for the development of Li-S batteries. Herein, we report the nitrogen-doped
highly porous carbon (NC) with interconnected pores as the sulfur
host (NC-S), which is synthesized by a facile one-step process without
using any template and activation agents. The highly interconnected
porous structure of NC can accommodate a high amount of sulfur loading
and provide space for sulfur volume expansion during redox reactions.
Besides, to mitigate the lithium polysulfide dissolution and shuttle
mechanism, metallic and polar magnesium diboride (MgB<sub>2</sub>)
is used as an interlayer. Consequently, the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode
delivers higher specific capacity, rate capability, and excellent
cyclic stability than the NC-S cathode and bulk sulfur cathode with
MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer. The lithium polysulfide (LPS) adsorption
test shows that MgB<sub>2</sub> has strong chemisorption toward lithium
polysulfides, which can inhibit the dissolution of LPS into the electrolyte
and minimizes the shuttle effect. The dynamic electrochemical impedance
spectroscopy analysis investigates the electrochemical reaction kinetics
of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode during the charging and discharging
processes. Overall, this work demonstrates that the synergy between
the nitrogen-doped porous carbon-sulfur host and polar metallic MgB<sub>2</sub> improves the performance of the Li-S battery, which is beneficial
for the development of high-energy-density batteries for the future.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>ao0c02778</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>ao0c02778</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Lithium-sulfur
(Li-S) batteries are considered as the next-generation
electrochemical energy storage devices owing to their high energy
density (2600 Wh kg<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>) and theoretical capacity
(1672 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>). Besides, eco-friendliness, low
cost, and wide availability of sulfur cathode make it a promising
candidate.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> However, the poor ionic/electronic conductivity
of sulfur/discharged products, pulverization of sulfur during the
redox reactions, dissolution of intermediately formed lithium polysulfides
(LPS) into the electrolyte, and shuttle mechanism are the major barriers
for the development of Li-S batteries in a larger scale.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup> These issues give rise to low coulombic efficiency,
poor cyclic stability, and active material losses of Li-S batteries.
For commercialization of Li-S batteries, the above-mentioned challenges
should be addressed.</p><p>The electrical conductivity and wettability
of the sulfur and discharge
product lithium sulfide (Li<sub>2</sub>S) can be enriched by incorporating
sulfur into carbonaceous host materials. This can improve the specific
capacity, rate capability, and cyclic stability of the Li-S battery.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref></sup> These parameters also depend on the choice of carbonaceous host.
In this context, porous carbon nanostructures are considered as more
suitable materials owing to their high specific surface area, controlled
pore size distribution, and chemical and thermal stabilities.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref></sup> Porous carbon with the combination of mesoporous
and microporous structures can enhance the active materials storage
and utilization and therefore, mitigate the lithium polysulfide shuttling.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup> For the synthesis of porous carbon structures,
many approaches have been made using various templates. These processes
are time-consuming, have complex synthesis routes, and costly.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref></sup> Besides, addition of a nitrogen dopant to the
porous carbon structure can enhance the interaction between the lithium
polysulfides (LPS) and carbon structure, thereby improving the performance
of the Li-S battery.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref></sup> In the present work,
a nitrogen-doped porous carbon (NC) has been synthesized by the facile
thermal decomposition method. For this, sodium bicarbonate is used
as pyrogen, and melamine and glucose are used as nitrogen and carbon
sources, respectively. The highly porous nitrogen-doped carbon is
used as a sulfur host (NC-S).</p><p>Extensive research has been carried
out for developing promising
polar, nonpolar, organic, and inorganic materials for the confinement
of lithium polysulfides (LPS) and minimize the active material losses.
The carbon-based materials can provide conductivity to the sulfur
cathode and also reduce the LPS shuttling by physical confinement.
This weak interaction between nonpolar carbonaceous materials and
polar LPS limits the performance of the Li-S battery.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref></sup> Therefore, the strong interaction between lithium polysulfides (LPS)
and polar materials can trap the lithium polysulfides efficiently
through chemical interactions. Transition-metal oxide, carbide, nitrides,
and sulfides are mainly identified as polar materials, which can easily
adsorb the LPS on their surface by the Lewis acid&#x02013;base reaction,
unlike nonpolar carbonaceous materials.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref></sup> The shuttle
mechanism is only partially limited by chemical interactions using
transition-metal oxides, nitrides, carbides and sulfides due to the
less number of available sites for these materials, which therefore
hamper the cycling capability of the Li-S battery. To improve the
performance of the Li-S battery, new materials/chemistry should be
explored. The study on interactions of metal borides with lithium
polysulfide has not been reported much. Li et al. have reported conductive
and polar titanium boride (TiB<sub>2</sub>) as a sulfur host in Li-S
batteries and effectively confined the shuttle effect.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref></sup> Guan et al. have reported an amorphous Co<sub>2</sub>B@graphene composite for immobilization of LPS and explained
that the synergistic effect of Co and B interactions with LPS and
high conductivity of graphene could efficiently restrict the LPS dissolution.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup></p><p>In this work, we report the layer-structured
and room-temperature
metallic nature MgB<sub>2</sub> as an interlayer to mitigate LPS shuttling.
MgB<sub>2</sub> consists of alternative layers of magnesium and boron
atoms, where the boron layer forms honeycomb stacks with the magnesium
layer as a space filler.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> MgB<sub>2</sub> has similar band structures to graphite with deeper &#x003c0; bands
and coexistence of 2D covalent bands from in-plane sigma bonds and
3D metallic conducting bands from the interlayer-made MgB<sub>2</sub> as the most attractive material in the field of superconductivity.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> The application of metallic, layered, and structured MgB<sub>2</sub> as the lithium polysulfide immobilizer is not explored much. Recently,
Linda F. Nazar&#x02019;s group has reported ultra-lightweight MgB<sub>2</sub> as the polysulfide mediator for LPS redox reaction.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> They have stated that both magnesium and boron
centers bind S<sub>2</sub><sup>2&#x02013;</sup> anions in the absence
of Li<sup>+</sup> cations, which can enhance the diffusion of Li<sup>+</sup> ions. The interaction reported here is different from the
previously reported Lewis acid&#x02013;base interactions on chalcogenides,
carbides, and nitrides with LPS.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup></p><p>In the present work, a simple one-step synthesis has been approached
from the synthesis of highly porous nitrogen-doped carbon (NC) without
using KOH or templates. The nitrogen-doped porous carbon is used as
the sulfur host (NC-S) to fabricate the cathode. SEM, TEM, and surface
area measurements confirm the highly porous nature of NC. Magnesium
diboride coated on the carbon cloth with high LPS adsorption is used
as the interlayer. Li-S batteries are tested with NC-S cathode with
and without the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer. To understand the significant
performance of the NC-S cathode, the cells were fabricated using 65%
sulfur, 25% carbon, and 10% binder as bulk sulfur cathode with the
MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer and compared to the NC-S cathode with MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2</label><title>Experimental Section</title><sec id="sec2.1"><label>2.1</label><title>Synthesis of NC and NC-S</title><p>Synthesis
of nitrogen-doped porous carbon (NC) involves a facile thermal decomposition
technique. Briefly, melamine, glucose, and sodium bicarbonate were
taken as nitrogen, carbon, and pore-forming precursors, respectively.
Melamine, glucose, and sodium hydrogen carbonate were taken in the
molar ratio of 1:1:1 and well ground with the help of a mortar and
pestle. The ground mixture was loaded into a horizontal tubular furnace
and heated at a heating rate of 5 &#x000b0;C min<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> to
800 &#x000b0;C and held at this temperature for 2 h. After the furnace
temperature reaches room temperature, the sample was washed with ethanol
and deionized water for the removal of sodium content and any unreacted
compounds. The final NC sample was obtained by filtering and drying
the washed sample at 60 &#x000b0;C in a vacuum oven for 10 h. The pore
formation mechanism is dependent on the hydrogen-bond interactions
with the material precursors. Melamine consists of molecules like
N&#x02013;H&#x000b7;&#x000b7;&#x000b7;N bonds arranged in planar sheets, which
are connected with HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02013;</sup> anions originating
from bicarbonates forming bonds like N&#x02013;H&#x000b7;&#x000b7;&#x000b7;O.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> The self-assembly of porous sheets is promoted
by sodium bicarbonate.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref></sup> The sodium bicarbonate
and glucose decompose at a high temperature, liberating CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>O that lead to the formation of a porous network
in the sample.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref></sup></p><p>Sulfur-incorporated
nitrogen-doped porous carbon (NC-S) is synthesized by the melt-diffusion
method. First, sublimed sulfur and NC are taken in a 4:1 ratio and
a homogeneous mixture of sulfur and NC was obtained by grinding well
for 1 h. The sample was sealed in an ampoule and heated to 155 &#x000b0;C
very slowly and maintained at that temperature for 12 h and further
annealed at 300 &#x000b0;C to vaporize the surface-deposited sulfur.
Sulfur infiltration into the NC network was carried out at 155 &#x000b0;C,
where sulfur is in a molten state with the lowest viscosity and can
quickly diffuse through the pores of NC by capillary forces, which
are a very slow process, and polymerization of S<sub>8</sub> takes
place.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref></sup> The schematic illustration of
the synthesis process is given in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">Scheme <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="scheme">1</xref></xref>.</p><fig id="sch1" position="float"><label>Scheme 1</label><caption><title>Schematic Representation of the Synthesis
Procedure for NC and NC-S</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0010" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><label>2.2</label><title>Fabrication of MgB<sub>2</sub> Interlayer</title><p>MgB<sub>2</sub> (Alfa Aesar, 99%, &#x0223c;100 mesh powder) is well
ground with acetylene black and PVDF in an 80:10:10 ratio. The slurry
was prepared by adding the NMP solvent. The uniform mixture of the
slurry is coated on a carbon cloth by the doctor blade method (GDL,
Nickunj Eximp Entp Pvt Ltd, India). The MgB<sub>2</sub>-coated carbon
cloth is dried at 80 &#x000b0;C for 12 h in a vacuum oven. The dried
sample is cut into a 12 mm disk and used as the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer
for Li-S battery.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><label>2.3</label><title>Material Characterizations</title><p>X-ray
diffraction (XRD) patterns of the samples were recorded using a Rigaku
Smartlab X-ray diffractometer with Cu K<sub>&#x003b1;</sub> radiation
(&#x003bb; = 0.154 nm) at 40 kV and 100 mA embedded with a nickel filter.
The XRD patterns were recorded with a step size of 0.02&#x000b0;, in
the range of 10&#x02013;90&#x000b0;. The surface area analysis of the
synthesized samples was studied by recording nitrogen adsorption/desorption
isotherms at a liquid nitrogen temperature using a Micromeritics ASAP
2020. The specific surface area and porosity of the samples were calculated
using the Brunauer&#x02013;Emmett&#x02013;Teller (BET) and Barrett&#x02013;Joyner&#x02013;Halenda
(BJH) theories, respectively. The morphology of the synthesized samples
was characterized by an Inspect F50 scanning electron microscopy (SEM)
and a Technai G20 transmission electron microscopy (TEM) instruments.
Energy-dispersive X-ray spectra analysis (EDS) measurements were studied
using an Inspect F50 instrument. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA)
was carried out using an SDT Q600 from TA Instruments, at a heating
rate of 20 &#x000b0;C min<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> from room temperature to
1000 &#x000b0;C. The chemical structure/bonding of the samples was studied
by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) from a Specs X-ray photoelectron
spectrometer using Al K<sub>&#x003b1;</sub> enabled with PHOIBOS 100MCD
analyzer as an X-ray source.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.4"><label>2.4</label><title>Electrochemical Measurements</title><p>The
cathode of Li-S battery was prepared by mixing 75% active material
(NC-S), 10% acetylene black, and 15% poly(vinylidene fluoride) binder
(PVDF) with <italic>N</italic>-methyl-2-pyrrolidone (NMP) solvent
in the form of a slurry. The well-prepared slurry was cast over the
aluminum foil using the doctor blade technique and dried at 80 &#x000b0;C
overnight. Similarly, bulk sulfur (S) cathode was prepared by mixing
65% sulfur, 25% carbon, and 10% binder. The dried slurry-coated aluminum
foil was cut in the shape of circular disks with a 12 mm diameter
and served as the working electrode. The sulfur loading was controlled
as 2.5&#x02013;2.8 mg cm<sup>&#x02013;2</sup>. Li-S battery was fabricated
in 2032 coin cells using NC-S or S electrodes as a cathode, glass
fiber (GF/C) as a separator, and lithium metal as an anode. Bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimide
lithium salt (1 M, LITFSI) and LiNO<sub>3</sub> additive (0.2 M) in
1,3-dioxolane (DOL) and 1,2-dimethoxyethane (DME) (1:1 v/v) was used
as an electrolyte. The coin cell fabrication was carried out inside
a glovebox (Mbraun) by maintaining O<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>O levels &#x0003c;0.1 ppm. The coin cells were assembled with and without
MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayers.</p><p>Cyclic voltammetry (CV), electrochemical
impedance spectroscopy (EIS), dynamic electrochemical impedance spectroscopy
(DEIS) measurements were recorded using the Biologic VSP 300 electrochemical
test station, and galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge profiles were
recorded using Biologic BCS-810 battery cycler. The CV and galvanostatic
charge&#x02013;discharge profiles were recorded in the potential range
of 2.8&#x02013;1.7 V. The EIS and DEIS measurements were recorded in
the frequency range of 100 mHz to 1 MHz.</p><sec id="sec2.4.1"><label>2.4.1</label><title>Lithium
Polysulfide Absorption Test</title><p>Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> (0.5
M) was prepared by adding lithium
sulfide (Li<sub>2</sub>S) and elemental sulfur (1:5 molar ratio) in
DOL and DME solvents (1:1 v/v). The suspension was stirred continuously
for 72 h inside a glovebox for obtaining Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub>. For the LPS absorption test, Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> was further
diluted by adding 8 &#x003bc;L of Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> in 4 mL
of DOL and DME solvents (1:1 v/v). The samples (10 mg) were added
to the above solution, mixed for 30 min, and allowed to stand for
10 h. The supernatant of the samples was analyzed by UV&#x02013;vis
spectra using a Cary 100 UV&#x02013;vis spectrophotometer from Agilent
Technologies.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><label>3</label><title>Results and Discussion</title><p>The X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns for NC, NC-S, and MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer are shown in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>a. The XRD pattern of NC consists of a high-intensity
peak and a low-intensity peak at 26.4&#x000b0; and 44.1&#x000b0; respectively,
corresponding to the (002) and (101) planes of graphitic carbon, which
confirms the graphitization of porous carbon network. After sulfur
incorporation into the NC structure, the XRD of NC-S depicts mainly
sublimed sulfur peaks (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>a) with a broad hump at 20&#x02013;30&#x000b0;, suggesting the
infiltration of sulfur inside the porous network of NC.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref></sup> The XRD pattern of MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">Figure S1</ext-link>) illustrates peaks at 25.2, 35.5, 42.4, 51.9, 59.9,
63.2, 66.1, 70.4, 76.1, and 83.2&#x000b0; corresponding to the (001),
(100), (101), (002), (110), (102), (111), (200), (201), and (112)
planes of MgB<sub>2</sub> with hexagonal crystal structure (ICDD:
01-074-0982).</p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>(a) X-ray diffraction pattern for NC, NC-S, and sublimed
sulfur.
(b) Nitrogen adsorption&#x02013;desorption isotherms and (c) pore size
distribution for NC.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0002" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>b depicts
the nitrogen adsorption&#x02013;desorption isotherms obtained at 77
K for NC. The sample illustrates type IV isotherm with a hysteresis
loop above 0.5 relative pressure suggests the mesoporous structure
of the NC. Besides, the high nitrogen uptake in the low-relative-pressure
region (&#x0003c;0.1) indicates the presence of micropores in the sample.
The specific surface area of the NC sample estimated based on the
Brunauer&#x02013;Emmett&#x02013;Teller (BET) method is 1272.4 m<sup>2</sup> g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. The Barrett&#x02013;Joyner&#x02013;Halenda
(BJH) method is used to calculate the pore volume and pore size of
NC. <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>c represents
the pore size distribution of NC. The sample consists of both mesopores
(4 nm) and micropores (&#x0003c;2 nm), as indicated in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>c inset. The NC shows a total
pore volume of 1.04 cm<sup>3</sup> g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, including
mesopore and micropore volumes of 0.77 and 0.277 cm<sup>3</sup> g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, respectively. The high surface area and porosity
of the NC sample can enhance the electrochemical reactivity of the
sulfur by providing more surface area and improved diffusion of Li<sup>+</sup> ions and electrolytes into the porous network for the reactions
to occur.</p><p>Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) was carried out in
the air atmosphere
to estimate the decomposition temperature of NC and in a nitrogen
atmosphere to find the sulfur weight % in the NC-S sample. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">Figure S2a</ext-link> illustrates the profile of NC from
room temperature to 1000 &#x000b0;C in the presence of air. The weight
loss below 150 &#x000b0;C indicates the removal of surface-adsorbed moisture.
From 200 to 450 &#x000b0;C the NC sample wt % remains constant, and above
500 &#x000b0;C, the major decomposition occurs due to oxidation of carbon
in NC. The TGA profile of NC-S carried out in the nitrogen atmosphere
is shown in <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">Figure S2b</ext-link>. The decomposition
above 200 &#x000b0;C illustrates the oxidation of sulfur, and the final
weight of sulfur in NC-S is 78 wt %. This suggests that the high surface
and porous network of NC could accommodate a large amount of sulfur
in it. The dominant sulfur peaks in the NC-S XRD pattern is due to
the large amount of sulfur in the present sample.</p><p>The morphology
of the synthesized samples is studied by scanning
electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>a shows the SEM images
for NC, where randomly distribute interconnected open pores are clearly
visible. After sulfur incorporation into nitrogen-doped porous carbon,
SEM of NC-S illustrates a porous network with some pores filled with
sulfur nanoparticle (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>b). The open pores of NC still remain the same. The presence
of open pores, mainly mesoporous and microporous networks, can efficiently
store the active material inside the cathode, therefore improving
the active material utilization. The microporous configuration can
accelerate the diffusion of Li<sup>+</sup> ions, electrolyte, and
electron pathways.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref></sup><xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>c displays the TEM image of NC. The interconnected
channels of the pores with uniform distribution are illustrated. The
TEM image of NC-S depicts the dark sulfur particles over the porous
network of the nitrogen-doped carbon, as shown in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>d. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>e depicts the TEM of NC-S, where the sulfur
particles inside the porous carbon network are highlighted with yellow
arrows. The presence of sulfur inside the nitrogen-doped porous is
confirmed by energy-dispersive X-ray spectra analysis (EDS) measurements. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>f represents the
EDS pattern of NC-S, and the quantification of elements is given in
the <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>f inset
pie chart. The nitrogen content in NC-S is found to be 4.5%, which
can also help in improving the active material utilization in Li-S
battery.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>(a, b) SEM images, (c&#x02013;e) TEM images of NC and NC-S, and
(f) EDS spectra inset elemental composition for NC-S.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0003" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig><p>X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis was carried
out
to elucidate the chemical bonding of the samples. <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>a represents the high-resolution
XPS of N 1s spectra, which deconvoluted into four peaks at 398.2,
399.7, 400.7, and 402.4 eV corresponding to pyridinic-N, pyrrolic-N,
graphitic-N, and oxidized-N (NO<italic><sub>x</sub></italic>). The
pyridinic, pyrrolic, and graphitic-N contents are 47.3, 28.6, and
17.1%, respectively. The high amount of pyridinic-N in the NC-S sample
can bind the LPS by Lewis acid&#x02013;base interactions and suppress
the active material losses.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> The high-resolution
S 2p peak of NC-S is illustrated in <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>b. The S 2p spectra consist of three peaks
at 163.3, 164.4, and 168.1 eV corresponding to S 2p<sub>3/2</sub>,
S 2p<sub>1/2</sub>, and sulfate in air.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref></sup> The binding
energies of S 2p<sub>3/2</sub> and S 2p<sub>1/2</sub> shift to lower
values than the elemental sulfur due to the interaction of carbon
host and sulfur.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref></sup> The high-resolution
XPS Mg 2p and B 1s spectra are shown in <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>c,d, respectively. The Mg 2p spectra illustrate
a peak centered at 50.3 eV corresponding to the metallic Mg.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref></sup> The B 1s spectra deconvoluted into two peaks
at 187.7 and 192.2 eV correspond to the zero oxidation state of boron
and B<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>High-resolution X-ray
photoelectron spectra for (a) N 1s, (b) S
2p, (c) B 1s, and (d) Mg 2p.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0004" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig><p>The electrochemical performance of the synthesized materials is
tested in four different configurations: (i) 65% sulfur, 25% carbon,
and 10% binder cathode (S cathode) without any interlayer; (ii) 65%
sulfur, 25% carbon, and 10% binder cathode with a MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer
(S/MgB<sub>2</sub>); (iii) NC-S cathode without an interlayer; and
(iv) NC-S cathode with a MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer (NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub>). The electrochemical activity and the LPS adsorption capability
of the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes are studied
by cyclic voltammetry (CV) measurements at a scan rate of 0.1 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> in the potential range of 2.8&#x02013;1.7 V. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>a depicts the CV
profiles for S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes at
a scan rate of 0.1 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. In the cathodic scan,
the first reduction peak (I) at 2.37 V corresponds to the reduction
of S<sub>8</sub> to higher-order LPS (Li<sub>2</sub>S<italic><sub>x</sub></italic>, 4 &#x02264; <italic>x</italic> &#x02264; 8), and
the second the reduction peak (II) at 2.01 V indicates the reduction
of higher-order LPS to lower-order LPS (Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>/Li<sub>2</sub>S). During the anodic scan, the peak at 2.4 V signifies
the oxidation of lower-order LPS (Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>/Li<sub>2</sub>S) to higher-order LPS and sulfur. These peaks are well consistent
with the galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge profiles (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref> a&#x00026;b). The NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode illustrates reduction peaks at 2.37 V and 2.01 V
and an oxidation peak at 2.4 V. The S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode displays
sulfur reduction and oxidation peaks at 2.3 V, 1.91 V, and 2.45 V,
respectively. The reduction peaks of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode
are at more positive potentials, and the oxidation peak is more negative
than the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode, suggesting the low polarization
and enhanced sulfur redox kinetic of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref></sup> The anodic peak (III) and cathodic peak (I)
potential differences are found to be 30 and 150 mV for NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes, respectively. The lower overpotential
toward the redox reaction of LPS is an effective way to reduce the
cell polarization and enhance the rate capacity and durability of
the Li-S battery.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref></sup> To further understand
the overpotential caused at higher scan rates, cyclic voltammetry
studies were carried out at scan rates from 0.1 to 0.5 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> in the potential range of 2.8&#x02013;1.7 V. The CV profiles at different
scan rates for the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes
are shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>b,c respectively. An increase in the scan rate increases the peak
current and negative shits in the potential values. The variations
of the anodic peak (III) potential and the cathodic peak (I and II)
potentials with respect to scan rate are given in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>d&#x02013;f, respectively. A
large positive shift and negative shifts are observed in the oxidation
peak (III) and reduction peaks (I and II), respectively, for the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode, which indicate the slower redox reaction kinetics
toward LPS on the surface of sulfur. The addition of a nitrogen-doped
porous carbon network to sulfur has significantly lowered the overpotential
occurred during the lithiation/delithiation processes, suggesting
the inherent LPS adsorption property.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref></sup> This also facilitates the efficient conversion and utilization of
active sulfur materials within the cathode.</p><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(a) Cyclic voltammetry
curves at 0.1 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> for
S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes; cyclic voltammetry
curves for different scan rates (b) S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and (c) NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes; variation peak potential with respect to scan rate
for S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes (d) anodic
peak (III), (e) first cathodic peak (I), and (f) second cathodic peak
(II).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0005" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig><p>Galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
studies were carried out
at different C rates (1C-1672 mA g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>) in the potential
range of 2.8&#x02013;1.7 V. The galvanostatic discharge curves indicate
two plateaus at 2.38 and 2.1 V corresponding to the reduction of S<sub>8</sub> to higher-order and lower-order lithium polysulfides (LPS).
In the charge curve, the plateaus indicate the oxidation Li<sub>2</sub>S to lower-order LPS, higher-order LPS, and back to S<sub>8</sub>. <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>a depicts
the galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge profiles for S cathode without
any interlayer. In the first discharge cycle at 0.05C rate, the sulfur
cathode delivered a specific capacity of 452 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, and in the second cycle, the discharge specific capacity increased
very little to 459 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, which might be due
to the rearrangement of sulfur atoms. However, the charge profile
of the first cycles is overlapped by that of the second cycle; therefore,
it is not identified clearly in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>a. When the C rate increases to 0.1C, the specific
capacity of the S cathode decreases to 342 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, and the second plateau at 2.08 V falls to 1.95 V with a slopping
line rather than plateau. This indicates the pulverization of the
pure sulfur cathode and the shuttling of LPS. The galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
profiles for the NC-S cathode are shown in <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">Figure S3a</ext-link>. The NC-S cathode exhibits a specific capacity of 554,
475, 385, 298, and 156 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 0.1, 0.2, 0.5,
1, and 2C rates, respectively. The NC-S cathode delivers higher specific
capacity and rate capability than the S cathode, signifying the role
of the porous carbon structure, which acts as a buffer layer to accommodate
the volume changes occurred during the redox reactions of the sulfur.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup> Even though the specific capacity and current
uptake are higher than those of pure S cathode, the unstable discharge
plateaus at higher C rates indicate that the additional interlayer
can improve the specific capacity of the cathode.</p><fig id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
profiles at various C rates
for (a) S cathode; (b) S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, NC-S, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes at 0.1C rate; (c) rate capability and (d) EIS profiles
for S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, NC-S, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0006" id="gr6" position="float"/></fig><p><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">Figure S3b</ext-link> displays
the charge&#x02013;discharge
profiles for the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode at different C rates. The
specific capacities obtained by the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode at 0.1,
0.2, 0.5, 1, and 2C rates are 1015, 830, 627, 537, and 371 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, respectively. After the addition of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer, the specific capacity values drastically improved,
suggesting the strong LPS adsorption of the MgB<sub>2</sub> surface.
The Li-S battery performance of the NC-S cathode is also evaluated
with the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer. The galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
profile obtained for the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode from 0.1C to
2C is shown in <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">Figure S3c</ext-link>. The NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode delivers specific capacities of 1218, 1077, 946,
809, and 624 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 0.1, 0.2, 0.5, 1, and 2C
rates, respectively. These specific capacity values are much higher
than the NC-S cathode without interlayer and the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode, indicating that the highly porous nitrogen-doped carbon
architecture with a strong LPS MgB<sub>2</sub> adsorption mediator
interlayer has significantly contributed to the confinement of the
LPS shuttle effect. Therefore, the synergy between the NC-S cathode
and the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer delivers higher specific capacity
values at all current densities. The polarization values &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>1</sub>, &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>2</sub>, &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>3</sub>, and &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>4</sub> are measured between the linear regions of charge&#x02013;discharge
curves for pure S, NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes, respectively, as shown in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>a,b. The measured polarization values for
pure S, NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes
are &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>4</sub> &#x0003c; &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>3</sub> &#x0003c; &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>2</sub> &#x0003c; &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>1</sub>. Therefore, the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode
shows lower polarization than the other cathodes owing to the synergy
of inherent polysulfide adsorption property of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer and nitrogen dopant sites in the porous carbon structure.</p><p>The capability of the Li-S battery with the NC-S, NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes delivering the specific capacity
at higher C rates is evaluated by rate performance studies. <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>c shows the rate
performances of the NC-S, NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes from 0.1 to 2C rates. The rate performance of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode is higher than the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode due
to the nitrogen-doped interconnected porous structure of carbon, which
can minimize the shuttling of LPS.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref></sup> All
the cathodes significantly deliver specific capacity up to 2C rate.
However, the NC-S cathode without a MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer shows
lower specific capacity, and after the addition of a MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer to the NC-S cathode, the specific capacity values significantly
enhanced, contributing to the conductive carbon host and the polar
interlayer. All the cells are cycled up to 2C rate and switched back
to the 0.1C rate. The capacity retentions after switching to 0.1C
for the NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes
are 95.9%, 91%, and 96.6%, respectively. The NC carbon host could
retain maximum specific capacity after rate performance can be attributed
to the low overpotential measured from the CV profiles of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode.</p><p>The reaction kinetics of the NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes were studied by electrochemical
impedance spectroscopy
(EIS) analysis. The Nyquist plots for NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and
NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes after CV measurements are shown in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>d. All the Nyquist
plots comprise the depressed semicircles in the high- and mid-frequency
regions and an inclined line in the low-frequency region. Nyquist
plots have been fitted with an equivalent circuit model in the inset
of <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>d, where <italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub>, and <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> correspond to Ohmic resistance of the electrolyte,
surface film resistance of the electrode, and the charge-transfer
resistance between the electrode and electrolyte interface. CPE<sub>1</sub> and CPE<sub>2</sub> represent the constant phase elements,
and CPE<sub>3</sub> represents an infinite-length Warburg element
that deals with the diffusion of ions within the cathode.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref></sup> The <italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub>, and <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> values
for the NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes
are given in <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref>. The NC-S cathode depicts a higher <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> (33.9 &#x003a9;) value than the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes, which signifies that the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer
can act as an upper current collector by enhancing the conductivity
of the cathode.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref></sup> Besides, the LPS adsorption
property of MgB<sub>2</sub> also enhances the redox kinetics of sulfur
and promotes the high utilization of active materials. The NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode shows lower <italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub>, and <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> values
compared to the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode, suggesting that the synergistic
combination of nitrogen-doped highly porous carbon network and MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer can significantly improve the active material
utilization of Li-S battery and inhibit the shuttling mechanism.</p><table-wrap id="tbl1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title><italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub>, and <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> Values
for NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> Cathodes</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">cathode</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char="."><italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub> (&#x003a9;)</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char="."><italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub> (&#x003a9;)</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char="."><italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> (&#x003a9;)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">NC-S</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">30.7</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">33.9</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">S/MgB<sub>2</sub></td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">2.8</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">7.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.1</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub></td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">2.2</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">3.9</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The long-term cyclic stability
of the NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>,
and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes are evaluated at 1C rate in the
potential window 2.8&#x02013;1.7 V for 500 cycles (<xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>). The NC-S without any interlayer
could show cyclic performance up to 500 cycles, while the capacity
value is less. At the end of 500 cycles, the NC-S cathode could retain
66.4% of its initial capacity. S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cyclic stability
curves indicate the decrease in the specific capacity values with
increasing number of cycles. The capacity retention of the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode after 500 cycles is 71%. Even though MgB<sub>2</sub> has strong adsorption toward LPS, the poor stability of the sulfur
cathode degrades the performance of the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode.
The cyclic performance of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode is illustrated
in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>. The NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode could retain 85% of its initial capacity after 500
cycles, with nearly 99% coulombic efficiency. This suggests the synergistic
effect of highly porous nitrogen-doped carbon host and layered metallic
MgB<sub>2</sub>. As reported in the literature, Mg and B atoms can
adsorb polysulfide anions strongly and facilitate Li<sup>+</sup>-ion
diffusion without binding to Mg and B atoms.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> This has also contributed to the enhanced cyclic stability and rate
capability of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer. Nitrogen doping of the
carbon lattice, mainly pyridinic-N and graphitic-N, can strongly bind
the LPS via chemisorption and minimize the active material losses.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> Therefore, combination of the materials of these
two properties, such as the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode for Li-S
battery, results in an increase of specific capacity, rate performance,
and cyclic stability of the battery.</p><fig id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Cyclic stability at 1C rate for NC-S,
S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0007" id="gr7" position="float"/></fig><p>To elucidate the electrochemical process taking place on
the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode during the charging and discharging
processes distinctly,
the dynamic electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (DEIS) technique
has been studied. The DEIS technique is beneficial over EIS, where
the AC signal is superimposed by the DC signal during the charging/discharging
process, and the measurements are recorded in the quasi-stationary
state.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref38">38</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> This technique is helpful in studying the
electrochemical reaction kinetics of the electrode materials in both
charge and discharge states separately. <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>a,b depicts the DEIS profiles of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode during the discharging and charging processes, respectively.
Similar to EIS, the Nyquist plots of DEIS also comprise depressed
semicircles in high- and mid-frequency regions, followed by a slopping
line in the low-frequency region. It is clearly visible from the DEIS
profile of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode during the discharging
process that with increasing depth of discharge (DOD), the length
of the diffusion tail decreases until the voltage reaches 2.36 V.
This is because as the voltage reaches from 2.8 to 2.36 V, S<sub>8</sub> reduces for the formation of higher-order LPS (Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>8</sub>); during this stage, Li<sup>+</sup> ions have faster diffusion
kinetics and the diffusion tail decreases. Above 2.36 V, the higher-order
LPS reduces for the formation of lower-order LPS, which increases
the viscosity of the electrolyte, and therefore, diffusion tails increase.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref></sup> During the charging process, a similar trend
in the DEIS profile has been observed. The length of the diffusion
is minimum around 2.36 V due to the formation of higher-order LPS.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref40">40</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>DEIS
profiles for the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode during (a) discharging
and (b) charging processes. Resistance versus voltage profile during
(c) discharging and (d) charging processes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0008" id="gr8" position="float"/></fig><p>The electrochemical reaction kinetics of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode are analyzed by fitting the Nyquist plots during the discharging
and charging processes (<xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>a,b using the equivalent circuit given in the inset of <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>d). The variation
of <italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub>, and <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> with respect to DOD is illustrated
in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>c. The Ohmic
resistance (<italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>) values remain uniform
during the discharging process, which can be attributed to the synergistic
combination of the NC sulfur cathode and the metallic MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer that can inhibit LPS dissolution into the electrolyte.
The <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub> value is constant at the beginning
of the discharging process and it decreases with increasing DOD up
to 2.2 V due to the formation of higher-order lithium polysulfides
on the surface of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer, which is mostly
in liquid state and decreases the surface film resistance. Above 2.1
V, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub> increases for the conversion of
higher-order LPS to Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>/Li<sub>2</sub>S films
on the cathode surface. The <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> value
is higher during the initial discharging process due to the presence
of insoluble sulfur spices; as DOD increases, the <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> value decreases for the conversion of S<sub>8</sub> to Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>8</sub>/Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> with
faster reaction kinetics on the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer. Above
2.2 V, <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> tends to increase due to an
increase in the concentration of insoluble and nonconductive LPS (Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>/Li<sub>2</sub>S) species on the cathode. The
variation of resistance values (<italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub>, <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub>, and <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub>) during
the charging process is represented in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>d. Similar to the discharging process, the <italic>R</italic><sub>o</sub> value remains constant during the charging
process of NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode. During the initial charging
condition, the <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub> value is higher due
to the presence of Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>2</sub>/Li<sub>2</sub>S on
the cathode surface and decreases as the conversion of lower-order
LPS to higher-order LPS proceeds. At the end of charging, the <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub> value increases due to the deposition of
a sulfur film on the cathode. The <italic>R</italic><sub>si</sub> value
represents the resistance offered due to the diffusion of electrolyte
through pores of the interlayer, which suggests that the electrochemical
process taking place during the charging is governed by the transport
properties of the electrolyte.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref></sup> During
charging, the <italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub> values tend to decrease
from 2.2 to 2.5 V due to the formation of higher-order LPS and reaches
maximum at the end of the charging process.</p><sec id="sec3.1"><label>3.1</label><title>Evaluation
of Lithium Polysulfide Confinement</title><p>The adsorption capability
of nitrogen-doped porous carbon (NC)
and MgB<sub>2</sub> toward LPS is evaluated by the LPS adsorption
test. For this, NC and MgB<sub>2</sub> are added in a blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution, mixed well, and kept undisturbed for
10 h inside an argon-filled glovebox. <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>a inset displays the digital photographs
of blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution and Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution with NC and MgB<sub>2</sub> samples. Compared to
the blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution, the NC sample shows
a very light yellowish color due to the adsorption of LPS. The MgB<sub>2</sub> sample solution becomes completely transparent, suggesting
the strong adsorption of LPS on its surface. This is further analyzed
using UV&#x02013;vis photospectrometer by collecting the supernatant
solution of NC and MgB<sub>2</sub> samples. A UV&#x02013;vis spectrum
is obtained for the blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution for
comparison. In <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>a, the UV&#x02013;vis spectra of the blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution show a peak at &#x0223c;357 nm corresponding to the absorbance
of S<sub>6</sub><sup>2&#x02013;</sup> anions.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref></sup> The peak intensity reduces for the supernatant solution NC, indicating
the adsorption of LPS on the surface but not completely. On the other
hand, for the MgB<sub>2</sub> supernatant solution, the peak at &#x0223c;357
nm disappears, indicating the absence of Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> in the solution. Moreover, the intensity of absorbance also reduces
for the supernatant solution of MgB<sub>2</sub> compared to NC and
blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution. This also corroborates
the strong adsorption capability of MgB<sub>2</sub> toward LPS, which
can minimize the shuttle effect during cycling. This also infers that
polar metallic compounds have strong LPS adsorption capability over
carbonaceous materials. However, the carbonaceous material as the
sulfur host can accommodate a large amount of sulfur loading and suppress
the volume changes during the redox cycle due to its high surface
and porosity.</p><fig id="fig8" position="float"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>(a) UV&#x02013;vis spectra and (inset) digital photograph
of LPS
adsorption of NC, MgB<sub>2</sub>, and reference blank Li<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> solution; NC-S cathode (b) uncycled, (c) cycled with
MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer, (d) uncycled MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer,
(e) cycled MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer with NC-S, and (f) cycled MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer with S cathode.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_0009" id="gr9" position="float"/></fig><p>To understand the interaction of LPS with electrode and interlayers,
the morphology of the cycled electrode and interlayers and uncycled
electrodes are studied SEM images. <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>b illustrates the SEM image of the uncycled
NC-S electrode with interconnected open pores. After cycling the NC-S
electrode, the pores of nitrogen-doped porous carbon covered the polysulfides,
suggesting the porous structure of NC contributed to anchoring the
LPS in the cathode (<xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>c). The SEM images of uncycled MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer
and cycled interlayer with the NC-S cathode and pure sulfur cathode
are represented in <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>d&#x02013;f, respectively. The morphology of the cycled MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer with the NC-S cathode is changed when compared
to the uncycled one where larger and discrete particles of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer are identified. This can be due to the adsorption
of LPS on its surface. The cycled MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer with
S cathode shows the high polysulfide deposition of LPS on the surface
of MgB<sub>2</sub> with very less discrete particle nature. This can
be attributed to the poor adsorption capability of the sulfur cathode.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec4"><label>4</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>In summary, nitrogen-doped porous
carbon (NC) with interconnected
pores has been synthesized by a facile one-step synthesis method and
used as the sulfur host (NC-S) for Li-S battery. The high surface
area for NC can accommodate a high amount of sulfur loading in the
cathode and also provide space for the sulfur volume change and prevent
pulverization. The NC-S cathode delivers higher specific capacity
(554 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 0.1C) and rate capability (up to
2C) than bulk sulfur (S) cathode, signifying the role the porous of
the carbon structure. To prevent the polysulfide dissolution and inhibit
the active material losses, room-temperature metallic and polar material
MgB<sub>2</sub> has been used as an interlayer. The sulfur cathode
with MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer (S/MgB<sub>2</sub>) delivers a specific
capacity of 1015 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 0.1C rate, much higher
than the sulfur cathode, owing to the inherent LPS adsorption property
of MgB<sub>2</sub>. The NC-S cathode with MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer
(NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub>) delivers a specific capacity of 1218 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 0.1C rate higher than the S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode.
Moreover, the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode shows excellent cycling
stability up to 500 cycles, with 85% of capacity retention. The high
performance of NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> can be attributed to the synergy
between the interconnected porous network of the NC cathode and the
strong LPS adsorption capability of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer.
The dynamic electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (DEIS) analysis
elucidates the electrochemical reaction kinetics of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode during the charging and discharging processes. In
conclusion, the synergy of the lithium polysulfide confinement and
conversion reactions of the NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathode paves the
way for the development of high-energy-density lithium-sulfur batteries.</p></sec></body><back><notes id="notes-1" notes-type="si"><title>Supporting Information Available</title><p>The Supporting Information
is available free of charge at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778?goto=supporting-info">https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778</ext-link>.<list id="silist" list-type="simple"><list-item><p>X-ray diffraction pattern
of the MgB<sub>2</sub> interlayer,
TGA profiles of NC and NC-S samples, and galvanostatic charge&#x02013;discharge
profiles of the NC-S, S/MgB<sub>2</sub>, and NC-S/MgB<sub>2</sub> cathodes
(<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.0c02778/suppl_file/ao0c02778_si_001.pdf">PDF</ext-link>)</p></list-item></list></p></notes><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="sifile1"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao0c02778_si_001.pdf"><caption><p>ao0c02778_si_001.pdf</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d7e1704-autogenerated"><p>The authors declare no
competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors acknowledge the Indian Institute
of Technology
Madras (IITM), Chennai, India, for financial support. One of the authors
(R.S.) thanks the Department of Science and Technology (DST) for the
financial support to establish Nano Functional Materials Technology
Centre (NFMTC) through SR/NM/NAT/02&#x02013;2005 project.</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Rechargeable Lithium&#x02013;Sulfur
Batteries</article-title>. <source>Chem. Rev.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>114</volume>, <fpage>11751</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11787</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr500062v</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25026475</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrode&#x02013;Electrolyte Interfaces in Lithium&#x02013;Sulfur
Batteries with Liquid or Inorganic Solid Electrolytes</article-title>. <source>Acc. Chem. Res.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>50</volume>, <fpage>2653</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2660</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.accounts.7b00460</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29112389</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Lochala</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Robinson</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Research Progress toward
the Practical Applications of Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2017</year>, <fpage>24407</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>24421</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b06208</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28617586</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>D.-W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>H.-M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gentle</surname><given-names>I. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>G. Q. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Carbon&#x02013;Sulfur
Composites for Li&#x02013;S Batteries: Status and Prospects</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>9382</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c3ta11045a</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Eftekhari</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.-W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Cathode Materials
for Lithium&#x02013;Sulfur Batteries:
A Practical Perspective</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>17734</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>17776</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7TA00799J</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Borchardt</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Oschatz</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kaskel</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Tailoring Porosity in Carbon Materials
for Supercapacitor Applications</article-title>. <source>Mater. Horiz.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>157</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>168</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C3MH00112A</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Abru&#x000f1;a</surname><given-names>H. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>S. X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Tailoring Pore Size
of Nitrogen-Doped Hollow Carbon Nanospheres for Confining Sulfur in
Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <elocation-id>1401752</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201401752</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Nitrogen-Doped Porous Hollow Carbon
Sphere-Decorated Separators for
Advanced Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Power
Sources</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>300</volume>, <fpage>157</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>163</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2015.09.067</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dou</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Synergistically
Enhanced Interfacial Interaction to Polysulfide via
N,O Dual-Doped Highly Porous Carbon Microrods for Advanced Lithium-Sulfur
Batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>13573</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13580</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.8b02084</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29616547</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Status and
Prospects in Sulfur-Carbon Composites as Cathode Materials for Rechargeable
Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Carbon</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>92</volume>, <fpage>41</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>63</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2015.03.008</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lv</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q.-H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Twinborn TiO 2 &#x02212;TiN
Heterostructures Enabling Smooth Trapping&#x02013;Diffusion&#x02013;Conversion
of Polysulfides towards Ultralong Life Lithium&#x02013;Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>1694</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1703</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7EE01430A</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>B. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y. T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z. Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>G. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>X. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Spherical Metal
Oxides with High Tap Density as Sulfur Host to Enhance Cathode Volumetric
Capacity for Lithium-Sulfur Battery</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl.
Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>12</volume>, <fpage>5909</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5919</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b20111</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31944646</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Conductive
and Polar Titanium Boride as a Sulfur Host for Advanced
Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Chem. Mater.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>6969</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6977</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.8b01352</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The Facile Synthesis and Enhanced
Lithium-Sulfur Battery Performance of an Amorphous Cobalt Boride (Co<sub>2</sub>B)@graphene Composite Cathode</article-title>. <source>J. Mater.
Chem. A</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>24045</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>24049</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8TA09301F</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Kortus</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mazin</surname><given-names>I. I.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Belashchenko</surname><given-names>K. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Antropov</surname><given-names>V. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Boyer</surname><given-names>L. L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Superconductivity
of Metallic Boron in MgB<sub>2</sub></article-title>. <source>Phys.
Rev. Lett.</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>86</volume>, <fpage>4656</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4659</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.86.4656</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11384307</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Belashchenko</surname><given-names>K. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>van Schilfgaarde</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Antropov</surname><given-names>V. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Nature of Bonding and Electronic
Structure in MgB<sub>2</sub>, a Boron Intercalation Superconductor</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>64</volume>, <elocation-id>092503</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.64.092503</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Bud&#x02019;ko</surname><given-names>S. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lapertot</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Petrovic</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cunningham</surname><given-names>C. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Canfield</surname><given-names>P. C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Boron Isotope Effect
in Superconducting
MgB<sub>2</sub></article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>86</volume>, <fpage>1877</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1880</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.86.1877</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11290271</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Pang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kwok</surname><given-names>C. Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kundu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nazar</surname><given-names>L. F.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lightweight
Metallic MgB<sub>2</sub> Mediates Polysulfide Redox and Promises High-Energy-Density
Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Joule</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>136</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>148</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2018.09.024</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.-W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.-T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.-Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Enhanced Electrochemical
Kinetics
on Conductive Polar Mediators for Lithium-Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>55</volume>, <fpage>12990</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>12995</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201605676</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Seshadhri</surname><given-names>G. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ramaprabhu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Green Synthesis
of Nitrogen-Doped Self-Assembled Porous Carbon-Metal Oxide Composite
towards Energy and Environmental Applications</article-title>. <source>Sci. Rep.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>9</volume>, <elocation-id>5187</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-41700-5</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30914729</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Suvorova</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Saunders</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tade</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Heteroatom
(N or N-S)-Doping Induced
Layered and Honeycomb Microstructures of Porous Carbons for CO<sub>2</sub> Capture and Energy Applications</article-title>. <source>Adv.
Funct. Mater.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>26</volume>, <fpage>8651</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8661</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.201603937</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit22"><name><surname>Hartman</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Svoboda</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Poho&#x00159;el&#x000fd;</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>&#x00160;yc</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Thermal Decomposition
of Sodium Hydrogen Carbonate and Textural Features of Its Calcines</article-title>. <source>Ind. Eng. Chem. Res.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>52</volume>, <fpage>10619</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>10626</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ie400896c</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Liquid
Electrolyte Lithium/Sulfur Battery: Fundamental Chemistry, Problems,
and Solutions</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>231</volume>, <fpage>153</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>162</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2012.12.102</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>D. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Condi De
Godoi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gentle</surname><given-names>I. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Synergy of Nanoconfinement and Surface
Oxygen in Recrystallization of Sulfur Melt in Carbon Nanocapsules
and the Related Li-S Cathode Properties</article-title>. <source>J.
Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>2</volume>, <fpage>6439</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6447</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c4ta00314d</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrochimica Acta
Fabrication of High Conductive S/C Cathode by Sulfur Infiltration
into Hierarchical Porous Carbon/Carbon Fiber Weave-Structured Materials
via Vapor-Melting Method</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>127</volume>, <fpage>123</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>131</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2014.02.001</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>3D Nitrogen-Doped Hierarchical
Porous Carbon Framework for Protecting Sulfur Cathode in Lithium&#x02013;Sulfur
Batteries</article-title>. <source>New J. Chem.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>43</volume>, <fpage>9641</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>9651</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C9NJ01017C</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>T. Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J. Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>X. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>M. Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>He</surname><given-names>L. Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Strongly Coupled
Interfaces between a Heterogeneous Carbon Host and a Sulfur-Containing
Guest for Highly Stable Lithium-Sulfur Batteries: Mechanistic Insight
into Capacity Degradation</article-title>. <source>Adv. Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>1</volume>, <elocation-id>1400227</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/admi.201400227</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>K. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ahn</surname><given-names>J. H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Root-like Porous
Carbon Nanofibers with High Sulfur
Loading Enabling Superior Areal Capacity of Lithium Sulfur Batteries</article-title>. <source>Carbon</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>128</volume>, <fpage>138</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>146</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2017.11.025</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit29"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>L. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>D. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pei</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gentle</surname><given-names>I. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>H. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Fibrous
Hybrid of
Graphene and Sulfur Nanocrystals for High-Performance Lithium-Sulfur
Batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Nano</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>5367</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5375</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nn401228t</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23672616</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit30"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bin Wu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>X. W. D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Enhancing Lithium-Sulphur
Battery Performance by Strongly Binding the Discharge Products on
Amino-Functionalized Reduced Graphene Oxide</article-title>. <source>Nat. Commun.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <elocation-id>5002</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncomms6002</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25255431</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit31"><name><surname>Vasquez</surname><given-names>R. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>C. U.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>M.-S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J. Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-I.</given-names></name>
<article-title>X-Ray Photoemission
Study of MgB2</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>64</volume>, <elocation-id>052510</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.64.052510</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit32"><name><surname>Garg</surname><given-names>K. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chatterji</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dalela</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Heinonnen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Leiro</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dalela</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Singhal</surname><given-names>R. K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Core Level Photoemission
Study of Polycrystalline MgB2</article-title>. <source>Solid State Commun.</source>
<year>2004</year>, <volume>131</volume>, <fpage>343</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>347</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ssc.2004.01.006</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit33"><name><surname>Thangavel</surname><given-names>N. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gopalakrishnan</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Arava</surname><given-names>L. M. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Understanding Heterogeneous Electrocatalysis
of Lithium Polysulfide Redox on Pt and WS<sub>2</sub> Surfaces</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>121</volume>, <fpage>12718</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>12725</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b01514</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit34"><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A Collaboratively Polar
Conductive Interface for Accelerating Polysulfide
Redox Conversion</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>14035</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>14043</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.8b21447</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30869862</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit35"><name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>S. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Singhal</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kalra</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrochemically
Stable Rechargeable Lithium-Sulfur Batteries with a Microporous Carbon
Nanofiber Filter for Polysulfide</article-title>. <source>Adv. Energy
Mater.</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <elocation-id>1500738</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201500738</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref36"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit36"><name><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy Study of a Lithium/Sulfur
Battery: Modeling and Analysis of Capacity Fading</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>160</volume>, <fpage>A553</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>A558</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/2.026304jes</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref37"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit37"><name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>Y. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cochell</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A Strategic Approach to Recharging
Lithium-Sulphur Batteries for Long Cycle Life</article-title>. <source>Nat. Commun.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>4</volume>, <elocation-id>2985</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncomms3985</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24346483</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref38"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit38"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Dynamic Electrochemical
Impedance Spectroscopy Reconstructed
from Continuous Impedance Measurement of Single Frequency during Charging/Discharging</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>273</volume>, <fpage>1098</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1102</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.07.067</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref39"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit39"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ge</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Dynamic Electrochemical Impedance
Spectroscopy of a Three-Electrode Lithium-Ion Battery during Pulse
Charge and Discharge</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>176</volume>, <fpage>311</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>320</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2015.07.017</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref40"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit40"><name><surname>Garapati</surname><given-names>M. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>V.S</surname><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sundara</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Synergy between
Partially Exfoliated
Carbon Nanotubes-Sulfur Cathode and Nitrogen Rich Dual Function Interlayer
for High Performance Lithium Sulfur Battery</article-title>. <source>Carbon</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>147</volume>, <fpage>364</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>376</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2019.03.007</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref41"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit41"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.-F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mistry</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>P. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Probing
Impedance and Microstructure
Evolution in Lithium&#x02013;Sulfur Battery Electrodes</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>121</volume>, <fpage>21206</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>21216</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b07245</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref42"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit42"><name><surname>Kolosnitsyn</surname><given-names>V. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kuzmina</surname><given-names>E. V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Karaseva</surname><given-names>E. V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mochalov</surname><given-names>S. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A Study of the Electrochemical
Processes in Lithium-Sulphur Cells by Impedance Spectroscopy</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>196</volume>, <fpage>1478</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1482</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2010.08.105</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref43"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit43"><name><surname>Barchasz</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Molton</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Duboc</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lepr&#x000ea;tre</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Patoux</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Alloin</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium/Sulfur Cell Discharge Mechanism:
An Original Approach for Intermediate Species Identification</article-title>. <source>Anal. Chem.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>84</volume>, <fpage>3973</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3980</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ac2032244</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22482872</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>