<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Spatiotemporal sampling efforts are unparalleled in 
 <italic>D. melanogaster</italic>. Because flies have short generation times, the system is highly compatible with empirical time series studies. Time series studies can differ in depth of past evolutionary history. 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">Dobzhansky (1943)</xref> demonstrated that some inversions cycle with the seasons in 
 <italic>Drosophila pseudoobscura</italic>. In 
 <italic>D. melanogaster</italic>, many variants seem to cycle seasonally in a single temperate population (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Bergland et al., 2014</xref>) as well as across many different locations worldwide (
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">Machado et al., 2021</xref>). Two consortiums in Europe and North America, DrosEU and the DrosRTEC, have been sampling and sequencing wild 
 <italic>D. melanogaster</italic> populations annually since 2014 across multiple locations (
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">Kapun et al., 2020</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">2021</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">Machado et al., 2021</xref>). These efforts are expected to continue for the foreseeable future, increasing even further spatiotemporal resolution. Other studies went even far back in time and compared classical latitudinal patterns published decades ago with more recent data (
 <xref rid="B69" ref-type="bibr">Umina et al., 2005</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Cogni et al., 2014</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Efforts to sequence specimens collected decades ago are just now starting to emerge (
 <xref rid="B70" ref-type="bibr">Veeramah et al., 2020</xref>; John Pool, personal communication). Theoretically, one could go even deeper in time by sequencing museum specimens (
 <xref rid="B72" ref-type="bibr">Wandeler et al., 2007</xref>), but it is unclear whether museums have enough disposable specimens. Future advances in DNA sequencing with minimal tissue availability could make this more feasible.
</p>
