<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">This study adds to the ongoing discussions on climate change and food security by focussing on Africa. Further research in this area is crucial for several reasons. First, more than 20% of Africa’s population is undernourished (FAO et al
 <italic>.,</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">2019</xref>). Food availability remains a critical concern in Africa, given the rising population growth rates and poverty levels. Recent estimates show that 704 million people (9.2%) of the world’s population were subject to severe food insecurity in 2018 (FAO et al
 <italic>.,</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">2019</xref>). The situation is most alarming in Africa, where severe food insecurity rose from 210.7 million to 277 million between 2014 and 2018, affecting 21.5% of the population in 2018 (FAO et al
 <italic>.,</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">2019</xref>). Food insecurity is on the increase in almost every sub-region of Africa. In 2018, Southern Africa had the highest prevalence of severe food insecurity (30.6%), followed by Eastern Africa (25.9%), Western Africa (17.6%), and Northern Africa (8%) (FAO et al
 <italic>.,</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">2019</xref>). Bumb and Byrnes (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">1998</xref>) stated that cereals account for 60–70% of the average per capita calorie consumption, so they are periodically used as a proxy for food security. The quantities of cereals produced for food supply in countries are estimated in calories to reflect the amount of food everyone consumes (Bezuneh &amp; Yiheyis, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">2014</xref>; Smith &amp; Haddad, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR75">2001</xref>). Figure 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> displays the Pareto plot of average cereal production over the period 1970–2016 in 15 selected African countries with a history of food insecurity and food emergencies. On average, Nigeria produced 17,281,243 tonnes, followed by Egypt, producing 14,888,196 tonnes, with South Africa occupying the third position with 11,936,601 tonnes. Morocco came in fourth, producing 5,674,449 tonnes, followed closely by Kenya (3,084,558 tonnes), and Mali took sixth place with 2,828,047 tonnes. The Pareto plot of average cereal production shows that thirteen countries, including South Africa, cumulatively produced 50% of total cereal production by the selected African countries. In comparison, the remaining 50% was generated proportionately by Nigeria and Egypt between 1970 and 2016.
</p>
