<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">Second, while the debate on food security continues, ongoing discussions concern the implications of frequent temperature variations, rainfall variability, and increased climatic events across African countries (Etana et al
 <italic>.,</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">2021</xref>; Hulme et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">2001</xref>; Nicholson et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">2000</xref>; Nicholson, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">2001</xref>; Owusu et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">2021</xref>). Although Africa is considered a minor player in total global greenhouse gas emissions, generating less than 4% of the world’s total (Oliver &amp; Peters, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">2020</xref>), the continent is susceptible to the adverse consequences of climate change variability (Boko et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">2007</xref>; Lobell et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">2011</xref>; Nakhooda et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">2011</xref>; Sy, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR76">2016</xref>). Prior evidence suggests that countries in Africa, especially those in sub-Saharan Africa (SSA), will experience an increase in temperature of 2–4 °C by 2100, which is about 1.5 times higher than the expected mean increase in global temperature (Boko et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">2007</xref>; Christensen et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">2007</xref>). According to Easterling et al. (
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">2007</xref>), a rise in temperature by 3 °C or more will cause food prices to increase by 40%. A large proportion of the African population relies on rain-fed farming for their livelihood (Adhikari et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">2015</xref>; Cooper et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">2008</xref>; Muchuru &amp; Nhamo, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">2019</xref>), so extreme climate variability poses a significant threat to food production (Boko et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">2007</xref>; Etana et al
 <italic>.,</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">2021</xref>; Lobell et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">2011</xref>; Schlenker &amp; Lobell, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR71">2010</xref>). Climate change and variability also raise food production costs, translating to high consumer prices (Berrera &amp; Hertel, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">2021</xref>; Dadzie et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">2021</xref>; FAO, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">2008</xref>). Evidence shows that climate change could decrease agricultural output in SSA by 8% by 2080, compared with a decrease of about 4% in Asia (Shah et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR73">2008</xref>). This negative effect of climate change will severely impair access to food, given that most economies in Africa are unable to finance food importation (Nathaniel et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">2021</xref>; Shah et al., 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR73">2008</xref>). A decreased income for farmers in Africa resulting from reduced agricultural output will influence most households’ capacity to buy food, even if it is available commercially.
</p>
